<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--Generated by Site-Server v6.0.0-20140421.2-129 (http://www.squarespace.com) on Tue, 22 Apr 2014 17:28:23 GMT
--><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://www.rssboard.org/media-rss" version="2.0"><channel><title>Tab Dump</title><link>http://tabdump.com/</link><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 07:56:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><language>en-US</language><generator>Site-Server v6.0.0-20140421.2-129 (http://www.squarespace.com)</generator><description></description><item><title>April 22: 30 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 07:23:35 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/22/april-22-30-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:535618fde4b058b6b221b02b</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a target="_blank" href="https://itunes.apple.com/app/launch-center-pro/id532016360?at=11l5PD&amp;ct=LCP-tabdump">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: Launch actions, not <em>just</em> apps. It's like speed dial for everyday tasks. Launch Center Pro saves you time by launching complex actions in a single tap.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26185600">02</a> &nbsp;Alibaba: They have a service called Taobao that's a combination of eBay and Amazon, but twice as big as those two Western services combined. Here's a list of 10 "weird" things you can find on it. Semi-Spoiler: Scorpions, soap made out of breast milk, boyfriends, poetry.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-22/amazon-sales-take-a-hit-in-states-with-online-tax.html">03</a> &nbsp;Amazon: In most U.S. states, people don't pay tax for goods purchased online. In some states, they do. Researchers have discovered "in states that have the [online] tax, households reduced their spending on Amazon by about 10% compared to those in states that don't have the levy. For online purchases of more than $300, sales fell by 24%."</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/21/5637348/amazon-fire-tv-voice-search-will-support-netflix-later-this-year">04</a> &nbsp;Amazon: The newly announced Fire TV will be able to search Netflix's catalog via voice "later this year" according to Netflix CEO Reed Hastings.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.macrumors.com/2014/04/21/apple-trademark-jewelry-watches/">05</a> &nbsp;Apple: MacRumors has discovered that Apple is expanding the definition of the company's trademark to include jewelry.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://recode.net/2014/04/21/apple-interviewing-job-candidates-for-mobile-payments-push/">06</a> &nbsp;Apple: Re/code says Apple is interviewing people who will be tasked with "[building] an electronic payments business" that will make use of the 600+ million credit cards the company has on file. No word as to who is being interviewed, what the service will actually provide, or when it will launch.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/21/5636218/apple-tim-cook-narrates-environmental-sustainibility-ad-earth-day">07</a> &nbsp;Apple: They uploaded two new videos. One champions how green Apple is, the other is about Apple's upcoming "spaceship" campus. The former is getting a lot of attention because Tim Cook, Apple's CEO, did the narration. Both come off as boring to me, but that doesn't really matter, because I don't buy Apple hardware based on the quality of the company's commercials.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://about.att.com/story/att_eyes_100_u_s_cities_and_municipalities_for_its_ultra_fast_fiber_network.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+AttAllCategoriesRssFeeds+%28AT%26T+All+Categories+RSS+Feeds%29">08</a> &nbsp;AT&amp;T: They won't admit it, but because of Google Fiber, AT&amp;T published a list yesterday of 100 cities that may or may not eventually get "GigaPower" (read: one gigabit per second) internet access. No word as to how much the service will actually cost.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.billboard.com/biz/articles/news/digital-and-mobile/6062727/beats-musics-first-100-days-a-bumpy-start">09</a> &nbsp;Beats: This Spotify competitor (read: clone) is "in the process of closing a new round valued between $60 million and $100 million." It's also said that Beats allegedly has a "low six figure" number of paying subscribers.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="https://plus.google.com/+MikeDodd/posts/R1pixNfhsqq">10</a> &nbsp;Google: They've updated their chat app, Hangouts, to finally show text messages and chat messages from the same individual in one window. Previously, text messages (SMS) and instant messages (OTT) to the same person were considered different conversations.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://venturebeat.com/2014/04/21/google-is-researching-ways-to-make-encryption-easier-to-use-in-gmail/">11</a> &nbsp;Google: VentureBeat is reporting that Google is working on making PGP encryption drop dead simple to use with Gmail. No word as to when this research will transform into an actual product. Also, doesn't Google need to scan your email to serve you ads?</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.androidos.in/2014/04/htc-unveils-desire-210-goes-sale-april-end-inr-8700/">12</a> &nbsp;HTC: They announced a new budget 4.0 inch phone called the Desire 210. It's powered by a MediaTek processor and will cost roughly $145 when it launches in India next month.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/22/5638908/smart-watch-lg-champagne-gold">13</a> &nbsp;LG: They published three new pieces of information about the upcoming G Watch, the first device to be powered by Android Wear. There will be a "champagne gold" color option, the screen will always be on, and it's dust and water resistant. Note that earlier this month, LG told the UK publication Pocket-lint that the G Watch would hit the market <a target="_blank" href="http://www.pocket-lint.com/news/128341-lg-g-watch-release-date-by-july-and-less-than-180-in-the-uk-hands-on-pictures">before July</a> at a price of less than £180 ($300).</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/microsoft_blog/archive/2014/04/21/the-nokia-devices-and-services-acquisition-close-date.aspx">14</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: They published a blog post saying the Nokia deal will close this Friday (25th).</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/21/motorola-solutions-latest-to-sign-microsoft-licensing-agreement-for-chrome-android-devices/">15</a> &nbsp;Motorola Solutions: Not to be confused with Motorola Mobility, which Google bought and then sold, Motorola Solutions has just signed a licensing agreement with Microsoft over patents relating to Android and Chrome OS.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27106460">16</a> &nbsp;Netflix: The company reported their financial results yesterday. All you need to know is that they now have 48 million subscribers and they're planning to charge $1 to $2 more for the service later this year, but only for new customers in certain unspecified countries. Netflix CEO Reed Hastings was keen to point out that HBO has 130 million subscribers, and he's "eager to close the gap".</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/18/taking-on-amazon-target-expands-online-subscriptions-program-to-more-categories-lowers-prices/?ncid=rss">17</a> &nbsp;Target: Best thought of as a premium version of Walmart, Target is now offering 1,500 items via an online "subscription" service. In other words, you tell Target you want a bottle of shampoo and conditioner sent to your house once a month, and they'll deliver.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/miriamelder/ceo-of-russian-facebook-says-he-was-fired-and-that-the-socia">18</a> &nbsp;VKontakte: Russia's version of Facebook was just stolen from the CEO by people that aren't technically from the Russian government, but they may as well be.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://searchengineland.com/yahoo-testing-knowledge-graph-lookalike-search-results-189505">19</a> &nbsp;Yahoo!: You know how when you Google certain things, a box appears on the righthand side with a specific answer to your query? Yahoo! is testing a clone of that.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-china-27107248">20</a> &nbsp;China: Robots are used by companies to minimize the number of people they need to employ in their factories. This small restaurant is using that same thinking with their robotic chefs and waiters. Cute 82 second video.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27107339">21</a> &nbsp;China: Shandong Airlines just dropped $4.6 billion on 50 Boeing 737 jets.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.theatlantic.com/infocus/2014/04/the-easter-rocket-war-of-vrontados/100720/">22</a> &nbsp;Greece: Yesterday, I shared a video showing two Greek churches celebrating Easter by firing rockets at each other. Today, The Atlantic published 26 photos of the event, and they're stunning.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-27107273">23</a> &nbsp;North Korea: South Korea is reporting that a lot of unusual activity is taking place in and around North Korea's nuclear test site. They say North Korea is either going to set something off or want to look like they're going to set something off.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-27107267">24</a> &nbsp;South Korea: The latest numbers from the ferry disaster: 104 dead, 198 missing, 174 rescued.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27032797">25</a> &nbsp;Spain: Wind energy generated as much electricity as nuclear energy for the first time in Spain in 2013; 49.1% of the country's electricity now comes from renewables (wind, solar (photovoltaic and thermal) and hydro).</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-27101228">26</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: Now that Crimea is a part of Russia, what happens next? Putin wants to turn it into Las Vegas.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-27104904">27</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: The U.S. State Department has published photos of some of the soldiers fighting in Ukraine, claiming that several of the men are known to be Russian Special Forces. Russia continues to say they're not participating in the Ukrainian conflict.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-27106445">28</a> &nbsp;USA: Siale Angilau, age 25, was shot and killed in a courtroom in Utah after he "lunged" at a witness testifying against him. His daughter, who was there, says at least six shots were fired. Question: Why wasn't he restrained in the first place?</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27107416">29</a> &nbsp;World: Novartis and GlaxoSmithKline, two of the world's biggest drug makers, are going to combine, kind of. The structure of the deal is a little complicated, but all you need to know is that the two companies will merge their respective consumer health divisions.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://tabdump.com/support">30</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a target="_blank" href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 21: 44 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 10:42:23 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/21/april-21-44-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:5354f613e4b086059ffa3f7f</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a target="_blank" href="https://itunes.apple.com/app/launch-center-pro/id532016360?at=11l5PD&amp;ct=LCP-tabdump">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: Launch actions, not <em>just</em> apps. It's like speed dial for everyday tasks. Launch Center Pro saves you time by launching complex actions in a single tap.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.apptuners.tabdumper">02</a> &nbsp;Site News: I have two announcements to make. Number One: Starting today, Tab Dump links will open in a new window. I've lost count of the number of emails I've received asking me to add this "feature". While I personally don't get it, I can't argue with people's wants and desires. Number Two: Naveen Naushad is a huge Tab Dump fan, so much so that he's written an Android app for you guys called "Tab Dumper". It's now <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.apptuners.tabdumper">in the Play Store</a>, so make sure to check it out!</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://thenextweb.com/asia/2014/04/17/chinas-alibaba-will-launch-its-first-mobile-telecom-services-in-june/?awesm=tnw.to_f4qXs&amp;utm_source=social&amp;utm_content=38634&amp;utm_campaign=pro&amp;utm_medium=Twitter">03</a> &nbsp;Alibaba: Starting in June, Alibaba, which makes Amazon and eBay look tiny in comparison, will become a wireless operator. They're not going to build a network, however, instead they'll operate an MVNO that uses all three of China's wireless networks.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27055407">04</a> &nbsp;Amazon: Impressive data point of the day: "Every man, woman, and child in Britain spends an average of more than £70 ($120) a year on Amazon."</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702304626304579510020273541060?mg=reno64-wsj&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fonline.wsj.com%2Farticle%2FSB10001424052702304626304579510020273541060.html">05</a> &nbsp;Apple: According to the WSJ, Apple allegedly negotiated deals with gaming companies so that their titles would receive prominent App Store placement in exchange for platform exclusivity. Examples cited: "Plants vs. Zombies 2" stayed exclusive to iOS for two months. "Cut the Rope 2" stayed iOS exclusive for three months.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://9to5mac.com/2014/04/19/apple-hires-rising-medical-star-divya-nag-with-fda-approval-product-development-experience/">06</a> &nbsp;Apple: They recently hired Divya Nag, who 9to5Mac describes as "a rising star in the medical device community". No word as to what she'll actually do at the company, but it's said she's joined Apple's "Medical Technology Team".</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://recode.net/2014/04/18/beats-bites-the-bullet-and-starts-selling-subscriptions-from-apples-app/">07</a> &nbsp;Beats: This Spotify competitor is in the press because they've decided to start selling subscriptions to their service inside their iOS app. That means they're giving 30% of their revenues to Apple. Rhapsody and Rdio also do this, but Spotify, arguably the King of the Hill, does not.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/money/columnist/bartiromo/2014/04/20/bartiromo-blackberry-john-chen/7872801/">08</a> &nbsp;BlackBerry: In an interview with USA Today, the CEO of BlackBerry revealed that a "BlackBerry Classic" QWERTY smartphone will come out in November.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.scmp.com/business/china-business/article/1486324/coolpad-obtains-fresh-funds-4g-smartphone-expansion">09</a> &nbsp;Coolpad: You've probably never heard of this company, but they're China's third biggest smartphone maker, and they're not that far behind Lenovo (1% difference in market share). They raised $175 million on Friday.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140421PR200.html">10</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: According to DisplaySearch, 2014 will be the first year where revenues generated from the sale of mobile display panels (phones, tablets, laptops) will surpass revenues generated from television panels.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140418PD207.html">11</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: Apple was responsible for 47.77% of Foxconn's revenues in 2012. Last year, that number went up to 50.63%.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140421PD208.html">12</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: Buried in this article about alternative uses for displays was this interesting data point: "Samsung said 55% of a 5.7-inch AMOLED panel's costs are for materials and components while the percentage is 81% for 55-inch LCD panels." In other words, AMOLED panels are still priced high in order to recuperate R&amp;D costs.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140421PD204.html">13</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: HTC will allegedly make the next Nexus tablet, not ASUS, and it'll have an 8.0 inch panel.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://recode.net/2014/04/20/here-comes-facebooks-ad-network-mobile-ads-launching-this-month/#">14</a> &nbsp;Facebook: Re/code says that Facebook will announce a mobile ad network at their F8 conference later this month.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/18/facebook-location-advertising/">15</a> &nbsp;Facebook: They've confirmed to TechCrunch that the recently launched "Nearby Friends" feature will be used to serve advertising "in the future". No further details were mentioned.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://thenextweb.com/facebook/2014/04/18/facebooks-paper-ios-updated-birthdays-events-photo-comments-group-updates/">16</a> &nbsp;Facebook: They've updated Paper (remember Paper?) with enough new features that it's almost reached parity with the original Facebook app. And yes, it's still iOS only.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://mtksj.com/html/MTKshoujizixun/7457.html">17</a> &nbsp;Google: A rumor with some incredibly sketchy sourcing is being passed around the internet like wildfire. It says Google will unveil a $100 Nexus device this year powered by a MediaTek processor. Strong skepticism urged.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/19/google-issues-refunds-and-an-extra-5-play-store-credit-to-android-users-who-bought-the-phony-virus-shield-app/">18</a> &nbsp;Google: Some shady developer wrote an anti-virus app that did absolutely nothing, yet more than 10,000 people spent $3.99 on it. Google's decided to not only refund everyone their money, but also give them $5 of Google Play Store credit.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-17/htc-s-wang-parachutes-back-to-reverse-falling-phone-sales.html?cmpid=yhoo">19</a> &nbsp;HTC: Buried in this WSJ article on HTC's co-founder is this data point: "When last year's model of the One was released, it sold about 5 million phones in its first two months, compared with 20 million for Samsung's Galaxy S4."</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bgr.in/manufacturers/htc/htc-one-m8-google-play-edition-launched-in-india-for-rs-49900/">20</a> &nbsp;HTC: The Google Play Edition version of HTC's flagship phone, the M8, has launched in India. This is the first time a Google Play Edition device has launched outside the United States. What is a GPE device? It's a phone that runs stock Android instead of the custom software the device maker wrote.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://newsosaur.blogspot.fi/2014/04/print-ads-fell-86-at-papers-in-2013-naa.html">21</a> &nbsp;Journalism: "Print advertising at the nation's newspapers fell 8.6% to $17.3 billion in 2013, according to statistics released today by the Newspaper Association of America." To put some perspective on that $17.3 billion figure, print ads peaked in 2005 at $47.4 billion.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://blog.linkedin.com/2014/04/18/the-next-three-billion/">22</a> &nbsp;LinkedIn: They now have 300 million users; 100 million are in the United States.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://qctimes.com/news/local/government-and-politics/microsoft-brings-billion-data-center-to-iowa/article_b29695d2-df8b-597c-9fb0-37cc20dba09f.html">23</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: They're going to build a $1.13 billion data center in Des Moines, Iowa. It'll take four to five years to complete.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.winbeta.org/news/eleven-new-microsoft-stores-set-open-may-did-your-city-make-list">24</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: They're going to open 11 "Specialty Stores" across the U.S. next month. Translation: Mall kiosks.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.xataka.com.mx/celulares-y-smartphones/exclusiva-moto-e-el-proximo-smartphone-de-motorola">25</a> &nbsp;Motorola: Rumor has it that Motorola will launch a 4.3 inch smartphone during the next few weeks called the "Moto E". Unlike the Moto G and Moto X, the Moto E will allegedly have a microSD card slot.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://recode.net/2014/04/18/nike-denies-fuelband-shutdown-but-layoffs-could-reveal-new-cracks-in-wearables-market/">26</a> &nbsp;Nike: During the weekend, CNET published an article saying Nike wants to kill its smartwatch division because they don't want to compete with Apple's upcoming iWatch. Re/code says that's not what they're hearing. Some people have been let go, yes, but the company is still debating what to do with their FuelBand product.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.fonearena.com/blog/101347/obi-mobiles-backed-by-former-apple-ceo-john-scully-launched-in-india.html">27</a> &nbsp;Obi Mobiles: Former Apple CEO John Sculley has launched a new smartphone brand in India: Obi. They haven't really announced anything other than the company logo, and that $20 million will be invested this year to build a supply chain.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.engadget.com/2014/04/20/samsung-com-outage-sds-fire/">28</a> &nbsp;Samsung: On Sunday, one of Samsung's buildings in Korea caught on fire. No one was hurt, thankfully, but said fire caused Samsung's website to go down and error messages to start appearing on Samsung phones, tablets, and televisions. This brings up a serious question: Is one data center powering all of Samsung's services?</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702304311204579506531408901234">29</a> &nbsp;Samsung: Remember that free music streaming service Samsung launched back in March? According to the WSJ, it's been downloaded 380,000 times. A premium version will come "soon", though no price and feature list was mentioned.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-to-add-premium-subscription-milk-music">30</a> &nbsp;Samsung: The company accidentally published an infographic saying that they'll offer a premium $3.99 per month tier for their music service, Samsung Milk. Other than being "ad-free", it's not yet known what else that $3.99 gets you.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-27037504">31</a> &nbsp;Television: The BBC has written an article that explains why various online video streaming services are creating their own television programs. Spoiler: People are not stupid, they prefer shows that feature a story arc that lasts longer than one episode.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/education-27094931">32</a> &nbsp;UK: According to a survey of 7,500 teachers, over 20% of them say they've been harassed via social media. Shockingly, 27% of the negative online comments are from parents, not students.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://venturebeat.com/2014/04/18/ahead-of-its-twc-merger-comcast-may-sell-5m-subscribers-to-charter/">33</a> &nbsp;USA: According to an article from the Financial Times that's behind a paywall, Comcast and Time Warner Cable are thinking about giving five million of their subscribers to Charter in order to receive permission to merge.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-china-27076645">34</a> &nbsp;China: The country's Environmental Protection Ministry published a report on Friday that says "16.1% of China's soil and 19.4% of its arable land [shows] contamination." Samples from roughly two-thirds of China's land area were captured between 2005 and 2013, so it's safe to say this data is accurate, and disturbing.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-27093121">35</a> &nbsp;Greece: This 85 second video shows how two churches on the Greek island of Chios celebrate Easter in their own peculiar way. Spoiler: They launch rockets at each other. The goal is to hit the other church's bell.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-27076991">36</a> &nbsp;Netherlands: An unnamed 35 year old man has just been charged with "extortion, internet luring, criminal harassment, and child pornography." Why? Because in In 2012, Amanda Todd, a 15 year old Canadian girl, killed herself after being blackmailed by this sick bastard. He befriended her, asked her to perform sexual acts in front of her webcam, and then used said material to control her.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-south-asia-27078194">37</a> &nbsp;Pakistan: One of the schools in the country's capital has decided to name their library after Osama Bin Laden, calling him both a "martyr" and a "hero". The local government is not happy about this, because it (obviously) sends the world the wrong message about Islam.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-27081279">38</a> &nbsp;South Korea: Lee Joon-seok, age 69, was the captain of the ferry that sank. He's officially been arrested and "faces charges including negligence of duty and violation of maritime law."</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-27100056">39</a> &nbsp;South Korea: The latest numbers from the ferry disaster: 64 dead, 238 missing, 174 rescued.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-27065916">40</a> &nbsp;UK: In the mid-1970s, roughly 1,800 people developed malignant melanoma every year. Today, the number is closer to 13,000. Putting those figures another way: In the mid-1970s, three out of every 100,000 people in Britain were diagnosed with malignant melanoma. Today, it's 17 out of every 100,000 people. Cheap holidays to Southern Europe and tan bed abuse are being blamed.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27100284">41</a> &nbsp;USA: Kraft is recalling 96,000 pounds (43,545 kilograms) of hotdogs. They're not dangerous, they're simply mislabeled as "Classic Wieners" instead of "Cheese Dogs". Word of advice: Buy hotdogs from your local butcher. They're guaranteed to taste a million times better.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-27027200">42</a> &nbsp;USA: SpaceX successfully launched two tons of supplies and food to the International Space Station on Friday. This is their third mission in conjunction with NASA. Only reason I'm putting this story on Tab Dump is because I love watching rockets take off, so be sure to watch the video.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-27026521">43</a> &nbsp;Venezuela: According to the Venezuelan Plastic Surgeons Association, 30% of women between the ages of 18 and 50 are paying people to inject silicone into their butts, despite the fact the government banned the dangerous procedure in 2006.</p><p><a target="_blank" href="http://tabdump.com/support">44</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a target="_blank" href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 18: 40 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 07:38:57 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/18/april-18-40-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:5350d696e4b03c887de01780</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/sponsor">01</a> &nbsp;This spot is reserved for sponsors. If you want more details, <a href="mailto:stefan@whatthebit.com?subject=Sponsor">send me an email</a>.</p><p><a href="http://thenextweb.com/media/2014/04/17/amazon-partners-hulu-plus-crackle-showtime-anytime-integrate-catalogs-fire-tvs-voice-search/">02</a> &nbsp;Amazon: One of the key selling points of Amazon's new set top box is voice search. Unfortunately, said feature only searches videos offered by Amazon. That will change "this summer" with Hulu Plus, Crackle, and Showtime adding support. Netflix, however, is still missing.</p><p><a href="http://youtu.be/AYCSkTDXKRc">03</a> &nbsp;Apple: Different car makers are implementing CarPlay in different ways. This two and a half minute video from The Verge shows several of those variations, including one that doesn't even use a touch screen.</p><p><a href="http://9to5mac.com/2014/04/17/ipad-mini-with-retina-display-hits-the-apple-refurbished-store-for-the-first-time-starts-at-339/">04</a> &nbsp;Apple: They've finally started selling refurbished iPad mini Retina units. The 16 GB model is $339, which is $60 cheaper than a new device. A good friend of mine never buys new Apple equipment, only refurbished stock, and I've never heard him complain.</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/17/dropbox-acquires-cloud-photos-startup-loom-service-to-be-shut-down-as-users-transferred-to-carousel/">05</a> &nbsp;Dropbox: They bought two companies yesterday. The first is Loom. They have seven employees and make a photo management app for iOS and Mac users. The second is Hackpad, which TechCrunch calls "a lightweight, document-collaboration web and mobile application." No financial figures were disclosed.</p><p><a href="https://newsroom.fb.com/news/2014/04/introducing-a-new-optional-feature-called-nearby-friends/">06</a> &nbsp;Facebook: They launched a new feature for their Android and iOS apps that allows you to see if your friends are nearby. What's great about this news isn't the feature itself, but how it was presented. Facebook went out of their way to emphasize, repeatedly, that this is optional and fully opt-in.</p><p><a href="http://blog.flickr.net/2014/04/17/introducing-flickr-3-0-for-iphone-and-android/">07</a> &nbsp;Flickr: They've launched a completely redesigned app for Android and iOS. Spoiler: It looks like Instagram, but with a dark theme.</p><p><a href="http://9to5google.com/2014/04/17/try-before-you-buy-google-launches-home-try-on-program-for-glass/">08</a> &nbsp;Google: They're now sending people dummy Google Glass units so they can try them on before forking over $1,500. When you order the dummy units, Google puts a $50 hold on your credit card, which is released once you return the glasses.</p><p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-18/htc-said-to-hire-former-samsung-u-s-marketing-executive.html">09</a> &nbsp;HTC: According to Bloomberg, HTC has "hired the former head of marketing at Samsung Electronics' U.S. mobile phone business as an adviser to Chairman Cher Wang." His name is Paul Golden, and on his LinkedIn profile, he says he "created and launched the highly successful Galaxy brand for Samsung." Marketing is one of HTC's biggest weaknesses, so this is rather exciting.</p><p><a href="http://thenextweb.com/asia/2014/04/17/line-launches-creators-market-let-upload-sell-stickers-users/">10</a> &nbsp;LINE: My favorite chat app has launched a sticker store that enables people to sell their own stickers. The company will take a 50% cut, and while the store only works in Indonesia, Japan, Taiwan, and Thailand at the moment, there are plans to expand.</p><p><a href="http://news.xbox.com/2014/04/xbox-one-march-npd">11</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: Yesterday, Sony said they sold seven million PS4 consoles. Today, Microsoft is saying they've sold five million XBOX One units.</p><p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-17/vodafone-said-to-be-in-talks-with-netflix-for-content.html">12</a> &nbsp;Netflix: According to Bloomberg, they're talking to Vodafone, the world's second largest wireless operator, about a bundling deal. This isn't exactly a new concept. For example, Vodafone UK will gladly offer you a mobile phone contract that includes "free" access to Spotify Premium.</p><p><a href="http://www.nokia.com/global/2520-charger/">13</a> &nbsp;Nokia: If you bought a Nokia Lumia 2520 tablet, what's wrong with you? No, but seriously, the company is issuing a recall over the charger. The plastic cap covering the metal contacts can fall off, and if you touch a piece of metal that's plugged into the wall, you know what happens next. Note this impacts roughly 30,000 chargers, so is that how many of these tablets were sold in total?</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/17/us-samsung-elec-globalfoundaries-idUSBREA3G1L620140417?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">14</a> &nbsp;Samsung: In an effort to compete with (and piss off) TSMC, they're going to license their newest chip making technology to GlobalFoundries. More importantly, Samsung says they expect to begin "mass production of foundry chips using 14 nanometer FinFET technology in the fourth quarter." Today's top of the line smartphone chips use 28 nanometer technology. Qualcomm recently announced 20 nanometer chips, but they're not shipping until 2015.</p><p><a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/3029119/most-innovative-companies/tencent-the-secretive-chinese-tech-giant-that-can-rival-facebook-a#!">15</a> &nbsp;Tencent: Fast Company has published what many people are calling the definitive article on Tencent, China's largest internet company. I haven't read the article yet because it's incredibly long, but I plan to during the weekend.</p><p><a href="http://www.hurriyetdailynews.com/twitter-posts-to-be-blurred-to-eliminate-malicious-content-minister-says.aspx?NewsCatID=339&amp;nID=65200&amp;pageID=238">16</a> &nbsp;Twitter: According to Turkish Communications Minister Lütfi Elvan, Twitter has deleted over 200 tweets, per request of Turkish authorities.</p><p><a href="https://blog.twitter.com/2014/a-new-way-to-promote-mobile-apps-to-1-billion-devices-both-on-and-off-twitter">17</a> &nbsp;Twitter: They've launched two ad products. The first, ads in the Twitter app that point to other apps. Some of you might have already seen them. And the second, a generic mobile ad network powered by last year's MoPub acquisition (<a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/09/09/twitter-said-to-acquire-mopub/">allegedly for $350 million</a>).</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/17/us-usa-wireless-fcc-idUSBREA3G1VW20140417">18</a> &nbsp;USA: Yesterday, AT&amp;T threatened to not participate in the FCC's 2015 spectrum auction if there were rules in place limiting how much spectrum they could buy. Today, the Head of the FCC, Tom Wheeler, said he doesn't care.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27066024">19</a> &nbsp;Weibo: China's version of Twitter went public on the Nasdaq stock exchange yesterday. Their share price went up almost 20% by the end of the day.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26925271">20</a> &nbsp;Belgium: The brains of 21 art students and 23 regular people were scanned and compared. Turns out artists have "significantly more grey matter in an area of the brain called the precuneus in the parietal lobe." Translation: Artists have better motor skills.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-27056809">21</a> &nbsp;Brazil: Scientists have discovered insects with confusing genital characteristics. The women have "penises" called "gynosomes" that they stick into male "vaginas" which are said to hold sperm. But the most impressive discovery, to me at least, is that these insects have sex for 70 hours at a time.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-27076019">22</a> &nbsp;India: A Delhi surgeon has just reported that he has successfully removed 12 bars of gold, weighing almost 400 grams total, from a man's stomach. That's certainly one way to hide it.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-27065532">23</a> &nbsp;Iran: They agreed to cut their supply of enriched uranium by half earlier this year, and they've complied, so the United States is unfreezing Iranian funds worth roughly $450 million.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-27075632">24</a> &nbsp;South Korea: The latest numbers on the ferry disaster: 26 people dead. 179 people rescued. 270 still missing.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-27054366">25</a> &nbsp;Space: Kepler 186f is being described by scientists as the "most Earth-like planet yet". It's roughly 10% larger than our planet, it's 500 light years away, it has an orbit of roughly 130 days, and it's believed to be a rocky planet that may hold water.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-27063715">26</a> &nbsp;UK: The King's College of London has been tracking 7,771 children since 1958 to study the effects of bullying. Their data shows those who were frequently bullied at a young age never really recover from the harassment. They often face depression, anxiety, and even have suicidal thoughts. Bullied children also end up turning into less educated adults, and thus earn less.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-27063796">27</a> &nbsp;UK: Where's the best place to put all the CO2 that your coal burning power planet spits out? Under the ground, of course. The White Rose carbon capture and storage (CCS) project will be awarded $415 million in June by the European Union. Once complete, said plant will be able to power 630,000 homes, and 90% of the CO2 it outputs (two million tons a year!) will be stored in undersea rock formations.</p><p><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/infocus/2014/04/battling-for-control-of-eastern-ukraine/100719/">28</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: The Atlantic has published 36 photos of the latest events in Ukraine. Some are quite graphic.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-27075251">29</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: There are 11 cities in Ukraine that want to pull a Crimea. Not one, not two, but 11. This two and a half minute video features interviews with the locals, who are screaming from the top of their lungs that they want to be Russian.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-27075713">30</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: You've probably read about the "successful" talks in Geneva regarding the Ukrainian situation. Well, the President of the United States just said "I don't think, given past performance, that we can count" on Russia to uphold their end of the bargain.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27069715">31</a> &nbsp;USA: Alfa Romeo will start selling cars in the United States again this year, after leaving the market in mid-90s. Before you get all excited, here's the sad quote: "The company says it expects to sell just under a thousand regular 4C models, at a base price of $54,000, by the end of this year."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-27069611">32</a> &nbsp;USA: An unnamed man urinated in a water reservoir that serves the city of Portland, Oregon. What does Portland decide to do with said reservoir? Empty it. All 38 million gallons (143 million liters).</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-27074289">33</a> &nbsp;USA: Barack Obama has announced "more than eight million Americans have enrolled for health coverage, with 35% of those under age 35."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27075296">34</a> &nbsp;USA: Keith Seilhan, age 47, will have to pay a $224,118 fine for insider trading. He sold $1 million of BP shares after finding out just how bad the Gulf of Mexico oil spill was. Note that he was in charge of the "initial cleanup operations."</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/17/us-michaelsstores-cybercrime-idUSBREA3G27N20140417?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">35</a> &nbsp;USA: Michaels, the arts and crafts store chain, says 2.6 million credit card numbers may have been stolen. This obviously isn't Target scale damage, but it's still a disturbing trend.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-27058552">36</a> &nbsp;USA: North Dakota's ban on abortion has been overturned.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/17/us-walmart-euronet-idUSBREA3F1ZM20140417?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">37</a> &nbsp;USA: Walmart is launching a competitor to Western Union called "Walmart-2-Walmart". It'll only work in the United States. I have just one question: Do people not know that the U.S. Postal Service offers extremely cheap money orders?</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/blogs-magazine-monitor-27039192">38</a> &nbsp;World: 420 is universally understood to be slang for marijuana. What's the origin story of that number? In 1971, a bunch of guys from Northern California would always smoke weed together after school at roughly 04:20 PM every day. They started to use that term amongst themselves, and the rest is history.</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">39</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p><p><a href="http://tinyletter.com/tabdump">40</a> &nbsp;One more thing: Tradition dictates I remind you <a href="http://tinyletter.com/tabdump">Tab Dump via email</a> exists on Friday.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 17: 44 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 08:56:46 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/17/april-17-44-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:534f9751e4b09b70f38ef997</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/sponsor">01</a> &nbsp;This spot is reserved for sponsors. If you want more details, <a href="mailto:stefan@whatthebit.com?subject=Sponsor">send me an email</a>.</p><p><a href="http://thevoicemail.wordpress.com/2014/04/17/episode-094/">02</a> &nbsp;Podcast: The latest episode of The Voicemail, which James Whatley and I record every week, is live. We covered the iPhone 6 leak, the LG G3 leak, the Galaxy S5's fingerprint scanner, and answered several listener questions.</p><p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-17/apple-said-to-prepare-song-id-feature-for-iphone-software.html">03</a> &nbsp;Apple: Bloomberg says Apple will partner with Shazam in order to add song identification to iOS 8. It should be noted that the ability to identify the song you're listening to is already baked into <a href="http://lifehacker.com/5985622/google-search-for-android-can-now-tell-you-what-song-is-playing">Android</a> and <a href="http://youtu.be/ZwxVlBUD2Wo">Windows Phone</a>.</p><p><a href="http://www.macrumors.com/2014/04/16/8gb-iphone5c-six-countries/">04</a> &nbsp;Apple: They launched the 8 GB iPhone 5c in 16 new European countries.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/16/new-app-frontback-arrives-on-android-to-bring-context-to-your-selfies/">05</a> &nbsp;Apps: Frontback, an app that combines a photo from both your rear and front facing cameras in one image, is finally available on Android. Sadly, the insane hype it generated when it came out for iOS over half a year ago has all but disappeared. Note that less than 10,000 people have installed it.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/16/us-usa-wireless-spectrum-idUSBREA3F1AD20140416">06</a> &nbsp;AT&amp;T: The FCC wants to auction off some spectrum next year, but they don't want the big wireless operators to buy it all up. This has AT&amp;T so pissed off that they're threatening to not participate in the auction at all. The exact rules of the auction aren't set in stone, however, and they're expected to be finalized on May 15th.</p><p><a href="http://chrome.blogspot.fi/2014/04/chrome-remote-desktop-goes-mobile.html">07</a> &nbsp;Google: Accessing your computer with VNC or Microsoft Remote Desktop isn't new, but Google is now offering a free first party solution called "Chrome Remote Desktop". Just install a Chrome extension on your Mac or PC, install an app on your Android device, and you're done.</p><p><a href="http://www.ifixit.com/Teardown/Project+Tango+Teardown/23835">08</a> &nbsp;Google: iFixit has torn apart Project Tango, Google's prototype smartphone that doubles as a pocket 3D scanner. They found a chip in the device from PrimeSense, a company that Apple purchased last year.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/16/significant-google-app-redesign-allegedly-slips-out-in-series-of-screenshots/">09</a> &nbsp;Google: Images have leaked of a completely redesigned Google+ app for Android. The design matches the recently leaked Gmail and Calendar apps. Expect design to be a major focus of Google I/O, which kicks off on June 25th.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/16/google-calendar-for-android-finally-suggests-locations-of-nearby-places-and-lets-you-join-video-calls-in-hangouts-apk-download/">10</a> &nbsp;Google: The Calendar app in Android now uses the Google Maps backend to let you enter the locations of your meetings using plain English. Example: Whole Foods on Ocean Avenue.</p><p><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/apr/16/google-building-digital-superstate-german-media-dopfner">11</a> &nbsp;Google: The Head of Europe's largest newspaper publisher, Mathias Döpfner, says Google's business model is a "protection racket" and that their motto should be "if you don't want us to finish you off, you better pay."</p><p><a href="http://googleonlinesecurity.blogspot.fi/2014/04/street-view-and-recaptcha-technology.html">12</a> &nbsp;Google: The technology they've developed to read the numbers on buildings that are photographed with a Google Street View car can apparently decode CAPTCHAs with an accuracy rate of 99%. So why are websites still using CAPTCHAs then?</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/16/google-misses-in-q1-with-revenue-of-15-42b-eps-of-6-27-as-its-cost-per-click-fell-9/">13</a> &nbsp;Google: Their Q1 2014 financial results are out. Here are the two numbers people are focusing on: "Google's recorded cost-per-click average rate fell 9%. Total paid clicks rose 26% year-over-year."</p><p><a href="https://plus.google.com/+android/posts/86JHD2mWW6k">14</a> &nbsp;Google: They've ripped the camera app out of Android and are now providing it as a download via the Play Store to any device running Android 4.4 KitKat or higher. Best feature? It won't allow you to record videos in portrait mode.</p><p><a href="http://googledevelopers.blogspot.fi/2014/04/a-conversation-about-design.html">15</a> &nbsp;Google: Think Google I/O is an event just for developers? The company has announced a series of "sessions and workshops focused on design and designers." Make sure to watch the Jony Ive inspired videos.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-27058143">16</a> &nbsp;Heartbleed: Stephen Arthuro Solis-Reyes, 19 years old, has officially become the first person to be arrested for maliciously using the Heartbleed bug. He's accused of hacking into Canada's version of the IRS and stealing over 900 social security numbers.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/16/us-ibm-results-idUSBREA3F1R720140416?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">17</a> &nbsp;IBM: "IBM reported its lowest quarterly revenue in five years on Wednesday as the company struggles with falling demand for its storage and server products."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-27052773">18</a> &nbsp;Japan: For reasons I don't understand, a Japanese researcher has invented a pair of glasses with two screens that face outward instead of inward. Said glasses "could be used to simulate emotional reactions", but why?</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/16/5619884/lg-golden-g3-launch">19</a> &nbsp;LG: The Verge has obtained a photo of the retail box that LG's next flagship phone, the LG G3, will ship in. LG also confirmed to The Verge that "its next phone will feature a 2560 x 1440 screen resolution."</p><p><a href="http://www.koreaherald.com/view.php?ud=20140416001164">20</a> &nbsp;LG: They're going to start making their own chips "soon", possibly this quarter. And by "make", I mean design. TSMC will be responsible for the actual manufacturing. Going vertical is what all the cool kids seem to be doing these days.</p><p><a href="http://www.computerworld.com/s/article/print/9247708/Microsoft_slashes_Windows_XP_custom_support_prices_just_days_before_axing_public_patches">21</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: They're slashing the price of Windows XP support so that they don't appear to be too greedy. One example given was an unnamed client with 10,000 computers running XP. Microsoft originally wanted $2 million to continue support, but they dropped that down to $250,000.</p><p><a href="http://www.bing.com/blogs/site_blogs/b/search/archive/2014/04/16/bing-com-gets-more-personal.aspx">22</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: They've changed the Bing homepage. It now has what can best be described as a ticker showing "cards" similar to those Google uses in Google Now.</p><p><a href="http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/telecom/nokia-likely-to-leave-india-plant-out-of-microsoft-deal/articleshow/33830793.cms">23</a> &nbsp;Nokia: They have a factory in India that's delaying the Microsoft acquisition, leading local media to predict that the plant will stay with Nokia and not be transferred to Microsoft. What's the issue here? Nokia and the Indian government are embroiled in a tax dispute.</p><p><a href="http://thenextweb.com/insider/2014/04/17/amazon-partners-samsung-launch-custom-kindle-e-book-service-galaxy-devices/">24</a> &nbsp;Samsung: Amazon will make a custom Kindle app for Samsung phones. Owners of the Galaxy S5 will be able to download 12 Kindle books a year for free. No, you can't have any book, Amazon will give you a choice of four books every month.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-galaxy-s5-launch-day-sales-double-galaxy-s4-one-british-retailer">25</a> &nbsp;Samsung: Phones 4u, a fairly large independent UK mobile phone retailer, has published a press release saying that sales of the Galaxy S5 on launch day were double that of Galaxy S4 sales on its respective launch day.</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/16/5619724/samsung-android-wear-watch-and-google-less-phone-coming-this-year">26</a> &nbsp;Samsung: They've confirmed to The Verge that they're going to make an Android Wear powered smartwatch and launch it this year. Note that all of Samsung's smartwatches thus far only work with Samsung phones. Will an Android Wear powered Samsung watch work with any Android device?</p><p><a href="http://blog.us.playstation.com/2014/04/16/ps4-hits-7-million-globally/">27</a> &nbsp;Sony: PlayStation 4 sales have officially hit seven million units.</p><p><a href="http://torrentfreak.com/spotify-starts-shutting-down-its-massive-p2p-network-140416/">28</a> &nbsp;Spotify: Without peer-to-peer technology, Spotify couldn't have launched back in 2008 with their limited resources. But now that they're all grown-up, they've announced that they're going to switch from P2P to dedicated servers by the end of this year.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/chinarealtime/2014/04/16/billions-of-hours-wasted-candy-crush-comes-to-china/">29</a> &nbsp;Tencent: China's biggest internet company is partnering with King to bring Candy Crush to China this summer. No financial details were mentioned. Tencent will promote the app on WeChat, which has 355 million monthly users.</p><p><a href="http://gigaom.com/2014/04/16/time-warner-bets-big-on-easy-and-secure-wi-fi-rolling-out-hotspot-2-0-across-its-network/">30</a> &nbsp;Time Warner Cable: This American television and internet service provider has rolled out Hotspot 2.0 technology across their 33,000 WiFi access points. Translation: Connect to TWC's WiFi network once, and you'll never have to fiddle with settings or a login screen again. Expect to hear more ISPs talking about Hotspot 2.0 in the future.</p><p><a href="http://www.wired.co.uk/news/archive/2014-04/16/watch-on-sky-twitter-tool">31</a> &nbsp;Twitter: The UK television company Sky is allowing their subscribers to "start watching or remotely record a TV show" simply by clicking a tweet. This capability is apparently already live in the United States with Comcast, but it's the first I've heard of it.</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/04/16/marissa-mayers-secret-plan-to-get-apple-to-dump-google-and-default-to-yahoo-mobile-search/">32</a> &nbsp;Yahoo!: Re/code says Marissa Mayer is in the process of building a mobile search engine, and that her end goal is to convince Apple to set that search engine as the default in Safari on the iPhone and iPad.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-27058948">33</a> &nbsp;Argentina: Police have rescued a 15 year old girl that's been kept locked in a garage for nine years and fed only bread and water. No word as to what will happen to her foster parents, but I'm personally hoping for the worst.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-27049659">34</a> &nbsp;Europe: The first images from Europe's new Copernicus space program have just been published. The Sentinel-1a satellite that captured said images was launched on April 3rd.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27060201">35</a> &nbsp;France: Earlier this week, I wrote about whiskey makers <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-scotland-scotland-business-26974320">losing money</a> because of China's new government policies on excessive gift giving. Now it's cognac's turn. Remy Cointreau just issued a warning, saying full year profits will plunge by a third, and they specifically called out China.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-27048242">36</a> &nbsp;Malaysia: The Bluefin-21 submersible that's searching for the MH370 flight recorders has now had its first successful mission. The first two missions ran into issues, but with this third one, everything went to plan. Sadly, nothing has been found.</p><p><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/infocus/2014/04/south-korea-ferry-sinks-hundreds-missing/100718/">37</a> &nbsp;South Korea: The Atlantic has published 23 photos of the ferry disaster. These pictures are not easy on the eyes.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-27056653">38</a> &nbsp;South Korea: The latest numbers from the ferry sinking: Nine people have died. Dozens have been injured. 170 have been rescued. 287 are still missing. What's terrifying is that over 325 of the passengers on that ferry were students from the same High School.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-27056698">39</a> &nbsp;Space: Scientists say they may have witnessed the birth of Saturn's 63rd moon. They're naming it Peggy.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-england-cumbria-27055750">40</a> &nbsp;UK: More than 10 cars have had their tires punctured in a six month period in one town. Crazy kids, right? Security footage shows it was actually a dog that really hates cars.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27047970">41</a> &nbsp;UK: When you order lamb at a restaurant, there's a 30% chance it's actually not lamb. That's what the Foods Standards Agency found after testing 145 samples. They say they'll test 300 samples next month.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-27053500">42</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: "Pro-Russian militants in eastern Ukraine have seized six Ukrainian armored vehicles, the defense ministry in Kiev says." Let's not bullshit each other, these are Russian soldiers, not armed countryside folks who like Putin.</p><p><a href="http://www.foliomag.com/2014/playboy-re-releases-its-first-issue-60-years-later#.U09fhOaSzFc">43</a> &nbsp;USA: Playboy is going to republish the very first issue of their magazine (December 1953) and sell it for $10.</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">44</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 16: 46 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 07:55:20 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/16/april-16-46-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:534e376de4b0ec6f487473f9</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/sponsor">01</a> &nbsp;This spot is reserved for <a href="http://tabdump.com/sponsor">sponsors</a>. If you want more details, <a href="mailto:stefan@whatthebit.com?subject=Sponsor">send me an email</a>.</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702303887804579501411932558776?mg=reno64-wsj&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fonline.wsj.com%2Farticle%2FSB10001424052702303887804579501411932558776.html">02</a> &nbsp;Alibaba: The WSJ has produced an amazing four minute video explaining what Alibaba is and why they want to raise $15 billion from their IPO. Spoiler: Alibaba's transaction volume is "more than double the size of Amazon, triple the size of eBay, and one-third larger than the value of all the transactions last year at the two U.S.-based e-commerce giants combined."</p><p><a href="http://bgr.com/2014/04/15/amazon-smartphone-photos-specs-kindle-phone-exclusive/">03</a> &nbsp;Amazon: The first images of Amazon's smartphone have leaked. Note that the device is in an incredibly thick case that makes it impossible to see anything meaningful. Earlier this week, the WSJ said Amazon would unveil the phone in June and ship it in September.</p><p><a href="http://appleinsider.com/articles/14/04/15/closer-look-at-alleged-iphone-6-front-panel-suggests-51-screen-with-169-ratio">04</a> &nbsp;Apple: A photo of what's alleged to be the front of the iPhone 6 has leaked. Luckily, someone held an iPhone 5/5s next to said component for scale. Using some quick math, it looks like the iPhone 6 will have a 5.1 inch display. In other words, forget about the 4.7 inch and 5.5 inch iPhone rumor, there can only be one Highlander.</p><p><a href="http://www.macrumors.com/2014/04/15/iphone-6-mockups-electronics-fair/">05</a> &nbsp;Apple: At the Hong Kong Electronics Fair, a metal brick that allegedly looks like the next iPhone is being shown off. Said brick was made so case makers have a mold to use to create their products.</p><p><a href="http://www.engadget.com/2014/04/15/pioneer-carplay-update/">06</a> &nbsp;Apple: CarPlay support will come to Pioneer's NEX series of aftermarket consoles (ranges from $700 to $1,500) via a firmware update this summer.</p><p><a href="http://blog.appannie.com/app-annie-index-market-q1-2014/">07</a> &nbsp;Apps: App Annie has released a slew of data points, here are my favorite three: Google Play downloads in Q1 2014 were 45% higher than iOS App Store downloads, yet iOS App Store revenues were 85% higher than Google Play Store revenues. Chinese iOS App Store revenues grew 70% sequentially (Q1 2014 versus Q4 2013).</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/15/bbc-iplayer-users-can-now-download-videos-on-any-android-device-running-android-4-0-or-higher/">08</a> &nbsp;Apps: BBC iPlayer for Android now allows you to download content for offline use. This functionality was previously limited to a handful of phones. Now it works on nearly every Android device out there.</p><p><a href="http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2014/04/15/exclusive-automattic-seeking-to-raise-more-than-100-million/">09</a> &nbsp;Automattic: The company that makes WordPress is allegedly looking to raise $100 million to $150 million. There's also a pretty eye opening data point: "WordPress now powers 22% of the world's websites, up from 19% last July."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-27032221">10</a> &nbsp;Bitcoin: Mark Karpeles, the guy in charge of MtGox, is supposed to attend a hearing in Washington D.C. this Friday, but he refuses to to travel to the United States.</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/article_email/SB10001424052702303663604579504691512965308-lMyQjAxMTA0MDEwNTExNDUyWj">11</a> &nbsp;Bitcoin: MtGox "has asked a Tokyo court to allow it to be liquidated." Translation: It's dead.</p><p><a href="http://torrentfreak.com/game-of-thrones-sets-new-torrent-swarm-record-140415/">12</a> &nbsp;BitTorrent: The second episode of the fourth season of "Game of Thrones" set a couple of BitTorrent records: "More than 193,000 people shared a single copy yesterday evening, and roughly 1.5 million people downloaded the episode during the first day."</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/15/us-nanthealth-blackberry-idUSBREA3E0SE20140415?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">13</a> &nbsp;BlackBerry: They've spent an undisclosed amount of money to buy a stake in a digital health start-up called NantHealth. Said start-up offers services to 250 hospitals and connects to 16,000 medical devices.</p><p><a href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140413PD200.html">14</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: "Apple had a dominant market share of 58.7% for 4G smartphones sold in the China market in January-February 2014, followed by Samsung Electronics with 26.4%, Coolpad 9.4%, K-Touch 2.5%, Sony 1.2% and Huawei 0.8%, according to Sino Market Research."</p><p><a href="http://gmailblog.blogspot.fi/2014/04/the-photos-from-your-phone-now-one.html">15</a> &nbsp;Google: In yet another demonstration of why it's good to be vertically integrated, Gmail now allows you to attach pictures that your Android phone has automatically uploaded to Google Photos in the background with just one click.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/15/android-design-head-matias-duarte-talks-about-the-essence-of-design-google-io-and-the-death-of-mobile/">16</a> &nbsp;Google: Matias Duarte, the Head of Android Design, sat down with the Editor in Chief of The Verge for 38 minutes. I haven't watched the video yet, so I can't say whether or not it's worth your time.&nbsp;<strong>Update:</strong> Watched the interview over lunch. Highly recommended.</p><p><a href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/+JennyMurphy/posts/VwT2gDDnAyJ">17</a> &nbsp;Google: The latest Google Glass update enables Bluetooth Low Energy support.</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/15/5615880/building-blocks-how-project-ara-is-reinventing-the-smartphone">18</a> &nbsp;Google: The Verge produced a delightful six minute video about Project Ara, Google's attempt to make a modular phone. I still don't know why anyone would want this, but hopefully Google will find some way to pitch the idea when it goes on sale early next year.</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/article_email/SB10001424052702304117904579499470802467100-lMyQjAxMTA0MDEwNDExNDQyWj">19</a> &nbsp;Google: The WSJ says Google is looking for "enough space to hold more than 3,000 employees" in New York City. That translates to an 80% increase in the number of NYC Google employees.</p><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intels-q1-solid-but-mobile-losses-weigh-7000028477/">20</a> &nbsp;Intel: They published their Q1 2014 financial earnings yesterday. Key data points: $12.8 billion in revenue, $1.9 billion in earnings, the new group labeled "Mobile and Communications" only made $156 million, and "we shipped 5 million tablet processors, making strong progress on our goal of 40 million tablets for 2014."</p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/456041762092376064">21</a> &nbsp;LG: This is an image of a leaked LG Android phone heading to Japan. I'm putting it on Tab Dump because it has practically zero bezels, which is a design trend I think we'll soon start seeing here in the West.</p><p><a href="http://articles.economictimes.indiatimes.com/2014-04-15/news/49155846_1_micromax-informatics-smartphones-samsung-electronics">22</a> &nbsp;Micromax: They've issued a denial about the rumor saying they want to buy a stake in Pantech.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.office.com/2014/04/15/office-365-personal-now-available-and-unlocks-editing-and-document-creation-on-ipad/">23</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: Office 365 Personal is now available. Instead of paying $100 a year or $10 a month to run Office on five computers and five tablets, you can now pay $70 a year or $7 a month and have Office work on one computer and one tablet.</p><p><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/apr/15/motorola-uk-boss-sale-lenovo">24</a> &nbsp;Motorola: The Head of Motorola Mobility UK is resigning. Fun Fact: He found out about the sale to Lenovo just 30 minutes before the press release hit the wires.</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/14/oculus-rift-shares-developer-hardware-sales-data/">25</a> &nbsp;Oculus: They gave TechCrunch some sales numbers for the Oculus Rift: 25,000 second generation units. 60,000 first generation units. Total: 85,000 units.</p><p><a href="http://www.koreatimes.co.kr/www/news/tech/2014/04/133_155398.html">26</a> &nbsp;Samsung: According to "Samsung insiders", the company has a goal of shipping 35 million GS5 units in Q2 2014. The insiders also say 63 million GS4 units were shipped, but only 40 million were actually sold.</p><p><a href="http://www.koreaherald.com/view.php?ud=20140415001044">27</a> &nbsp;Samsung: The company has unveiled the 210 mAh curved battery that's inside their new Gear Fit wearable device.</p><p><a href="http://youtu.be/sfhLZZWBn5Q">28</a> &nbsp;Samsung: The Galaxy S5's fingerprint scanner can be "hacked" with a piece of tape.</p><p><a href="http://blog.squarespace.com/blog/squarespace-x-general-atlantic">29</a> &nbsp;Squarespace: The service that powers this website just raised $40 million.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/15/us-turkey-twitter-idUSBREA3D0TY20140415">30</a> &nbsp;Twitter: "Twitter will close some accounts in Turkey but will not set up an office there as the government wants, a senior Turkish official said late on Monday."</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/04/15/twitter-taps-google-maps-director-daniel-graf-for-product-vp-role/">31</a> &nbsp;Twitter: Daniel Graf is Twitter's new Vice President of Consumer Product. Before Twitter, he worked at Google, where he was not only in charge of Google Maps, but was also in charge of the team that wrote Google Maps for iOS.</p><p><a href="https://blog.twitter.com/2014/twitter-welcomes-gnip-to-the-flock">32</a> &nbsp;Twitter: Gnip has been using their access to Twitter's firehose to sell social data to companies for years. Twitter decided they would rather sell that data to companies directly, so they just bought Gnip. Price unknown.</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/04/15/apple-google-microsoft-samsung-and-carriers-back-anti-theft-measures-for-smartphones/">33</a> &nbsp;USA: Five of America's biggest wireless operators, and pretty much every handset maker that sells devices in the U.S., have voluntarily agreed to ship phones with "kill-switches" built-in starting July 2015. For what it's worth, both Android and iOS have this feature out of the box, but most people don't configure it.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27043776">34</a> &nbsp;Yahoo!: They published their Q1 2014 financial earnings. Key data points: $312 million in profits, 8% increase in employees (12,400 total), 430 million monthly mobile users.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-27031180">35</a> &nbsp;India: The Supreme Court has ruled that "transgender" is the third official sex. There are an estimated two million people in the country who identify as being transgender.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-27037455">36</a> &nbsp;Iraq: The infamous Abu Ghraib prison has been shut down. Its 2,400 inmates have been relocated to other nearby facilities.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-27045449">37</a> &nbsp;Malaysia: The data captured by the Bluefin-21 submersible has been analyzed. Nothing was found. It's been deployed again, but the U.S. Navy says it could take "from six weeks to two months to scan the search zone."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27031630">38</a> &nbsp;Russia: Because of the situation in Ukraine, Russia's Finance Minister, Anton Siluanov, says the country will have 0% growth this year, and that it's facing "the most difficult conditions since the 2008 crisis."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-27045512">39</a> &nbsp;South Korea: A ferry carrying over 470 people has just sunk. One person has died. 179 people have been rescued. This is an ongoing operation.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-england-london-27038723">40</a> &nbsp;UK: A barber shop that used a photo of Kim Jong-un in an advertisement was visited by two men from the North Korean Embassy. They demanded to speak to the manager. The manager proceeded to throw them out.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-27015348">41</a> &nbsp;UK: Remember that Polish politician I wrote about that wanted to go to the UK and live off £100 a week to see why people from his country are leaving in droves? He's been there since April 5th, he quickly realized his budget was far too small, and he's now working as a handyman. He plans on returning on the 22nd.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27032642">42</a> &nbsp;UK: The Trussell Trust says they handed out 347,000 boxes of food to those less fortunate in 2012. In 2013, that number skyrocketed to 913,000 boxes. Why the rise? The new welfare system.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-27045534">43</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: Vladimir Putin called up Angela Merkel and told her that Ukraine is "on the verge of civil war".</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-27043912">44</a> &nbsp;USA: "The New York Police Department has disbanded a secret program designed to eavesdrop on Muslims to identify potential terrorism threats." The program has been in operation since 2003.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26925249">45</a> &nbsp;World: There's a new field of science out there called "neurogastronomy". Chefs, food companies, whiskey makers, they're all discovering something that we've all instinctively known for years: The environment in which you consume something is often as important as the food or drink you're consuming. Even simple things, like the color and shape of a plate, changes how people perceive their meal.</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">46</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 15: 36 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 07:35:31 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/15/april-15-36-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:534ce14ae4b0b41c59e6a92a</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/sponsor">01</a> &nbsp;This spot is reserved for <a href="http://tabdump.com/sponsor">sponsors</a>. If you want more details, <a href="mailto:stefan@whatthebit.com?subject=Sponsor">send me an email</a>.</p><p><a href="http://www.streetinsider.com/Analyst+Comments/Apple+(AAPL)+Considering+Raising+iPhone+6+Prices/9376072.html">02</a> &nbsp;Apple: According to Jefferies analyst Peter Misek, rumor has it that Apple is trying to get U.S. wireless operators to price the upcoming iPhone 6 at $299 with a two year contract instead of $199 with a two year contract. As someone who buys only unlocked smartphones, this has me wondering if the base model iPhone 6 will cost over 800 Euros.</p><p><a href="http://www.macrumors.com/2014/04/14/iphone-6-mold-4-7/">03</a> &nbsp;Apple: Another photo of an alleged Foxconn mold for the upcoming iPhone 6 has surfaced.</p><p><a href="http://translate.google.com/translate?hl=en&amp;sl=ko&amp;tl=en&amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fnews.naver.com%2Fmain%2Fread.nhn%3Fmode%3DLSD%26mid%3Dsec%26sid1%3D105%26oid%3D029%26aid%3D0002215727">04</a> &nbsp;Apple: Rumor has it that LG will be the sole display maker for the upcoming iWatch, it'll launch in September, and Apple is expecting to sell nine million units in calendar 2014.</p><p><a href="http://asia.nikkei.com/Markets/Tokyo-Market/Alpine-to-sell-console-for-Apple-s-in-car-infotainment-system">05</a> &nbsp;Apple: Want to use CarPlay, but don't want to buy a new car? Rumor has it Alpine will start selling an aftermarket console in the U.S. and Europe this fall for between $500 and $700.</p><p><a href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140414PD201.html">06</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: Intel is allegedly selling their CPUs for tablets for less than $5 in China in order to better compete with MediaTek and Allwinner.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27018112">07</a> &nbsp;eBay: Data Point: "Last year 73% of the items on its website were sold at a fixed price, rather than via auction."</p><p><a href="http://www.engadget.com/2014/04/14/facebook-money-transfer-service-europe/?utm_source=Feed_Classic_Full&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Engadget&amp;?ncid=rss_full">08</a> &nbsp;Facebook: According to an article from The Financial Times that's behind a paywall, Facebook is "only weeks away" from launching a PayPal-like service in Europe.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/14/us-google-email-idUSBREA3D1RT20140414?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">09</a> &nbsp;Google: "Google updated its terms of service on Monday, informing users that their incoming and outgoing emails are automatically analyzed by software to create targeted ads." In other news, water is wet.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/14/android-4-4-3-build-ktu48f-for-the-nexus-5-should-start-rolling-out-today-according-to-sprint/">10</a> &nbsp;Google: Android 4.4.3 (the newest version of the OS) is being pushed out to Nexus 5 owners using the Sprint network. The changelog has just two line items: "Enable Sprint Spark band 26 and band 41. Misc Android updates." No word as to when other devices will get this update, but I'm assuming it'll be sooner rather than later, and hopefully we'll also get a more detailed list of the updates within.</p><p><a href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/+chrome/posts/HwGoDkvuBnN">11</a> &nbsp;Google: Chrome OS has been updated. It now supports a feature Microsoft introduced in Windows 8, the ability to dock (Microsoft says "<a href="http://winsupersite.com/windows-8/windows-81-tip-master-auto-snap">snap</a>") small apps to the side of your screen.</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702304117904579501701702936522">12</a> &nbsp;Google: Facebook wanted to buy Titan Aerospace, but Google just beat them to the punch. No price was mentioned. Titan builds solar powered drones, has roughly 20 employees, and is based out of New Mexico.</p><p><a href="https://plus.google.com/+GoogleGlass/posts/gNS3JvHEdvV">13</a> &nbsp;Google: They've announced a "subtle, but big" software update for Google Glass that will be pushed out later this week. From what I can tell, it's mainly just bug fixes and battery life improvements. Video calling has been removed because the experience was less than ideal.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-27028101">14</a> &nbsp;Heartbleed: Canada's version of the IRS says that because of Heartbleed, 900 social security numbers were stolen.</p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/JasonMacHTC/status/455758924579233792">15</a> &nbsp;HTC: If you own an "old" HTC One, and want the software that ships on the 2014 HTC One, you'll be happy to know you're due to get an update by the end of May.</p><p><a href="http://www.pulitzer.org/awards/2014">16</a> &nbsp;Journalism: Here's the list of publications and journalists that won a Pulitzer this year.</p><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.co.kr/news/news_view.asp?artice_id=20140415065518">17</a> &nbsp;LG: ZDNET Korea is reporting that LG's next flagship phone, the G3, will be released in July and feature a 5.5 inch screen with a resolution of 2560 x 1440 pixels. We're talking 534 pixels per inch here.</p><p><a href="http://www.wpcentral.com/how-sign-windows-phone-81-preview-developers">18</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: If you have a Windows Phone, and you want to test Windows Phone 8.1 right now instead of waiting for your device maker or operator to push out an update, here's everything you need to know.</p><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-makes-office-online-available-in-chrome-web-store-7000028408/">19</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: Office Online is now available via the Chrome Web Store. It's free, but note that you don't get all the features of Office. Think of this more like Microsoft's version of Google Docs.</p><p><a href="http://www.imore.com/windows-phone-81-somehow-working-apple-passbook">20</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: Windows Phone 8.1 appears to somehow be compatible with Apple's Passbook, but no one is entirely sure if this is officially sanctioned.</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/14/5613280/netflix-streaming-speeds-on-comcast-65-percent-faster">21</a> &nbsp;Netflix: They've published a chart ranking the best performing ISPs in the U.S. for the month of March. That's not very interesting. What's interesting is that Comcast's average streaming speeds jumped 65% after they struck a deal with Netflix.</p><p><a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/meet-jasper-open-source-voice-computing/">22</a> &nbsp;Open Source: Apple has Siri. Google has Google Now. Microsoft has Cortana. But what about the open source community? Meet Jasper.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/14/us-retail-cybersecurity-idUSBREA3D1GM20140414?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">23</a> &nbsp;Security: Remember all those credit cards that were stolen from Target? No one wants that to happen again, ever, so the "National Retail Federation said on Monday it will establish an Information Sharing and Analysis Center, or ISAC, for the retail industry in June."</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/04/14/square-hires-amazon-aws-exec-alyssa-henry-as-engineering-lead/">24</a> &nbsp;Square: The woman responsible for Amazon's infrastructure, Alyssa Henry, is now in charge of Square's infrastructure.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-27019389">25</a> &nbsp;USA: Drone technology is advancing so rapidly that the Pentagon has a stockpile of old units just collecting dust. They've decided to put them to good use by transforming them into Wi-Fi hotspots for soldiers in the field.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-27027876">26</a> &nbsp;Asia: Researchers have found a link between increased pollution and stronger storms. Tiny pollutant particles make storm clouds denser, which in turn causes increased precipitation.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27030815">27</a> &nbsp;Australia: The city of Sydney is going to get a second international airport. They've been wanting one since as far back as 1946. It's going to cost $2.4 billion to build, it'll be done in the mid-2020s, and it's expected to bring with it 60,000 jobs.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27030705">28</a> &nbsp;China: Crazy Number of the Day: The Chinese bought 1,132 tons of gold in 2013. Your typical Honda Civic weighs less than 1.5 tons.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-27028990">29</a> &nbsp;France: An auction for roughly 40 pieces of Nazi memorabilia, including Goering's passport and a napkin used by Hitler, was canceled due to complaints that assigning value to these objects is disgusting.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-27030741">30</a> &nbsp;Malaysia: The robotic submarine searching for the MH370 flight recorder had to cut its mission short because its built-in safety system wouldn't allow it to dive any deeper. Note that the sub is rated to withstand depths of 4,500 meters (15,000 feet).</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-26969150">31</a> &nbsp;Mongolia: This brief, but beautiful photo essay shows how one young girl uses a golden eagle to hunt for food. Make sure you scroll to the bottom.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-27021291">32</a> &nbsp;Netherlands: Street lights are expensive. Glow in the dark paint is not. That's the logic the Dutch are using to test a 500 meter stretch of highway to see how well people can get by with just the green paint.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-27027200">33</a> &nbsp;Space: SpaceX had to abort the launch of a Falcon-9 rocket yesterday because one of its sensors detected a helium leak. Said rocket was supposed to carry two tons of food and supplies to the space station.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-27030652">34</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: Barack Obama called Vladimir Putin and told him to stop whatever it is he's doing in East Ukraine, and that even if he wasn't responsible, he should use his power to get pro-Russian forces in the region to stop acting like a bunch of madmen.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27025703">35</a> &nbsp;USA: "U.S. retail sales saw their biggest gain in 18 months in March, according to official figures. Sales at general merchandise stores such as Wal-Mart, Target and department stores, rose by 1.9%, their strongest one-month gain since March 2007."</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">36</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 14: 38 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 08:57:25 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/14/april-14-38-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:534ba2f9e4b08ae8ac6aae5a</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/sponsor">01</a> &nbsp;This spot is reserved for <a href="http://tabdump.com/sponsor">sponsors</a>. If you want more details, <a href="mailto:stefan@whatthebit.com?subject=Sponsor">send me an email</a>.</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702303873604579495940522902678">02</a> &nbsp;Amazon: The WSJ says Amazon will announce a phone in June and then start selling it in September. The key selling point will be four front facing cameras that enable the device to "make some images appear to be 3-D, similar to a hologram."</p><p><a href="http://www.macrumors.com/2014/04/13/iphone6-chassis-molds/">03</a> &nbsp;Apple: These are allegedly the molds Foxconn will be using to make the 4.7 inch iPhone 6.</p><p><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/apr/11/apple-bloom-fm-music-app-iads">04</a> &nbsp;Apple: They banned a UK online streaming radio company from advertising on iAd because they're "a competitive service to iTunes Radio and it is against Apple policy".</p><p><a href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140410PD209.html">05</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: You know how HTC's 2014 flagship phone, the M8, has two rear facing cameras? Altek, one of the companies that makes dual-camera modules for smartphones, says Lenovo and Huawei will follow in HTC's footsteps this quarter. Samsung and Apple will do the same in 2015.</p><p><a href="http://vimeo.com/91738585">06</a> &nbsp;Dropbox: For those of you that like to watch press conferences, here's the one Dropbox held on the 9th.</p><p><a href="https://blog.dropbox.com/2014/04/our-commitment-to-your-rights-and-privacy/">07</a> &nbsp;Dropbox: Here's the (borderline useless) three paragraph response Dropbox has issued to those concerned about Condoleezza Rice joining the Dropbox board.</p><p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-11/facebook-s-hardware-push-behind-the-scenes-draws-oculus.html">08</a> &nbsp;Facebook: In 2010, Facebook had seven people on a hardware team dedicated to servers. Today, that number is 170. They spent $1.36 billion on data centers last year.</p><p><a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/how-google-is-transforming-power-and-politicsgoogle-once-disdainful-of-lobbying-now-a-master-of-washington-influence/2014/04/12/51648b92-b4d3-11e3-8cb6-284052554d74_story.html">09</a> &nbsp;Google: "Google's federal lobbying spending now ranks on par with the largest U.S. corporations active in Washington. The company went from 213th place in 2004 to second in 2012." So how much did Google actually spend on lobbying in 2012 in order to reach silver status? $18.2 million.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/13/rumor-googles-android-app-icons-to-get-a-moonshine-makeover/">10</a> &nbsp;Google: According to Android Police, which is killing it in the Google rumor department, these are the new icons that Google will use for the next version of Android. They represent a much flatter design language, some might say even iOS 7-ish. Expect to hear more about the next version of Android at I/O on June 25th.</p><p><a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/google-exec-we-never-copied-iphone-features-for-android/">11</a> &nbsp;Google: I'm keeping one eye on the Apple/Samsung trial in case any interesting data points come out. Hiroshi Lockheimer, Google VP of Engineering for Android, recently testified that the Android team is made up of 600 to 700 people. In 2006, it was 20 to 30 people.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-27004713">12</a> &nbsp;Heartbleed: "The U.S. National Security Agency has denied it knew about or exploited the Heartbleed online security flaw. The denial came after a Bloomberg News report alleging the NSA used the flaw in OpenSSL to harvest data."</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/11/us-microsoft-apple-patents-idUSBREA3A0R020140411">13</a> &nbsp;Intellectual Ventures: One of the world's best known patent trolls is looking to raise $3 billion. Microsoft and Sony said sure, we'll give you some money. Apple and Intel said no, go away, despite the fact that they've both contributed in the past.</p><p><a href="http://in.reuters.com/article/2014/04/14/micromax-pantech-sale-idINKBN0D000L20140414">14</a> &nbsp;Micromax: Indian phone maker Micromax wants to buy a stake in Korean phone maker Pantech. No word as to how big of a stake.</p><p><a href="http://research.microsoft.com/en-us/projects/3dscan/">15</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: Remember <a href="https://www.google.com/atap/projecttango/">Project Tango</a>, Google's prototype phone that has a built-in 3D scanner? Microsoft just announced their own version of it, and it's called Skynet of all things.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.windows.com/windows/b/buildingapps/archive/2014/04/12/consolidated-price-tiers-to-support-universal-windows-apps-may-impact-your-app-pricing.aspx">16</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: They're now allowing apps in the Windows Store (the app store for the desktop) to be priced at either $0.99 or $1.29. The company says 55% of all apps purchased on Windows Phone fall into those two categories.</p><p><a href="http://www.lightreading.com/mobile/4g-lte/o2-uk-talks-4g-ran-modernization/d/d-id/708635?_mc=RSS_LR_EDT">17</a> &nbsp;O2 UK: This operator recently hit one million 4G LTE customers. In their announcement was this eye-popping data point: "Customers used more data in the 4G network's first six months than the entire O2 network carried between 2000 and 2008."</p><p><a href="http://realscreen.com/2014/04/10/miptv-14-atlantic-eyes-oculus-rift-for-conquest-of-flight/">18</a> &nbsp;Oculus: Sir David Attenborough is filming a new nature documentary called "Conquest of the Skies" that's specifically meant to be viewed on the Oculus Rift.</p><p><a href="http://www.fiercewireless.com/tech/story/qualcomm-joins-mimosa-others-pushing-fcc-open-10-ghz-mobile-broadband/2014-04-11?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss">19</a> &nbsp;Qualcomm: They're asking the FCC to open up spectrum in the 10 GHz band. The only reason I even mention this story is because I never knew companies were even looking into this absurdly high frequency band.</p><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.co.kr/news/news_view.asp?artice_id=20140413100023">20</a> &nbsp;Samsung: A lot of people are pointing to this article on ZDNET Korea, which says Galaxy S5 opening day sales are between 130% to 200% better than Galaxy S4 sales, but the exact source of those two numbers isn't mentioned, so do exercise caution.</p><p><a href="http://www.engadget.com/2014/04/14/samsung-event-singapore-galaxy-k-zoom/">21</a> &nbsp;Samsung: They're going to unveil a camera focused smartphone on the 29th.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2014/04/11/new-data-quantifies-dearth-of-tweeters-on-twitter/?utm_content=buffer85afb&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer">22</a> &nbsp;Twitter: "A report from Twopcharts, a website that monitors Twitter account activity, states that about 44% of the 974 million existing Twitter accounts have never sent a tweet." Plenty of people are talking about this report, and they're saying it doesn't matter if people don't tweet, because one doesn't need to tweet to enjoy the benefits of Twitter. But what does Twitter want?</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27017623">23</a> &nbsp;China: They just dropped $6 billion on a copper mine in Peru. Said mine is expected to supply 450,000 tons of copper a year for the first five years it's open.</p><p><a href="http://yle.fi/uutiset/itella_to_release_tom_of_finland_stamps/7188557">24</a> &nbsp;Finland: This September, "Tom of Finland" stamps will go on sale in Finland. If you don't know who "Tom of Finland" is, he's famous for drawing homosexual men in various ... poses.</p><p><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/apr/10/angela-merkel-denied-access-nsa-file?CMP=twt_gu">25</a> &nbsp;Germany: "The U.S. government is refusing to grant Angela Merkel access to her NSA file or answer formal questions from Germany about its surveillance activities." Reminder:&nbsp;Merkel grew up in East Germany, so this stuff is all too familiar to her.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26986773">26</a> &nbsp;Germany: A furniture store chain ordered 5,000 coffee cups from China. Said cups featured a portrait of Hitler. The store chain sold about 175 of the cups until someone pointed Hitler out. The remaining cups have been destroyed.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-27017928">27</a> &nbsp;Malaysia: "Teams searching for the missing Malaysia Airlines plane are to deploy a submersible for the first time." It's called the Bluefin-21, and it'll be sent to the area where four pings from the flight boxes were heard.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26993872">28</a> &nbsp;Norway: Remember that <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/3/6/5476944/norway-will-cut-through-an-island-in-tribute-to-massacre-victims">beautiful Breivik massacre memorial</a> that was planned? The families of the victims don't want it to be built. They're "getting sick" of being constantly reminded about the tragedy, and will take the government to court if construction of the memorial begins.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-scotland-scotland-business-26974320">29</a> &nbsp;Scotland: Xi Jinping became China's new president in March 2013. He promised to tackle corruption and excessive "gift giving". Result? Sales of whiskey to China dropped 30% in 2013 according to the Scotch Whisky Association (SWA).</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-27017629">30</a> &nbsp;South Korea: "South Korea's state health insurer is suing three tobacco firms to offset smoking-related treatment costs." How much do they want? $52 million, which seems ridiculous considering they spend $1.6 billion a year to treat "smoking-related diseases."</p><p><a href="http://www.dvice.com/2014-4-10/handheld-jet-engines-take-extreme-sports-next-level?utm_content=buffer3fcba&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;utm_campaign=buffer">31</a> &nbsp;Switzerland: Take four small jet engines, attach them to a stick, and make someone strapped to a snowboard hold said stick. Rarely does one get to witness the birth of a new extreme sport.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-27018199">32</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: The deadline that the Ukrainian government gave to Pro-Russian militants to end their occupation of certain government buildings in the Eastern part of the country has passed. The militants haven't budged an inch.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26987653">33</a> &nbsp;USA: "A new treatment for hepatitis C 'cured' 90% of patients with the infection in 12 weeks, scientists said." The drug was tested on 380 patients last year. Two trials took place, one of which lasted 12 weeks, the other double that.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-27017750">34</a> &nbsp;USA: Man hurls racist insults and spits on neighbors, including their disabled kids in wheelchairs. Judge orders him to stand outside with a sign that says "I am a bully", plus 15 days of jail time.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26954138">35</a> &nbsp;USA: Researchers have invented a pair of augmented reality goggles that allow surgeons to "see" cancer. A patient is injected with a special dye that sticks to cancer cells, and said dye gives off "light" at a wavelength only the glasses can see.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-27015608">36</a> &nbsp;Venezuela: The death toll from the protests has hit 41.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-26935867">37</a> &nbsp;World: Here's a list of 10 inventions that wouldn't have been possible without the first World War. Some of the items, such as the vegetarian sausage and daylight savings time, are quite surprising.</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">38</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 11: 42 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 07:24:09 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/11/april-11-42-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:5347989fe4b022b8c63560d0</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.igloosoftware.com/campaigns/swisscom?ref=tabdump&amp;type=blog&amp;month=april">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: Igloo, makers of an intranet you'll actually like, are happy to announce an OEM partnership with Swisscom. Under the trademark Dynamic Intranet, Swisscom will host and distribute Igloo's cloud intranet solution to their customers in Switzerland, Germany, and Italy. This offers Swisscom's European customers a state-of-the-art hosting facility in Zürich, while Igloo's North American and international customers continue to be hosted at CenturyLink facilities in Canada.</p><p><a href="http://venturebeat.com/2014/04/10/digital-advertising-hits-43b-passing-broadcast-tv-for-the-first-time-ever/">02</a> &nbsp;Advertising: "Digital ad revenues surpassed broadcast television for the first time." We're talking $42.8 billion spent in 2013 on internet advertising versus $40.1 billion on TV. There are a ton of data points in this article, so enjoy.</p><p><a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/amazon-app-store-grows-to-200000-apps/">03</a> &nbsp;Amazon: Their app store now has 200,000 apps. "The Amazon Appstore launched in March 2011 with 3,800 apps. Amazon reported having 100,000 apps in August 2013."</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/10/amazon-acquires-digital-comic-book-service-comixology/">04</a> &nbsp;Amazon: They spent an undisclosed amount of money to buy comiXology, which can best be thought of as Kindle-like service for comic books.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.blackberry.com/2014/04/not-leaving-handsets/">05</a> &nbsp;BlackBerry: Yesterday, Reuters quoted the CEO of BlackBerry as saying "If I cannot make money on handsets, I will not be in the handset business." That quote went viral, so the CEO decided to issue a correction on the company blog. And I quote: "We have not given up and we are not leaving the devices business."</p><p><a href="http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2014/04/10/apple-iphone-6-changewave/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+fortuneapple20+%28FORTUNE%3A+Apple+2.0%29">06</a> &nbsp;ChangeWave: A lot of people are quoting a new survey published by ChangeWave that says 14% of people (sample size 4,109) want to buy an iPhone 6 because it has a larger screen. Personally, I think surveys that ask people what they want to buy mean little to nothing, and that the only data worth analyzing is sales data. That being said, of course people want a bigger iPhone!</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/10/following-spotify-deezer-goes-freemium-on-mobile/">07</a> &nbsp;Deezer: This Spotify clone just announced that people will be able to "listen to smart radios for free" on their mobile phone, but the bigger news is this: "The company also announced a new partnership with Samsung in Europe. New Samsung Galaxy S5 owners will get 6 months of Premium+." That's $85 worth of unlimited music streaming.</p><p><a href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140410PD204.html">08</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: "Microsoft will set up four additional Azure data centers in 2014 and is expected to expand its procurement orders to server ODMs." So instead of calling up Dell and HP and ordering servers, Microsoft is going straight to the companies that build the servers in the first place.</p><p><a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/dropbox-adds-condoleezza-rice-to-board-2014-4">09</a> &nbsp;Dropbox: Buried in all of yesterday's Dropbox news was this little nugget: Condoleezza Rice is joining the Dropbox board. This is the same woman that authorized warrantless wiretapping and who is best buddies with the NSA. This should be more controversial than some guy donating $1,000 to ban gay marriage, but no one seems to care.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26980551">10</a> &nbsp;eBay: "Activist investor Carl Icahn has dropped his call for eBay to sell its payments business, PayPal." He still thinks eBay should spin-off PayPal, but he's acknowledged it's not going to happen with the current board.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26952394">11</a> &nbsp;Facebook: Researchers using a sample set of 881 female U.S. college students have discovered "the more time women spent on Facebook, the more they compared their bodies with those of their friends, and the more they felt negative about their appearance."</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/10/whatsapp-privacy/?ncid=rss">12</a> &nbsp;Facebook: The United States Federal Trade Commission just approved the WhatsApp purchase, but with one string attached. Facebook can't use WhatsApp's data without getting explicit permission from WhatsApp's users.</p><p><a href="http://variety.com/2014/digital/news/youtube-once-tvs-enemy-tries-to-show-how-it-drives-viewers-to-tv-shows-1201155364/">13</a> &nbsp;Google: "According to Google, video views of TV-related content on YouTube grew 35% in 2013 from the previous year, while time spent viewing TV-related content on the site jumped 65% over that period. Furthermore, Google searches for TV content were up 16% year over year." The report with all these figures is <a href="http://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/articles/the-role-of-digital-in-tv.html">here</a>.</p><p><a href="https://plus.google.com/+GoogleGlass/posts/HaUCDHtRvcn">14</a> &nbsp;Google: On April 15th, starting at 06:00 California time, anyone in the U.S. will be able to plop down $1,500 for a pair of Google Glass. This is a one day only sale.</p><p><a href="http://officialandroid.blogspot.fi/2014/04/expanding-googles-security-services-for.html">15</a> &nbsp;Google: They just announced an always-on antivirus service for Android, but specifically didn't use the word "antivirus", because that just has too many negative connotations.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/10/us-financial-regulations-internet-idUSBREA3921420140410?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">16</a> &nbsp;Heartbleed: "U.S. financial regulators on Thursday told banks to upgrade their systems as soon as possible." That kind of goes without saying, right?</p><p><a href="http://www.hardwarezone.com.sg/tech-news-htc-one-m8-users-experiencing-sim-card-issues-cause-remains-unknown">17</a> &nbsp;HTC: A Singaporean operator is reporting that several of the HTC One M8 units they've sold are having SIM card issues. Reminder: This is the company's brand new flagship phone.</p><p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-10/line-targets-1-billion-users-in-2015-as-message-services-surge.html">18</a> &nbsp;LINE: My favorite chat app says they plan on hitting "500 million to 600 million users by the end of this year" and over one billion users at some point in 2015. They're growing at a rate of roughly 1.7 million users a day.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/microsoft_blog/archive/2014/04/10/privacy-authorities-across-europe-approve-microsoft-s-cloud-commitments.aspx?utm_source=dlvr.it&amp;utm_medium=twitter">19</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: Their cloud service is now the first and only cloud service that's compatible with the European Union's privacy laws.</p><p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-10/samsung-boosts-galaxy-freebies-to-600-to-fend-off-apple-xiaomi.html">20</a> &nbsp;Samsung: "Samsung expects S5 sales to reach 10 million units within 25 days based on pre-orders from global wireless operators, Seoul Economic Daily reported today, citing an unidentified Samsung official."</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/04/09/a-sale-or-ipo-or-more-funding-heres-what-might-be-next-for-square/">21</a> &nbsp;Square: According to Re/code, both Google and Apple are interested in buying Square, with the rumored acquisition price being roughly $8 billion. Square might decide to do their own thing, however, and IPO. What I want to know is what's Square going to do come October 2015 when chip and pin cards become mandatory in the U.S.?</p><p><a href="http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2014-04-10/staples-wants-to-bring-3-d-printing-to-the-masses#r=rss">22</a> &nbsp;Staples: "Staples has been selling 3D printers for about a year. Now it wants to begin selling access to them. The office supply retailer began offering 3D printing services in two stores on Thursday, one in New York and another in Los Angeles." Prices range, depending on what you're printing, from several dollars to thousands.</p><p><a href="http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2014/04/10/twitter-and-facebook-wield-little-influence-on-tv-watching/?_php=true&amp;_type=blogs&amp;gwh=F1F5EE45B09063C1EA385D9FDCB45367&amp;gwt=regi&amp;_r=0">23</a> &nbsp;Television: Everyone fiddles with their phone while watching TV, right? According to a survey on 1,665 Americans between the ages of 15 to 54, the answer is no. "Only 16.1% of the survey respondents said they had used social media while watching TV during prime time. And less than half of the people using social media were actually discussing the show they were watching."</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/10/us-turkey-youtube-idUSBREA390J320140410">24</a> &nbsp;Turkey: As predicted, YouTube is still banned, despite what the courts have said.</p><p><a href="https://blog.twitter.com/2014/stay-connected-with-notifications-on-twittercom">25</a> &nbsp;Twitter: If you use Twitter via Twitter's desktop website, you can now look forward to notifications, just like Facebook.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-26979021">26</a> &nbsp;Brazil: This is the world's most insane football (read: soccer) fan. Two minute video.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26982173">27</a> &nbsp;Europe: Ukraine has some unpaid gas bills ($2.2 billion). Russia, which supplies about a third of the EU's natural gas, is now threatening 18 European countries with gas cuts if it doesn't get paid. The U.S. is of course waving their finger at Russia, but not much else.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26560558">28</a> &nbsp;Health: One BBC reporter tried to go one week without eating processed foods. She documented her diet. I'm stunned she had so much difficulty eating healthy, because I'm pretty sure fruits and vegetables are quite easy to find in Western countries.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26984113">29</a> &nbsp;Japan: Despite Fukushima, the Japanese government just announced that they're going to reactivate some of the country's nuclear power plants.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26984162">30</a> &nbsp;Malaysia: Four pings thought to originate from the MH370 black boxes have been detected. A fifth ping was recently heard, but it's now been debunked by the Australian Joint Acoustic Analysis Center.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-26978872">31</a> &nbsp;Nigeria: A 14 year old girl was forced to marry a 35 year old man. She didn't want any part of it, so she poisoned the food at the wedding. Not only did the husband die, but so did three other people; 10 people were sent to the hospital.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26975865">32</a> &nbsp;Russia: "Five members of Russia's parliament have called for the former president, Mikhail Gorbachev, to be prosecuted over the collapse of the Soviet Union." 1991 called. They want their headline back.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-26973587">33</a> &nbsp;Somalia: What happens when the residents of Mogadishu access the internet via a fiber optic connection for the first time? They report "culture shock" and joy for finally having the ability to use YouTube.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-26979101">34</a> &nbsp;Syria: Only 54% of the country's reported 1,200 tons of chemical weapons has been sent to factories to be destroyed. The country agreed to send all their chemical weapons by the 27th of this month.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26970132">35</a> &nbsp;UK: "In a study of 847 men with prostate cancer, 209 out of the 415 who were initially told their cancer was slow-growing were found to have a more aggressive form of the disease. And for almost a third of the 415 men, it had spread around the body." Translation: Today's cancer tests are terrible. As someone who lost a parent to cancer, this upsets me.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-england-dorset-26979187">36</a> &nbsp;UK: Man sexually abuses 13 year old girl. Man goes to jail. Man asks police to give his laptop back, which has images of said abused girl. Technically, the police have to fulfill his request. Outrage ensues.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26982860">37</a> &nbsp;USA: "A woman has thrown a shoe at former First Lady Hillary Clinton as she was giving a speech in Las Vegas." This is a 53 second video, not an article.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26981580">38</a> &nbsp;USA: "Health Secretary Kathleen Sebelius is resigning following the problematic launch of President Barack Obama's healthcare law." She's been at her post since 2009. Rumor has it Obama will replace her with Sylvia Mathews Burwell, Director of the White House Office of Management and Budget.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26943442">39</a> &nbsp;USA: Researchers studying how flies move have discovered that they use the same type of aerial techniques that fighter jet pilots use, namely split-second banking (aka rolling). It takes as little as five milliseconds for a fly to change the direction it's heading.</p><p><a href="http://news.walmart.com/news-archive/2014/04/10/walmart-and-wild-oats-launch-effort-to-drive-down-organic-food-prices">40</a> &nbsp;USA: Walmart is getting into the organic food business. They promise that their organic food prices will be at least 25% cheaper than competing organic food brands.</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">41</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p><p><a href="http://tinyletter.com/tabdump">42</a> &nbsp;One more thing: Tradition dictates I remind you <a href="http://tinyletter.com/tabdump">Tab Dump via email</a> exists on Friday.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 10: 49 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 07:26:54 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/10/april-10-49-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:534647c3e4b0c08d31d60b2f</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.igloosoftware.com/campaigns/swisscom?ref=tabdump&amp;type=blog&amp;month=april">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: Igloo, makers of an intranet you'll actually like, are happy to announce an OEM partnership with Swisscom. Under the trademark Dynamic Intranet, Swisscom will host and distribute Igloo's cloud intranet solution to their customers in Switzerland, Germany, and Italy. This offers Swisscom's European customers a state-of-the-art hosting facility in Zürich, while Igloo's North American and international customers continue to be hosted at CenturyLink facilities in Canada.</p><p><a href="http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/alibaba-chairman-jack-ma-pays-694725">02</a> &nbsp;Alibaba: Think of Alibaba as a sort of eBay and Amazon mixed together, but with higher revenues. They just bought a 20% stake in a Chinese online TV company for $1 billion. Note that Alibaba is expected to IPO soon, and they're going to be worth more than Facebook.</p><p><a href="http://adage.com/article/agency-news/apple-poised-add-digital-agencies-roster/292569/">03</a> &nbsp;Apple: "Apple is set to add four digital agencies to its roster, including WPP's AKQA and Interpublic Group's Huge on the West Coast, as well as small, New York-based indie shops Area 17 and Kettle, Ad Age has learned."</p><p><a href="http://www.billboard.com/biz/articles/news/digital-and-mobile/6042224/underwhelming-start-to-itunes-radio-lights-fire-under">04</a> &nbsp;Apple: "iTunes Radio, which launched in September with much fanfare, so far only sees about 1% to 2% of listeners clicking the buy button." Not only that, but Apple now makes up 50% of the record labels' revenues, whereas it used to be 70% in 2012. According to Billboard, this situation is "forcing" Apple to speed up plans to offer a Spotify-like subscription music streaming service.</p><p><a href="http://appleinsider.com/articles/14/04/10/apple-confirms-retirement-of-greg-christie-as-sources-rebut-claims-of-internal-struggle">05</a> &nbsp;Apple: Human Interface Chief Greg Christie is leaving Apple. Some say it's because he didn't get along with Jony Ive. Others say he's just ready to retire after being with Apple for 18 years. One thing is certain: We'll never know the real reason.</p><p><a href="http://www.macrumors.com/2014/04/09/apple-2014-product-roadmap/">06</a> &nbsp;Apple: KGI Research analyst Ming-Chi Kuo, who has a pretty good track record when it comes to Apple rumors, says that in Q3 2014 we're going to see a new iPad Air, a new iPad mini, two iWatches (different sizes), a 4.7 inch iPhone 6, a new Apple TV, and a new 12.0 inch MacBook. There will be a larger 5.5 inch iPhone 6 in Q4. As for the 12.9 inch "iPad Pro", that's a 2015 product. Should you believe Kuo's predictions? My brain says maybe, but my gut says no.</p><p><a href="http://appleinsider.com/articles/14/04/09/apple-nabs-senior-rf-engineers-from-broadcom-amid-rumors-of-new-in-house-baseband-team">07</a> &nbsp;Apple: There was a DigiTimes rumor yesterday that said Apple wanted to make their own baseband chips, aka the part of the phone that talks to the cellular network. Today, AppleInsider has discovered two very senior Broadcom engineers have left to join Apple. In total, 30 RF engineers from Broadcom and Qualcomm have joined Apple over the past three years, and there are 50+ job openings on Apple's website relating to RF. Translation: The company that's known for being vertically integrated is taking things to the next level.</p><p><a href="http://auo.com/?sn=21&amp;lang=zh-TW&amp;c=2&amp;n=1590">08</a> &nbsp;AUO: This display maker has unveiled a 5.7 inch 2560 x 1440 pixel AMOLED panel. No word as to when it'll enter mass production. It should be noted that all the AMOLED panels Samsung uses are made by Samsung themselves, so I'm not even sure who would buy AUO's AMOLED panels.</p><p><a href="http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2014-04-09/automattic-steward-of-wordpress-snaps-up-longreads">09</a> &nbsp;Automattic: The makers of WordPress just bought Longreads. Financial details weren't disclosed.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/10/us-blackberry-ceo-idUSBREA3822M20140410">10</a> &nbsp;BlackBerry: The company's CEO just straight up said: "If I cannot make money on handsets, I will not be in the handset business."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26925463">11</a> &nbsp;Coursera: This online education company is "creating an international network of 'learning hubs', where students can follow virtual courses in real-life, brick and mortar settings." Turns out that people like being around people, and not just starring at a glowing rectangle. How many of these hubs are there? More than 30, and they're "run by partner organizations", not Coursera themselves.</p><p><a href="https://blog.dropbox.com/2014/04/introducing-carousel/">12</a> &nbsp;Dropbox: They released a Flickr/Instagram clone for Android and iOS called "Carousel". It's essentially a new way to view the photos you've backed up to Dropbox, plus there's a social network built on top.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/09/new-app-dropboxs-mailbox-app-finally-comes-to-android-to-tame-your-inbox/">13</a> &nbsp;Dropbox: They've released Mailbox for Android. Apparently it's a popular email app. Color me surprised, I've never heard of it until now.</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/09/dropbox-launches-project-harmony-to-bring-collaborative-features-to-microsoft-office/">14</a> &nbsp;Dropbox: With "Project Harmony", Dropbox is bringing what looks like Google Drive levels of chat support and collaboration to Microsoft Office. More details will be released tomorrow.</p><p><a href="http://articles.economictimes.indiatimes.com/2014-04-08/news/48971129_1_access-facebook-1-billion-users-javier-olivan">15</a> &nbsp;Facebook: "Facebook has crossed 100 million active users in India -- the second country, after the United States, in which it has done so."</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/09/facebook-column-ads-get-bigger/">16</a> &nbsp;Facebook: The ads on the right side of their website will soon get bigger, but fewer of them will be displayed. Because bigger ads equals more attention, right?</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/09/facebook-messenger-or-the-highway/">17</a> &nbsp;Facebook: They're "starting to notify users they'll no longer have the option to send and receive messages in Facebook for iOS and Android, and will instead have to download Facebook Messenger to chat on mobile." Personally, I use m.facebook.com on my phone during those rare times I want to look at Facebook while I'm out on the town. Not installing Facebook <a href="http://www.overthought.org/blog/2014/the-ultimate-guide-to-solving-ios-battery-drain">improves your phone's battery life</a>. Try it.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/09/rumor-google-now-will-soon-detect-and-remind-you-where-you-parked-apk-teardown/">18</a> &nbsp;Google: Android Police says Google Now will soon be adding a feature that will "detect when you get out of your car, and attempt to remember that location for later, serving you a card with Google's best guess as to where you left your vehicle."</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/9/5598622/project-ara-module-development-kit-explains-how-to-make-parts">19</a> &nbsp;Google: Companies looking to contribute to Project Ara, Google's attempt at creating a modular mobile phone, can now download the "Module Developers Kit" from Google's website. As for when Ara devices and modules will ship, Google says Q1 2015, but that's just a target.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26958985">20</a> &nbsp;Google: Google Ventures has bought a stake in a robotics company called Savioke. The size of said stake is not known, but the company says they've received $2 million in seed funding. Savioke wants to build robots for the service industry. Their website says "hotels, elderly care facilities, hospitals, and restaurants [are] possibilities."</p><p><a href="http://www.geek.com/android/google-is-testing-new-ui-and-features-for-google-calendar-1590615/">21</a> &nbsp;Google: The website that previously leaked Google's newly designed Gmail app has now leaked Google's newly designed Calendar app. It's hard to judge how pretty this looks based on a few images, but hopefully we'll see this new redesigned version of Android at Google I/O on June 25th.</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/article_email/SB10001424052702303873604579491861092490006-lMyQjAxMTA0MDAwOTEwNDkyWj">22</a> &nbsp;Heartbleed: The first real meaningful Heartbleed story: "Canada shut down its online tax-filing services just weeks before millions of Canadians must file their tax returns."</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/09/us-poland-hp-idUSBREA380EZ20140409?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">23</a> &nbsp;HP: "Hewlett-Packard agreed to pay $108 million to resolve wide-ranging U.S. government investigations into whether some of its foreign units bribed government officials to obtain lucrative contracts, U.S. officials said on Wednesday."</p><p><a href="http://www.idc.com/getdoc.jsp?containerId=prUS24794514">24</a> &nbsp;IDC: These analysts say 73.4 million computers were shipped in Q1 2014, which is down 4.4% year over year. Lenovo shipped the most computers, giving them 17.7% market share. HP was in second place with 17.1%. And Dell was in third with 13.4%.</p><p><a href="http://www.engadget.com/2014/04/09/transparent-land-rover-hood/?utm_source=Feed_Classic_Full&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Engadget&amp;?ncid=rss_full">25</a> &nbsp;Land Rover: What happens when you mix augmented reality with off-roading? You get a concept car with a "transparent" hood that lets you see the ground that you're driving on and the direction of your wheels.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/09/us-china-microsoft-idUSBREA380W520140409?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">26</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: They're partnering with Lenovo and Tencent to offer support for Windows XP, which according to data cited by the state news agency Xinhua, runs on 70% of the computers in the country.</p><p><a href="http://motorola-blog.blogspot.fi/2014/04/a-moto-insider-to-lead-us-forward.html">27</a> &nbsp;Motorola: "Rick Osterloh has been named as President and COO of Motorola Mobility." Note that the sale to Lenovo still hasn't gone through, and no one really knows what Lenovo will do with Motorola's top executives.</p><p><a href="http://news.mydrivers.com/1/300/300016.htm">28</a> &nbsp;Mozilla: Images of Firefox OS 2.0 have leaked. Spoiler: It's basically iOS 7.</p><p><a href="http://www.nikon.com/news/2014/0410_cpx_02.htm">29</a> &nbsp;Nikon: The first Android powered Nikon point and shoot didn't sell. Will the new COOLPIX S810c? Probably not. Spoiler: 3.7 inch screen, 16 megapixels, 12x optical zoom, Android 4.2.2 with all of Google's services baked in.</p><p><a href="http://conversations.nokia.com/2014/04/09/nokia-225/">30</a> &nbsp;Nokia: Despite being days away from being eaten up by Microsoft, they just announced a new $55 feature phone. Naturally, Bing is preloaded.</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/04/09/quora-raises-80m-led-by-tiger-global-now-valued-at-900m/">31</a> &nbsp;Quora: The premium version of Yahoo! Answers just raised $80 million at a $900 million valuation.</p><p><a href="http://www.sammobile.com/2014/04/09/sammobile-confirms-new-exynos-3250-soc-powers-gear-2-gear-fit-uses-cortex-m4-chip/?utm_source=feedly&amp;utm_reader=feedly&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=sammobile-confirms-new-exynos-3250-soc-powers-gear-2-gear-fit-uses-cortex-m4-chip">32</a> &nbsp;Samsung: For those who are curious about what's inside Samsung's new smart watches, this is for you. Spoiler: The Gear 2 and Gear 2 Neo use a Samsung made dual core 1 GHz Exynos 3250 chip. The Gear Fit (long skinny screen) uses an STMicroelectronics STM32F439 chip that features a 180 MHz ARM Cortex M4.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/09/us-samsung-elec-smartphones-analysis-idUSBREA3806J20140409">33</a> &nbsp;Samsung: The company "has knocked around a tenth off the price of its Galaxy S5 in South Korea, in the first such move for a marquee smartphone launch." The phone technically launches tomorrow, yet it's already been discounted in Korea?</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26963255">34</a> &nbsp;StoreDot: Remember that company that demoed a new type of battery technology that could fully recharge in 30 seconds? The founder was interviewed on television and revealed that the quick charge battery in question only lasts two to three hours on a charge. Translation: StoreDot scammed the internet.</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/04/09/most-mobile-game-players-quit-after-one-day-exclusive/">35</a> &nbsp;Swrve: This app testing company, using a sample size of 10 million mobile gamers, has come up with some pretty mind blowing stats: 19% of new games downloaded are only opened once. 66% of gamers stop playing a game 24 hours after they installed it. Only 2.2% of mobile gamers spend money on games, and 10% of them are responsible for 46% of all the revenues. Translation: Making money off mobile gaming is hard.</p><p><a href="http://www.nfcworld.com/2014/04/09/328653/wifi-alliance-adds-support-nfc/">36</a> &nbsp;WiFi: "The WiFi Alliance has updated its WiFi Protected Setup certification program to include tap-to-connect functionality via NFC." Go to your friend's house, tap their router, you're connected. Took long enough.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26966569">37</a> &nbsp;China: For the first time since 2009, Chinese exports have fallen for two consecutive months. Translation: Slowing economy.</p><p><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/education/2014/apr/09/new-work-life-balance-france-sweden-laws-countries-better-job-hours-work">38</a> &nbsp;France: "New labour laws in France now make it illegal for workers in the digital and consultancy sectors - including the French offices of Google, Facebook, Deloitte, and PwC - to respond to work emails after 6 PM."</p><p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-06/humans-replacing-robots-herald-toyota-s-vision-of-future.html?_ga=1.42881125.1374903220.1390550198">39</a> &nbsp;Japan: "Humans are taking the place of machines in [Toyota] plants across Japan so workers can develop new skills and figure out ways to improve production lines and the car-building process." So while everyone else is adding more robots, Toyota is saying nope, let's add more humans.</p><p><a href="http://apps.washingtonpost.com/g/page/world/the-depth-of-the-problem/931/">40</a> &nbsp;Malaysia: The Washington Post has done the impossible. They've made an "infographic" that's actually useful. It shows just how deep the MH370 flight recorder is in the Indian Ocean. Prepare to scroll. A lot.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26955341">41</a> &nbsp;Switzerland: This three minute video is a tour of a new airplane that will attempt to fly around the world next year using nothing but 18,000 solar cells embedded in its wings.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-26963938">42</a> &nbsp;UK: "Just three out of 43 police forces in England and Wales have a comprehensive plan to deal with a large-scale cyber attack, a report has found." But under what circumstances would a cyber attack become a police matter?</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26954482">43</a> &nbsp;UK: Research that was previously hidden, but is now available, says Tamiflu is about as useful as ordinary paracetamol (better known as Tylenol or Panadol). This is a pain point when you consider that the the U.K. government spent $795 million on a massive Tamiflu stockpile back when swine flu was a thing.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26959628">44</a> &nbsp;USA: "An attacker armed with two knives has gone on a rampage at a high school in the U.S. state of Pennsylvania, stabbing 21 students and a security guard. A suspect, named as Alex Hribal, 16, was arrested at Franklin Regional High School in Murrysville near Pittsburgh."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26966518">45</a> &nbsp;USA: "Bank of America has agreed to pay $783 million in fines and refunds to settle accusations it misled customers about its credit card services."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26964278">46</a> &nbsp;USA: "Republicans in the U.S. Senate have blocked a Democratic bill aimed at closing the gap between what men and women are paid. The Paycheck Fairness Act fell seven votes short of the 60 required to advance in the chamber."</p><p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2014/04/lapd-officers-monkey-wrenched-cop-monitoring-gear-in-patrol-cars/">47</a> &nbsp;USA: "The Los Angeles Police Commission is investigating how half of the recording antennas in the Southeast Division went missing, seemingly as a way to evade new self-monitoring procedures that the Los Angeles Police Department imposed last year." The watchers don't like being watched.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26939126">48</a> &nbsp;USA: Scientists have invented a new type of anchor after studying how a razor clam buries itself in the sand. This new clam is aptly called "RoboClam", but his friends call him Murphy. Practical uses? "Lay undersea cables and potentially even destroy mines."</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">49</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 09: 34 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 06:33:49 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/9/april-09-34-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:5344e9d4e4b092b8f01813f7</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.igloosoftware.com/campaigns/swisscom?ref=tabdump&amp;type=blog&amp;month=april">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: Igloo, makers of an intranet you'll actually like, are happy to announce an OEM partnership with Swisscom. Under the trademark Dynamic Intranet, Swisscom will host and distribute Igloo's cloud intranet solution to their customers in Switzerland, Germany, and Italy. This offers Swisscom's European customers a state-of-the-art hosting facility in Zürich, while Igloo's North American and international customers continue to be hosted at CenturyLink facilities in Canada.</p><p><a href="http://variety.com/2014/digital/news/amazon-streams-more-video-than-hulu-or-apple-but-its-still-miles-behind-netflix-1201154130/">02</a> &nbsp;Amazon: They say they're now the third largest video streaming service in the U.S., but what does that really mean? Netflix is number one with 57.5% of the video streaming market for the month of March. YouTube is number two with 16.9%. And finally, Amazon is number three with 6%.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2014/04/08/apple-closes-u-s-ad-spending-gap-with-samsung/">03</a> &nbsp;Apple: In 2012, Samsung spent $68 million more on marketing in the U.S. than Apple. In 2013, that number fell to $12 million. Curiously, Nokia spent 15x more on marketing in 2013 than they did in 2012. That obviously worked well for them.</p><p><a href="https://www.theinformation.com/Comcast-Quietly-Preps-Challenge-to-Wireless-Carriers">04</a> &nbsp;Comcast: According to an article on The Information that's behind a paywall, Comcast, America's largest cable TV provider, is thinking about launching an MVNO. When you're at home, your mobile phone will use WiFi for calls, texts, and data. When you're outside, you'll use an actual cellular network. Which network? That wasn't mentioned.</p><p><a href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140408PB203.html">05</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: "Apple is rumored to unveil its wearable iWatch in the third quarter and will target 65 million units in shipments for 2014." Righhht.</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/8/5594266/how-heartbleed-broke-the-internet">06</a> &nbsp;Heartbleed: This bug in the OpenSSL project, discovered by a Google employee, is getting a lot of attention. You've probably heard of it by now. Truth be told, there's a very high probability you're not going to be affected by it, yet the media continues to treat this situation like it's the end of times. My advice: Ignore it, because there's nothing you can do.</p><p><a href="http://youtu.be/mgytZ6bTmSQ">07</a> &nbsp;HTC: Here's the ad HTC hopes will convince people to buy their new flagship phone. Spoiler: Robert Downey Jr. talking for 62 (painful) seconds straight into the camera about design.</p><p><a href="http://www.eweek.com/blogs/storage-station/intel-huawei-to-co-develop-new-big-data-storage.html/">08</a> &nbsp;Huawei and Intel: The two have announced that they're going to tighten their R&amp;D relationship and work together on "big data" solutions. No financial figures were mentioned.</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/04/08/startup-promises-a-wearables-processor-with-30-days-of-battery-life/">09</a> &nbsp;Ineda Systems: Remember Sanjay Jha, the former CEO of Motorola Mobility? He's now chairman of a company (with 180+ engineers and $30 million in funding) that claims they've invented a chip that will enable wearable devices to last one month on a full charge. Re/code says we should see products using this chip in the next three to six months. It should be noted that Jha was a Qualcomm engineer, so he knows his stuff.</p><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/intels-new-reporting-structure-sheds-light-on-internet-of-things-mobile-7000028161/">10</a> &nbsp;Intel: Starting April 15th, when Intel publishes their Q1 2014 financial results, the company will report revenues from their mobile division (chips for phones and tablets) separately. This is historic when you consider that Intel has been trying, for years, to break into the mobile device market.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/09/us-intel-costa-rica-idUSBREA371TJ20140409?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">11</a> &nbsp;Intel: They're going to shut down their "assembly and test operation in Costa Rica, eliminating 1,500 jobs."</p><p><a href="http://www.pocket-lint.com/news/128341-lg-g-watch-release-date-by-july-and-less-than-180-in-the-uk-hands-on-pictures">12</a> &nbsp;LG: "LG has confirmed to Pocket-lint that its new LG G Watch, powered by Google's new Android Wear operating system, will be available before July and for less than £180 in the UK." Pocket-lint also has hands-on photos of the device, which is a first. Spoiler: It's ugly.</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/08/mediafire-takes-its-desktop-apps-out-of-beta-removes-file-size-restrictions/">13</a> &nbsp;MediaFire: This Dropbox and Google Drive competitor just slashed the price of their cloud storage service to $5 per month for 1 TB.</p><p><a href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140408PB202.html">14</a> &nbsp;MediaTek: Their Q1 2014 numbers are out. Revenues are up 91.9% year over year to $1.5 billion. If you don't know who MediaTek is, think of them as the Asian version of Qualcomm. Their chips may not be as good as Qualcomm's chips, but they're certainly good enough, and more importantly, they're far cheaper.</p><p><a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/netflix-begins-4k-streams/">15</a> &nbsp;Netflix: They've officially started streaming 4K video. One Catch: You need a 2014 4K TV. If you're an early adopter, sorry.</p><p><a href="http://articles.economictimes.indiatimes.com/2014-04-08/news/48939472_1_micromax-vineet-taneja-stores">16</a> &nbsp;Samsung: "Samsung India Electronics is looking to open 3,000-4,000 exclusive outlets across Indian towns with a population of less than 100,000."</p><p><a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/samsung-sues-korean-newspaper-2014-4">17</a> &nbsp;Samsung: "Samsung sued Korean newspaper ET News for the equivalent of almost $300,000 U.S. dollars for writing a negative story about the camera on the Galaxy S5."</p><p><a href="http://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-heads-youtube-show-galaxy-pro-tablets">18</a> &nbsp;Samsung: Here are their four latest 30 second TV ads. Spoiler: Your iPad doesn't have multiple user support. Your iPad can't multitask. Your iPad has fewer pixels than my Galaxy Tab.</p><p><a href="http://www.sammobile.com/2014/04/08/samsung-gear-fit-updated-with-option-to-enable-vertical-display-orientation/">19</a> &nbsp;Samsung: They've updated the software on the Gear Fit, the smartwatch that has a long skinny flexible screen, to work vertically. This addresses the number one complaint about the device, which technically doesn't even launch until Friday.</p><p><a href="http://thenextweb.com/media/2014/04/08/sesame-street-now-dedicated-video-demand-service-called-sesame-go/">20</a> &nbsp;Sesame Street: There's now a Netflix-like streaming service available for Sesame Street content. It's U.S. only and costs either $4/month or $30/year.</p><p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=10152331798589699&amp;set=a.76852559698.74126.54244899698&amp;type=1&amp;theater">21</a> &nbsp;Sony: According to an update on Sony Mobile Hong Kong's Facebook page, the company's flagship phone, the Xperia Z2, isn't shipping until June. This was a device that was supposed to launch globally in April.</p><p><a href="http://blog.us.playstation.com/2014/04/08/borderlands-2-ps-vita-bundle-coming-may-6th/">22</a> &nbsp;Sony: The updated version of Sony's mobile gaming device, the PS Vita, will come to the U.S. on May 6th for $200. Compared to the old Vita, the new one is significantly skinnier and also has better battery life.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26934932">23</a> &nbsp;StoreDot: This Israeli company got a lot of attention yesterday for demoing a smartphone battery that can fully recharge in 30 seconds. Why didn't I cover it? The founder of the company told the BBC that he'll "have a commercially ready device in three years." Translation: All we have is a rough prototype that's nowhere near ready for mass production.</p><p><a href="https://blog.twitter.com/2014/coming-soon-a-whole-new-you-in-your-twitter-profile">24</a> &nbsp;Twitter: They're renaming the service to Facebook.</p><p><a href="http://mediatel.co.uk/newsline/2014/04/08/tablet-ownership-up-63-as-digital-adspend-hits-record-high/">25</a> &nbsp;UK: "36% of people accessing the internet now do so via a tablet, according to UKOM and comScore, with UK tablet ownership growing 63% year on year in February 2014 to almost 18 million."</p><p><a href="http://www.techinasia.com/chinese-phone-maker-xiaomi-raked-in-242-million-in-12-hours-during-its-day-long-sales-blitz/">26</a> &nbsp;Xiaomi: They just sold 1.3 million phones in 12 hours to the tune of $242 million. If you still don't know why you should take Xiaomi seriously, Bloomberg <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-08/china-s-xiaomi-plans-to-give-the-world-iphone-cool-at-half-price.html">wrote written a fantastic brief</a> about the company yesterday.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26876844">27</a> &nbsp;Afghanistan: "The Afghan election complaints commission says it has received more than 3,000 reports of violations of which around half will be investigated." Picking a new president isn't easy.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26926724">28</a> &nbsp;France: Ever wanted to know how much money the French government spends on protecting sheep from wolves and compensating farmers that have lost some of their flock? $16.6 million a year.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/entertainment-arts-26935113">29</a> &nbsp;Hong Kong: A 15th century Chinese cup was sold at auction for $36 million. It's a new record for Chinese porcelain. The previous record, set in 2010, was $32.4 million. In other news, IKEA is holding a two for one sale on their $1 FÄRGRIK coffee mugs.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26950387">30</a> &nbsp;Malaysia: The team that originally "heard" the pings of the MH370 flight recorder say they've heard the pings again. Four pings in total have been picked up.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26950970">31</a> &nbsp;Toyota: They've just issued a recall affecting 6.4 million cars. They've identified five different issues in 27 of their models.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26949359">32</a> &nbsp;USA: "U.S. authorities have fined General Motors for failing to respond to requests for information about faulty ignition switches linked to 13 deaths. The car maker is being fined $7,000 a day until it complies with the request." Pocket change, sadly.</p><p><a href="http://www.sfgate.com/default/article/4-Smart-microcars-tipped-over-around-Bernal-5383973.php">33</a> &nbsp;USA: You know those tiny Smart Cars? Four of them were found tipped over on Monday morning in one small California town. Seven people with nothing better to do with their time are to blame.</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">34</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">why not become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 08: 45 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 07:46:11 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/8/april-08-45-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:5343a948e4b0fa0c168a7e34</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.igloosoftware.com/campaigns/swisscom?ref=tabdump&amp;type=blog&amp;month=april">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: Igloo, makers of an intranet you'll actually like, are happy to announce an OEM partnership with Swisscom. Under the trademark Dynamic Intranet, Swisscom will host and distribute Igloo's cloud intranet solution to their customers in Switzerland, Germany, and Italy. This offers Swisscom's European customers a state-of-the-art hosting facility in Zürich, while Igloo's North American and international customers continue to be hosted at CenturyLink facilities in Canada.</p><p><a href="http://9to5mac.com/2014/04/07/adobe-debuts-lightroom-mobile-for-ipad-for-powerful-on-the-go-photo-editing/">02</a> &nbsp;Adobe: Lightroom is now available for the iPad. "It requires the latest version of Lightroom 5 for Mac or PC (update available today) and a subscription to Adobe's Creative Cloud."</p><p><a href="http://9to5mac.com/2014/04/07/everything-to-know-about-ios-8-and-os-x-10-10-roundup-new-details/">03</a> &nbsp;Apple: 9to5Mac has posted a WWDC preview that's incredibly comprehensive, though I question why they did so almost two months before the actual event. But I digress, all the iOS 8 and OS X 10.10 leaks and rumors currently out there are in this piece.</p><p><a href="http://www.overthought.org/blog/2014/the-ultimate-guide-to-solving-ios-battery-drain">04</a> &nbsp;Apple: A former Apple Genius has published a detailed guide on how to increase the battery life of your iPhone. If you're having issues, and I know some of you are, then I hope this helps. Spoiler: Kill Facebook.</p><p><a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/phil-schiller-emails-2014-4">05</a> &nbsp;Apple: If you care about drama, here are some of the emails exchanged between Phil Schiller and Apple's ad agency over how they should deal with Samsung's rising success.</p><p><a href="http://www.fiercewireless.com/story/cincinnati-bell-quits-wireless-business-will-sell-spectrum-verizon-210m/2014-04-07?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss">06</a> &nbsp;Cincinnati Bell: America's ninth largest wireless operator (roughly 340,000 subscribers) "will sell to Verizon all of its wireless spectrum licenses for $194 million in cash."</p><p><a href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140407PD210.html">07</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: "Apple reportedly plans to form a R&amp;D team to develop baseband processors for use in iPhones to be released in 2015." The baseband, often called the modem, is the thing that enables your mobile phone to connect to your mobile operator. It's easily one of the most complicated parts of a device.</p><p><a href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140407PD208.html">08</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: "Microsoft reportedly has been aggressively trying to persuade MediaTek to push Windows-based tablets in China's white-box market." Note that the Surface RT and all of Nokia's Lumia phones use chips from MediaTek's biggest competitor, Qualcomm.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2014/04/07/foxconns-founding-family-eyes-cable-tv-alliance/">09</a> &nbsp;Foxconn: The company that makes iPads and iPhones for Apple allegedly wants to spend $2 billion to buy a Chinese cable company that has 1.2 million customers. Foxconn's end goal is to eventually produce content.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/07/google-pushes-back-io-2014-registration-window-at-the-last-minute-now-open-next-week-april-15-18th/">10</a> &nbsp;Google: Registration for Google I/O 2014 has been pushed back by a week. It was supposed to take place today. I'm assuming Google isn't done testing their new ticketing system, which is based on a lottery.</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702304819004579487863309991116?mg=reno64-wsj&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fonline.wsj.com%2Farticle%2FSB10001424052702304819004579487863309991116.html">11</a> &nbsp;Google: The WSJ says "Google struck a licensing deal that will give it access to technology from hotel-booking-software start-up Room 77 while increasing the size of its hotel-search team. Among those who reported for work at Google today was Calvin Yang, Room 77's co-founder and chief technology officer." No financial figures were mentioned.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/07/htc-results-idUSL4N0MT1U620140407">12</a> &nbsp;HTC: Their Q1 2014 numbers are out. Nutshell: $62.06 million in the red.</p><p><a href="http://htcsource.com/2014/03/htc-ad-reveals-plans-for-stealth-black-stealth-red-htc-one-m8/#prettyPhoto">13</a> &nbsp;HTC: There will be a "Stealth Red" version of the HTC One M8. The company accidentally started advertising it on Google. No photos, sadly.</p><p><a href="http://www.mojandroid.sk/2014/04/02/huawei-ascend-p7-predstavenie/">14</a> &nbsp;Huawei: A Slovakian Android website says Huawei will be hosting an event in Paris on May 7th to unveil their latest flagship phone. They say Huawei has confirmed the event with them.</p><p><a href="http://variety.com/2014/biz/news/movie-studios-sue-defunct-piracy-site-megaupload-seeking-millions-in-damages-1201153704/">15</a> &nbsp;Megaupload: Six movie studios are suing Megaupload, they want $175 million (total).</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26884167">16</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: Today's the day. Windows XP is dead. Not really, but everyone will say that anyway.</p><p><a href="http://www.wpcentral.com/windows-phone-81-two-os-updates-2014?utm_source=wpc&amp;utm_medium=twitter">17</a> &nbsp;Nokia: Deep in this article about the alleged future of Windows Phone is this nugget: "I've also heard rumblings of a dual-lens phone from Nokia later this year, where two cameras would be used perhaps for a multi-focus, Lytro type effect." HTC's M8 has two cameras, so Nokia going the dual-camera route wouldn't be that insane.</p><p><a href="http://press.nokia.com/2014/04/08/planned-sale-of-substantially-all-of-nokias-devices-services-business-to-microsoft-has-received-regulatory-approval-from-china/">18</a> &nbsp;Nokia: They published a press release this morning saying China has approved the Microsoft deal. No word as to which countries haven't said yes yet, but most people think it's India.</p><p><a href="http://www.anandtech.com/show/7925/qualcomms-snapdragon-808810-20nm-highend-64bit-socs-with-lte-category-67-support-in-2015">19</a> &nbsp;Qualcomm: They announced two flagship 64-bit Snapdragon chips, the 808 and 810. Both are very unorthodox in that they use ARM designed application processors instead of Qualcomm's own in-house APs. They're also not going to ship until 2015.</p><p><a href="http://www.koreaherald.com/view.php?ud=20140407001171">20</a> &nbsp;Samsung: "Samsung Gear Solo" will allegedly be the product name for a new Samsung smartwatch that features a SIM card slot. Said watch is rumored to be a Korea only product.</p><p><a href="http://www.anandtech.com/show/7903/samsung-galaxy-s-5-review">21</a> &nbsp;Samsung: A ton of Galaxy S5 reviews have gone live today. I'm sure they're all good, but this one is the best.</p><p><a href="http://www.sammobile.com/2014/04/07/exclusive-samsung-sm-t800-10-5-amoled-tablet-specs/">22</a> &nbsp;Samsung: SamMobile has published the full specifications of a high-end 10.5 inch tablet that Samsung will soon announce. What makes this tablet special is that it has an AMOLED display. No photos, but expect this thing to look like a giant Galaxy S5.</p><p><a href="http://global.samsungtomorrow.com/?p=35678">23</a> &nbsp;Samsung: The Galaxy Ace Style is official. It's a low end 4.0 inch phone running the latest version of Android. No price, but Samsung says it'll ship globally starting this month.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26933449">24</a> &nbsp;Samsung: They expect to "make an operating profit of $7.9 billion for the January-to-March quarter, down 4% from the same period last year. This follows a 6% decline in operating profit in the previous quarter."</p><p><a href="http://www.extremetech.com/computing/179972-seagate-unveils-worlds-fastest-6tb-hard-drive-and-it-isnt-filled-with-helium">25</a> &nbsp;Seagate: They unveiled a $600 6 TB hard drive. It's meant for enterprises, but still, you have to marvel that 6 TB hard drives are now a thing.</p><p><a href="https://media.skype.com/skype-tx/">26</a> &nbsp;Skype: They've announced something called Skype TX, which is "an easy-to-use hardware and software combination" meant for broadcasters or people "within in a studio environment." Translation: A (hopefully) better version of Skype for professionals.</p><p><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/sarahcohen/2014/04/04/softbank-said-to-be-scouting-europe-for-opportunities/">27</a> &nbsp;SoftBank: Forbes is reporting that if SoftBank fails to merge Sprint and T-Mobile, they might start buying up European operators.</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/07/twitter-acquires-android-lockscreen-app-cover-moves-deeper-into-mobile-services/">28</a> &nbsp;Twitter: They spent an undisclosed amount of money on custom Android lock screen maker "Cover". What makes "Cover" special? Depending on your location and/or time of day, different application shortcuts are displayed on your screen.</p><p><a href="http://blog.uber.com/RUSH">29</a> &nbsp;Uber: The car hire service is expanding into the courier business, but only in Manhattan. The new service is called Uber RUSH and costs between $15 to $30, depending on distance.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidnext.de/news/whatsapp-as-a-carrier-pay-as-you-go-offer-launched-in-germany-unlimited-data-for-whatsapp-messaging-included/">30</a> &nbsp;WhatsApp: There's now a "WhatsApp" prepaid SIM in Germany that basically gives you free WhatsApp service, regardless of the balance on the SIM. Data is incredibly pricey at 0.24 Euros per megabyte, but if you pay 10 Euros a month, you get 600 "units", where a unit is either one megabyte of data or one SMS or one minute of calling. The SIM is powered by E-Plus.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.abc.net.au/news/2014-04-07/triathlete-injured-as-drone-filming-race-drops-to-ground/5371658">31</a> &nbsp;Australia: Raija Ogden was competing in a triathlon when a drone that was recording the event fell out of the sky from a height of 10 meters (32 feet) and hit her in the head. She's fine, and she says it could've been a lot worse, specifically saying the drone could have fallen on a small child in the crowd.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26923214">32</a> &nbsp;Europe: Scientists studying nearly 32,000 bee colonies in 17 EU countries have come to the conclusion that the rate of mortality of Northern European bees is off the charts. There's a 33.6% chance that a bee in Belgium will not survive the winter. In the UK, it's 28.8%. In Sweden, it's 28.7%. One normally expects a death rate of 10%.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/entertainment-arts-26921613">33</a> &nbsp;Germany: Remember that guy that had over 1,400 pieces of art stolen by the Nazis in his apartment? He's finally agreed to let investigators try and find the rightful owners of said art, which is estimated to to be worth $1.35 billion, and then return it to them.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26917871">34</a> &nbsp;Japan and Australia: The two countries have signed a trade deal after seven years of negations. There are a lot of bullet points, but here's the one sentence summary: Japan will pay less import taxes on Australian beef and cheese, and Australia will pay less import taxes on Japanese gizmos and cars.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-26923351">35</a> &nbsp;Poland: Artur Debski is a Polish politician that wants to find out why his country's young people are leaving en masse to find jobs in the UK, so he's decided to do what they do. He's coming to the UK to find a job via a job center and plans to live on $165 a week to see just how the British system works so he can bring it to Poland.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26329320">36</a> &nbsp;Space: Scientists studying the birth of the universe have discovered that "three billion years after the Big Bang, the cosmos was pushing itself apart by another 1% every 44 million years."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26919305">37</a> &nbsp;Taiwan: Students took over Taiwan's parliament building in the middle of March to protest the country's economic ties with China. They've been occupying the building this whole time. The students just announced that they'll be leaving on Thursday.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26931251">38</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: "Rebels occupying Donetsk's regional government building declared a 'people's republic' on Monday and called for a referendum on secession from Ukraine to be held by 11 May." Crimea 2.0?</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26920521">39</a> &nbsp;USA: "Four paralyzed men have been able to move their legs for the first time in years after electrical stimulation of their spinal cords, US doctors report." These guys aren't walking, but they're at least able to move their limbs, albeit in an uncontrolled fashion.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26921734">40</a> &nbsp;USA: "Petrol-sniffing spiders have forced Mazda to issue a voluntary recall notice so it can apply a software fix to its cars. The yellow sac spider is attracted to the smell of petrol, and will weave its web in engines, causing a blockage and build-up of pressure." This affects roughly 42,000 cars.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26927836">41</a> &nbsp;USA: Remember that train derailment in New York in December 2013 that killed four people? The National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) released a report on Monday saying the driver of that train, William Rockefeller, suffers from "severe obstructive sleep apnoea". Translation: He dozed at the wheel.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26927833">42</a> &nbsp;USA: The Washington mudslide death toll has reached 33; 10 people are still missing.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-26933392">43</a> &nbsp;Venezuela: The death toll from the protests now stands at 39.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26923260">44</a> &nbsp;World: "Global investment in renewables fell by 14% during 2013, but the percentage of electricity generated by renewable sources still grew." Also good news: "Renewables accounted for 43.6% of newly installed generation capacity in 2013." By the way, this data is from The United Nations, so it's solid.</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">45</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 07: 42 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 09:36:58 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/7/april-07-42-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:534271bde4b008f8c6d9a0f4</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.igloosoftware.com/?ref=tabdump&amp;type=blog&amp;month=april">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: Igloo has some exciting news to announce – tomorrow.</p><p><a href="https://fresh.amazon.com/dash">02</a> &nbsp;Amazon: They've unveiled a WiFi enabled stick that has a microphone and a barcode scanner. When you're out of toilet paper, milk, toothpaste, whatever, either say the name or scan the barcode of said item and it'll automatically be ordered. Note that to receive said stick, which is called the "Dash", you have to be personally selected by Amazon themselves, as well as be a user of Amazon Fresh.</p><p><a href="http://www.engadget.com/2014/04/06/apple-consumers-want-what-we-dont-have/">03</a> &nbsp;Apple: An internal slide dating back to April 2013 was released thanks to the Apple/Samsung trial. It's titled "Consumers want what we don't have" and shows Apple fully understands that the growth of the mobile phone market comes from sub $300 products and phones with screens larger than 4.0 inches.</p><p><a href="http://ausdroid.net/2014/04/06/asus-c200-chromebook-leaks-on-google/">04</a> &nbsp;ASUS: Photos of an unreleased Chromebook from ASUS have appeared online. This is semi-noteworthy because ASUS hasn't entered the Chromebook game yet.</p><p><a href="http://www.comscore.com/Insights/Press_Releases/2014/4/comScore_Reports_February_2014_US_Smartphone_Subscriber_Market_Share">05</a> &nbsp;comScore: People love when comScore publishes fresh data on the U.S. smartphone market, so here's a link to their latest numbers. Spoiler: Apple has more market share (41.3%), than the number two (Samsung at 27.0%), three (LG at 6.8%), and four (Motorola at 6.3%) players combined.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/03/us-italy-google-privacy-idUSBREA3226A20140403">06</a> &nbsp;Google: $1.4 million. That's how big of a fine Google received "over complaints that cars it used to record images on Italian streets in 2010 were not clearly recognizable."</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/06/rumor-googles-plan-to-bridge-chrome-android-and-search-to-do-everything-on-your-device/">07</a> &nbsp;Google: Android Police says Google is working on something called "Hera", which aims to give "apps" written in HTML the same kind of power that native Android apps have. The article is light on details, but I'm going to assume we'll hear more about this at Google I/O on June 25th. It should be noted that Sundar Pichai, the guy in charge of Chrome, also <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sundar_Pichai">took over Android</a> in March 2013.</p><p><a href="http://www.billboard.com/biz/articles/news/digital-and-mobile/6039418/business-matters-whats-behind-youtube-music-services">08</a> &nbsp;Google: Billboard says Google's Spotify clone has been delayed to Q2 or later. They say Google has all the content deals, that's not the problem, the problem is that Google isn't done with the product. Note that Google already has a Spotify clone called Google Play Music All Access, so it's not clear what this new service, powered by YouTube, will provide.</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/5/5584604/this-is-android-tv">09</a> &nbsp;Google: The Verge has obtained information and images of something called "Android TV". As far as I can tell, it's just a clone of Amazon's new Fire TV product that was unveiled last week. Android TV will allegedly launch "soon", and not much else is known.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26886579">10</a> &nbsp;IBM: "The IBM mainframe is celebrating its 50th anniversary. The first System 360 mainframe was unveiled on 7 April 1964."</p><p><a href="http://www.thejakartapost.com/news/2014/04/04/govt-may-impose-luxury-tax-cell-phones.html">11</a> &nbsp;Indonesia: All phones sold in Indonesia are taxed at a rate of 7.5%. The country is thinking about bumping that up to 20% for phones that cost more than $440.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/04/us-internet-ambitions-idUSBREA331R520140404?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">12</a> &nbsp;Internet Companies: Reuters polled roughly 5,000 Americans between March 11th and March 16th and discovered that over half of them (51%) said Google, Facebook, Amazon, Apple, Microsoft, and Twitter were "pushing too far and expanding into too many areas of people's lives." Another fun number: 27% think Google's "Don't Be Evil" slogan is total BS.</p><p><a href="http://news.lenovo.com/article_display.cfm?article_id=1784">13</a> &nbsp;Lenovo: The company that took Motorola off Google's hands has just bought 3,800 patents from NEC, some of which are considered essential for 3G and LTE. No price tag was given.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26879185">14</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: A five year old boy discovered a bug in the XBOX Live online gaming service that let him log into his father's account simply by using a password full of spaces. Conveniently, the boy's father is a security researcher. He reached out to Microsoft, who then thanked the boy and gave him four free games.</p><p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-07/microsoft-goes-hollywood-in-amazon-like-programming-push.html">15</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: Bloomberg says Microsoft has commissioned six television shows that will only be available to XBOX customers. Said shows will start airing in June. No word as to how much they cost to make.</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/5/5585148/microsoft-windows-in-the-car-concept">16</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: They unveiled a concept of what can best be described as an Apple CarPlay clone. Unlike CarPlay, which has a rough ship date and a list of partners, "Windows in the Car" is just a pretty slideshow right now.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26901433">17</a> &nbsp;Pakistan: "A Pakistani Christian couple have been sentenced to death for blasphemy after allegedly sending a text message insulting the Prophet Muhammad."</p><p><a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/samsung-key-executives-depart-from-us-business/#ftag=CAD590a51e">18</a> &nbsp;Samsung: "At least five high-ranking executives from Samsung's US mobile business -- known as Samsung Telecommunications America, or STA -- have left the company or have given their notice over the past two months, people familiar with the departures told CNET."</p><p><a href="http://www.sammobile.com/2014/04/05/dual-sim-galaxy-s5-launches-in-china/">19</a> &nbsp;Samsung: As expected, the company unveiled a dual-SIM version of the Galaxy S5 for China. Watch it also come to India, Russia, and other markets where dual-SIM is popular over the next few months.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-shows-official-galaxy-s5-wireless-charging-covers">20</a> &nbsp;Samsung: The company's 2014 flagship phone, the Galaxy S5, has a silly door covering the USB port. It's going to annoy tens of millions of people, guaranteed. Here are the official replacement battery door covers that add wireless charging.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/04/turkey-youtube-idUSL5N0MV0UC20140404">21</a> &nbsp;Turkey: "A Turkish court on Friday ruled that a blanket ban of social-media website YouTube violated human rights and ordered most of the restrictions be lifted." Wait, access to YouTube is a human right?</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702304441304579481614220149076">22</a> &nbsp;Twitter: According to the WSJ, Twitter "will debut 15 types of new ad products and improved ways to target users over the next six months." The first of those ad products, applications ads, have <a href="http://recode.net/2014/04/04/app-ads-are-huge-for-facebook-here-comes-twitters-version/">already been seen</a> by some users.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26876801">23</a> &nbsp;USA: Remember that Cuban version of Twitter that was allegedly designed by the United States government? The U.S. government has confirmed that yes, they were indeed behind the service.</p><p><a href="http://thenextweb.com/google/2014/04/06/waze-ceo-confirms-google-paid-1-15b-for-the-company-hints-investor-pressure-forced-deal/">24</a> &nbsp;Waze: "A blog post on LinkedIn from Noam Bardin, who is CEO and co-founder of Waze, confirms that Google agreed to a $1.15 billion deal to buy the company." This is the first time the Waze acquisition figure has been made public.</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/article_email/SB10001424052702304819004579485820610824060-lMyQjAxMTA0MDAwNjEwNDYyWj">25</a> &nbsp;Yahoo!: The WSJ says Yahoo! is close to ordering four television shows to be made, each with 10 episodes, with each episode being 30 minutes long and costing "from $700,000 to a few million dollars". No word as to when said shows, which technically aren't even real yet, will air.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26903931">26</a> &nbsp;Afghanistan: The country just had their first presidential election. Usually people who want to take control of Afghanistan use tanks and/or guns, so this is historic. Of the 12 million people eligible to vote, roughly seven million actually did, with one third of them being women. Results are expected to be announced in a few days.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26913497">27</a> &nbsp;Africa: Nigeria has officially surpassed South Africa to become the country with the largest economy in Africa. That being said, South Africa has a GDP-per-capita that's three times higher than that of Nigeria.</p><p><a href="http://www.theage.com.au/national/holy-smoke-tobacco-plant-shows-cancerfighting-potential-20140402-35xqm.html">28</a> &nbsp;Australia: There are two versions of tobacco. The pretty version, and the version that gets turned into cigarettes. Scientists have discovered the pretty version produces a chemical called "NaD1" that can "fight off fungal and bacterial infections". The researchers want to test this chemical on human cancer patients, but it should be stressed that it'll be at least a decade until this stuff becomes a commercial product.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26892459">29</a> &nbsp;Germany: "A team of engineers in Germany has produced a bionic kangaroo, capable of jumping and then recovering its balance." It weighs seven kilograms, it's one meter tall, and can jump 40 centimeters into the air. This isn't an article, it's a one minute video.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-26883201">30</a> &nbsp;India: The country's general election, officially the world's largest, has just begun. There are 814 million potential voters. The vote is so massive that it's being split over nine days, with the final votes due to be counted on May 16.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26917934">31</a> &nbsp;Malaysia: "An Australian vessel searching for the missing Malaysia Airlines plane has detected signals consistent with those from aircraft black boxes."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-26917419">32</a> &nbsp;Rwanda: They're going to "start a week of official mourning to mark the 20th anniversary of the country's genocide." 800,000 people were killed in 100 days. Sadly, the Rwandan Genocide doesn't really get a lot of attention, just like Syria, because hey, it's so far away, and we don't have economic ties with them, right?</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26872184">33</a> &nbsp;Space: Enceladus, one of Saturn's moons, apparently has a body of water the size of Lake Michigan. Key quote, from UK Professor Andrew Coates: "I think Enceladus has gone to the top of the charts in terms of a place where there could be life."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-26908613">34</a> &nbsp;UK: 15 million tons. That's how much food the UK throws away every year. The EU total is 90 million tons. It's easy to blame consumers, but this article points out that the relationship between supermarkets and their suppliers should also be examined.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26888272">35</a> &nbsp;UK: Sales of over the counter HIV tests are now legal. Unfortunately, no one is selling them yet due to EU regulations. That's expected to change either by the end of this year or early 2015. An estimated 25,000 people are living with HIV in the UK and don't know it.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-26892771">36</a> &nbsp;UK: The UK's Ministry of Defense has a new robot called "The Porton Man" that costs over $1.82 million, has more than 100 sensors inside its body, and will be used primarily for developing "the next generation of CB (chemical and biological) protective suit equipment." It also looks terrifying.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/blogs-news-from-elsewhere-26882664">37</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: Darth Vader will not be allowed to compete in the May 25th presidential election.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26910210">38</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: Donetsk, Luhansk, and Kharkiv are three cities in East Ukraine that are starting to look like they're going to be the next Crimea. Protestors in those cities have broken into government buildings, raised Russian flags, and are demanding a referendum on independence.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26902522">39</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: The country is used to paying $268.50 for 1,000 cubic meters of natural gas. Russia just raised that price by 81% to $485.50. Ukraine's response? Refuse to pay Russia and bring them to court if necessary.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26890910">40</a> &nbsp;USA: Former President George W. Bush has a hobby that I personally never knew he had: Painting. This past Saturday, he showcased over 24 portraits of some of the world leaders he's met.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26897226">41</a> &nbsp;USA: Remember that Chicago train derailment? Turns out the driver, age 25, fell asleep at the wheel. She's been fired.</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">42</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 04: 40 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 07:34:38 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/4/april-04-40-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:533e6095e4b063017f76e3d8</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://newsblur.com/">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: About one year ago, Google announced they were going to kill Google Reader. Now if you don't know what RSS is, then I can't adequately explain to you why that day was tragic. I immediately spent the next few weeks and months testing every RSS reader under the sun to find a suitable replacement, and I'm proud to say that I have: NewsBlur. Without NewsBlur, this website, and my enjoyment of the internet, would simply not be be possible.</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/03/speech-recognition-pioneer-novauris-bought-by-apple-team-now-works-on-siri/">02</a> &nbsp;Apple: "Apple quietly acquired an automatic speech recognition (ASR) technology company called Novauris Technologies, which grew out of Dragon Systems R&amp;D U.K. Ltd., the British research subsidiary of Dragon Systems." No financial figures were mentioned.</p><p><a href="https://developer.apple.com/wwdc/">03</a> &nbsp;Apple: WWDC dates have officially been announced: June 02 to 06.</p><p><a href="http://www.cyanogenmod.org/blog/cyanogen-inc-new-identity">04</a> &nbsp;Cyanogen: The company that's trying to turn their custom Android ROM into a legit business has rebranded themselves. Their new logo should be familiar to fans of the 1987 cult classic "RoboCop".</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/3/5577418/europe-connected-continent-net-neutrality-roaming-fees">05</a> &nbsp;Europe: The European Parliament has voted to eliminate roaming fees effective December 2015. They're also forcing all European ISPs to abide by net neutrality principles.</p><p><a href="http://www.macstories.net/news/facebook-messenger-4-1-adds-free-wifi-calls-for-all-users/">06</a> &nbsp;Facebook: "Facebook's Messenger app has today added free audio calls on WiFi (VoIP) for all users [Note: That means Android and iOS] in all countries."</p><p><a href="http://thenextweb.com/facebook/2014/04/03/facebook-paid-330-security-researchers-1-5-million-2013-part-bug-bounty-program/">07</a> &nbsp;Facebook: $1.5 million. That's how much money Facebook awarded to security researchers in 2013 for submitting critical bugs.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidcentral.com/firechat-bringing-grid-messaging-android">08</a> &nbsp;Firechat: That iOS chat app that's been getting a lot of attention because it lets you talk to people using only Bluetooth and WiFi is now available for Android.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2014/04/03/flickrs-spiering-departs-for-berlin-start-up-eyeem/">09</a> &nbsp;Flickr: Mark Spiering, Flickr's Head of Product, has left to become Head of Product at Berlin based EyeEm. They essentially make a Flickr clone that's mobile only. EyeEm's app has been downloaded over 10 million times.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/03/report-google-is-looking-into-offering-mobile-phone-service-in-google-fiber-markets/">10</a> &nbsp;Google: According to an article on The Information that's behind a paywall, Google has talked to Verizon about the possibility of launching an MVNO in areas where Google has deployed Google Fiber. I'm going to assume Google wants to do this so they can offer what the industry calls a "triple play" package. One bill, three services: Internet, TV, Phone.</p><p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.paidtasks&amp;hl=en&amp;referrer=utm_source%3D42matters.com%26utm_medium%3DWidgetWeb">11</a> &nbsp;Google: The "Google Opinion Rewards" app, which gives you Play Store credit in return for answering surveys, is now available in Canada, the United Kingdom, and Australia. Before it was U.S. only.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/law/2014/04/03/cracks-in-googles-bid-to-trademark-glass/">12</a> &nbsp;Google: The United States Patent and Trademark Office is refusing to give Google a trademark on the word "Glass". Here's the scary part: "Trademark attorneys for Google, Anne Peck and Katie Krajeck from Cooley LLP, wrote back to the trademark office examiner two weeks ago with a 1,928-page letter in defense of the application." How heavy was that envelope?</p><p><a href="http://youtu.be/_Q1JzJadgHY">13</a> &nbsp;Google: They've uploaded a three and a half minute video showing off Project Ara, which is an attempt to create a modular mobile phone. Personally, I have very little faith in this ever becoming a retail product.</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/03/after-five-years-of-bootstrapping-imgur-raises-40-million-from-andreessen-reddit/">14</a> &nbsp;Imgur: The center of the internet meme universe has just raised $40 million.</p><p><a href="http://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2014/04/03/news-revenue-declines-despite-growth-from-new-sources/">15</a> &nbsp;Journalism: New research from Pew says revenues generated by American journalism have declined by one third since 2006. That being said, the percentage of people paying for news has increased from 16% in 2006 to 24% today.</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/3/5578114/windows-phone-8-1-available-april-14th">16</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: On April 14th, Microsoft will allegedly publish a Windows Phone 8.1 Developer Preview that just about any Windows Phone owner will be able to install. I'm going to recommend you just wait for an official over-the-air update instead of potentially breaking your phone.</p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/Office/statuses/451796278578774016">17</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: The company has tweeted that Office for iPad has been downloaded over 12 million times.</p><p><a href="https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2014/04/03/brendan-eich-steps-down-as-mozilla-ceo/">18</a> &nbsp;Mozilla: The CEO of Mozilla has resigned because of all the controversy over his 2008 donation to a political campaign seeking to ban gay marriage in the U.S. state of California.</p><p><a href="https://nest.com/letter-from-the-ceo/">19</a> &nbsp;Nest: Sales of the Nest smoke and carbon monoxide detector have been halted due to a bug that lets users unintentionally disable the device.</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702303847804579479931560176964?mg=reno64-wsj&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fonline.wsj.com%2Farticle%2FSB10001424052702303847804579479931560176964.html">20</a> &nbsp;Samsung: Some athlete was paid a lot of money to promote a Samsung phone. Said athlete used his Samsung phone to take a selfie with the President of the United States. Said selfie went viral. According to the WSJ, the White House is furious about this.</p><p><a href="http://www.netzwelt.de/news/126221-galaxy-ace-style-einsteiger-smartphone-kitkat-s5-oberflaeche.html">21</a> &nbsp;Samsung: The company accidentally showed off a smartphone that hasn't been announced yet, the Galaxy Ace Style. It's a low end budget Android 4.4 device with a 4.0 inch screen.</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/4/5580848/samsungs-ativ-se-windows-phone-now-available-for-pre-order-from">22</a> &nbsp;Samsung: The Samsung ATIV SE is now official. It's a Galaxy S4 that runs Windows Phone.</p><p><a href="http://www.sammobile.com/2014/04/04/samsung-set-to-launch-the-galaxy-s3-neo-in-india/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=samsung-set-to-launch-the-galaxy-s3-neo-in-india">23</a> &nbsp;Samsung: They're relaunching the Galaxy S III in India. Reminder: It's a two year old phone.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26873603">24</a> &nbsp;Turkey: The Twitter ban has been lifted. The YouTube ban, however, is still in place.</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/04/03/tech-giants-team-up-with-pharma-to-protect-software-patents/">25</a> &nbsp;USA: You know how everyone likes to talk about the broken American patent system and how it should be fixed? Apple, Microsoft, and IBM, among other companies, are now working together to make sure nothing changes.</p><p><a href="http://blog.vine.co/post/81606025464/vine-messages">26</a> &nbsp;Vine: Twitter's six second video sharing service now supports direct (aka private) messaging.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26868529">27</a> &nbsp;VKontakte: Russia's version of Facebook is facing legal action from Sony, Universal, and Warner Music, over a service they offer that gives Russians access to unlicensed music. This isn't the first time this has happened. "In November 2012, VK was found guilty by the Russian Supreme Court of distributing unlicensed music belonging to the Gala Music Group."</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/article_email/SB10001424052702303847804579477633444768964-lMyQjAxMTA0MDAwMzEwNDMyWj">28</a> &nbsp;Yelp: Those reviews that you read on Yelp, ever stop and wonder if some of them aren't actually legitimate? This WSJ article makes for a fascinating read, and it has this startling data point: "Yelp said it <strong>receives roughly six subpoenas monthly</strong>, some of which seek the names of anonymous users."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26872866">29</a> &nbsp;ZunZuneo: That's the name of a Cuban version of Twitter that was secretly created by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID). It apparently had 400,000 users at its peak. ZunZuneo is Cuban slang for the noise a hummingbird makes.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://youtu.be/XbbROe8xOZQ">30</a> &nbsp;China: This 49 second shows a Chinese street vendor making popcorn in a rather peculiar way. Spoiler: His popcorn machine doubles as a cannon.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-scotland-glasgow-west-26875793">31</a> &nbsp;Europe: With a sample size of 3,955 people spread out over nine European countries, the International Agency for Research on Cancer has discovered that not regularly seeing a dentist puts you at a higher risk of developing oral cancer. Sounds obvious, right? On the flip side, they also discovered that people who regularly use mouthwash are also at a higher risk for developing oral cancer.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-pacific-26872447">32</a> &nbsp;Indonesia: The government will "pay $1.8 million in blood money to prevent an Indonesian maid being executed in Saudi Arabia." Said maid hit her employer in 2007 so hard that she slipped into a coma and died. The maid says she was constantly abused, hence the attack.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-26872357">33</a> &nbsp;Nigeria: Lamido Sanusi, Nigeria's Bank Chief, caused a bit of a ruckus when he reported that $20 billion of the country's oil revenues are missing. He had his passport confiscated and he's been harassed, so he filed a complaint. Result? $300,000 compensation. Sadly, that $20 billion is still missing.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26871970">34</a> &nbsp;UK: "An accumulating body of evidence supports a link between urban green space and benefits to human wellbeing." Translation: People feel better when they're near nature.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26868119">35</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: "Ukraine's special police were behind the killings of dozens of anti-government protesters in Kiev in February, a government inquiry says. Interior Minister Arsen Avakov told reporters that 12 members of the Berkut police had been identified as snipers and arrested."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26864194">36</a> &nbsp;USA: For the first time since January 2007, not a single American soldier has died in Afghanistan for a given calendar month. Let's hope future months will be as good as March.</p><p><a href="https://plus.google.com/+NASA/posts/eihoeSm5fVy">37</a> &nbsp;USA: NASA has published a statement on Google+ that basically says they're not going to work with Russia anymore. Note that this does not apply to NASA's commitments to the International Space Station.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26872869">38</a> &nbsp;USA: The death toll from the Washington mudslide now stands at 30; 13 people are still missing.</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">39</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p><p><a href="http://tinyletter.com/tabdump">40</a> &nbsp;One more thing: Tradition dictates I remind you <a href="http://tinyletter.com/tabdump">Tab Dump via email</a> exists on Friday.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 03: 48 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2014 09:26:22 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/3/april-03-48-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:533d2942e4b09af6610189ce</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://newsblur.com/">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: About one year ago, Google announced they were going to kill Google Reader. Now if you don't know what RSS is, then I can't adequately explain to you why that day was tragic. I immediately spent the next few weeks and months testing every RSS reader under the sun to find a suitable replacement, and I'm proud to say that I have: NewsBlur. Without NewsBlur, this website, and my enjoyment of the internet, would simply not be be possible.</p><p><a href="http://thevoicemail.wordpress.com/2014/04/03/episode-092/">02</a> &nbsp;Podcast: James Whatley and I sat down for 37 minutes this morning for our weekly mobile focused tech podcast. We spent the first 20 minutes talking about all of yesterday's Microsoft and Nokia news.</p><p><a href="http://www.engadget.com/2014/04/02/amazon-announces-android-powered-streaming-stick/">03</a> &nbsp;Amazon: They launched a $99 Android powered Apple TV clone in the United States that features a remote control which can perform voice searches. &nbsp;For an additional $40, Amazon will also <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2014/04/02/amazon-fire-tv-game-controller/?utm_source=Feed_Classic_Full&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Engadget&amp;?ncid=rss_full">sell you a videogame controller</a>.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2014/04/02/apples-jobs-declared-holy-war-on-google-over-android/?mod=rss_Technology">04</a> &nbsp;Apple: It's not every day you get to see snippets of the emails Steve Jobs sent to his colleagues. The WSJ has two. One says Apple is in a "Holy War" with Android. Another says Apple is in danger of developing a case of the innovator's dilemma.</p><p><a href="http://www.fiercewireless.com/press-releases/att-hiring-more-3000-retail-employees">05</a> &nbsp;AT&amp;T: They're going to "hire more than 3,000 retail sales and sales management employees nationwide over the next several months."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-26850393">06</a> &nbsp;Bolivia: The country's first telecommunications satellite, valued at $300 million, is now live. President Evo Morales says his people can expect their mobile phone bills to fall by 20%.</p><p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-02/coolpad-targets-online-phone-sales-to-pass-lenovo.html">07</a> &nbsp;Coolpad: This Chinese handset maker, which is almost as big as Lenovo in China, plans to sell 60 million smartphones in 2014, with 20 million of those being from their new online store that was built in partnership with JD.com.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/02/rumor-android-silver-may-be-googles-attempt-to-finally-provide-a-premium-android-sale-and-support-experience/">08</a> &nbsp;Google: According to leaked slides obtained by Android Police, Google is planning a premium Android retail experience for U.S. wireless operator stores called "Android Silver". To be in this program, device makers need to make hardware that "runs the latest version of Android with no or very limited customizations". Google will also offer 24x7 support to people who buy "Android Silver" devices. Said support will work in much the same way as Amazon's Mayday service, meaning someone can take over your Android phone and help you. A launch date for "Android Silver" was not mentioned.</p><p><a href="http://www.geek.com/android/google-is-testing-an-army-of-new-features-for-gmail-1589767/">09</a> &nbsp;Google: They're testing a completely new look for their Gmail mobile app. Here are two leaked screenshots of the Android version. Note that the iOS version will probably look very similar.</p><p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-02/intel-plans-100-million-china-fund-to-spur-adoption-of-chips.html">10</a> &nbsp;Intel: They've notoriously had difficulty getting tablet and smartphone makers to use their chips, so they've just announced a $100 million Chinese investment fund that aims to change companies' minds.</p><p><a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/intel-outs-baswell-next-chip-for-chromebooks/">11</a> &nbsp;Intel: They've released a 64-bit version of Android that unsurprisingly only works on Intel chips.</p><p><a href="http://variety.com/2014/digital/news/italo-motion-picture-org-anica-launches-its-own-vod-service-1201151551/">12</a> &nbsp;Italy: ANICA, Italy's version of the MPAA, will launch a video on demand service to combat piracy. At launch, only 350 titles will be available, but it's expected that this will be the premier service for Italian film. The price of the service was not mentioned.</p><p><a href="http://www.computerworld.com/s/article/print/9247358/Ex_Microsoft_employee_pleads_guilty_to_trade_secret_theft">13</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: Remember that Microsoft employee that leaked products to that French blogger and started the whole Microsoft/Hotmail/privacy scandal? Three months of jail time and a $22,500 fine.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kT3qLOMK6V4">14</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: The company held a three hour keynote yesterday. I highly recommend you watch The Verge's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kT3qLOMK6V4">seven minute supercut</a>. Here are the main highlights: <a href="http://blogs.windows.com/windows_phone/b/windowsphone/archive/2014/04/02/cortana-yes-and-many-many-other-great-features-coming-in-windows-phone-8-1.aspx">Windows Phone 8.1</a> is official. It comes with a notification shade, which looks exactly like the one in Android. It has an Apple Siri and Google Now clone called Cortana. It also has a swipe enabled keyboard, and you can finally set a background photo. <a href="http://blogs.windows.com/windows/b/windowsexperience/archive/2014/04/02/windows-8-1-update-important-refinements-to-the-windows-experience.aspx">Windows 8.1 Update 1</a> is official too. It'll make Windows more keyboard friendly when it ships on April 8th. Microsoft also demoed "the next version of Windows", and I'm happy to report the start bar is back. On top of that, the company showed off a preview of touch enabled Office, though they failed to provide a ship date. But the biggest announcement, bar none, is that Windows Phone is now free for OEMs, as is Windows 8.1, but only on tablets with a 9.0 inch or smaller screen.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidcentral.com/moto-g-forte-launching-mexico-get-your-moto-g-tough-case-soon">15</a> &nbsp;Motorola: The Moto G Forte is official. It's not a Moto G variant, as people originally believed, it's just a Moto G with a bundled Grip Shell case.</p><p><a href="https://nest.com/blog/2014/04/02/the-uk-just-got-a-little-more-comfy/">16</a> &nbsp;Nest: Google's latest acquisition is now selling their wares in the UK for £180.</p><p><a href="http://conversations.nokia.com/2014/04/02/lumia-930-lumia-630-lumia-635/">17</a> &nbsp;Nokia: They announced three Windows Phone 8.1 handsets during Microsoft's three hour keynote yesterday. The Lumia 930, Lumia 635, and Lumia 630. The Lumia 930 is the international version of the Verizon Wireless Lumia Icon. That means 5.0 inch 1080p display, top of the line everything, 20 megapixel camera. It ships in June for $599 before tax. The Lumia 630 comes in two versions: single SIM ($159) and dual SIM ($169). It has a 4.5 inch 854 x 480 pixel screen, quad core processor, 512 MB of RAM, and a 5 MP camera. The Lumia 635 ($189) is a Lumia 630, but with 4G LTE. Both the Lumia 630 and 635 ship in May.</p><p><a href="http://www.sammobile.com/2014/04/02/exclusive-galaxy-s5-mini-sm-g800-specs-leaked/">18</a> &nbsp;Samsung: According to SamMobile, who is almost never wrong, the Galaxy S5 Mini will have a 4.5 inch 720p display, 1.5 GB of RAM, and an 8 megapixel camera. No pics. No price. No availability information.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26849941">19</a> &nbsp;Turkey: The country's highest court has ruled the ban on Twitter is illegal. Not that it matters, the government does whatever they want.</p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/support/status/451399393850052610">20</a> &nbsp;Twitter: They now support emoji.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26854708">21</a> &nbsp;UK: "Vodafone has said it will create 1,400 jobs by opening 150 new shops in 2014."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/blogs-news-from-elsewhere-26853689">22</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: There's an app called "Boycott the Occupiers" that's been installed by over 50,000 Ukrainians. It lets users scan products to determine whether or not they were made in Russia.</p><p><a href="http://www.anandtech.com/show/7919/usbif-publishes-first-typec-connector-renderings">23</a> &nbsp;USB: The first images (technically renders) of USB's answer to Apple's Lightning connector are out. Note that you shouldn't expect to see devices with this connector until Q4 2014 at the earliest.</p><p><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/apr/01/wearables-consumers-abandoning-devices-galaxy-gear">24</a> &nbsp;Wearables: According to research from Endeavour Partners, "one-third of American consumers who have owned a wearable product stopped using it within six months" and "half of U.S. consumers who have owned a modern activity tracker no longer use it". Their sample size was "thousands" of 18+ year old Americans, and they collected their data in September 2013.</p><p><a href="http://www.engadget.com/2014/04/02/xiaomi-pressy-clone/">25</a> &nbsp;Xiaomi: They're going to sell an accessory you can plug into your device's headphone jack, giving your phone or tablet another physical button. No price. No date.</p><p><a href="http://yahoo.tumblr.com/post/81529518520/status-update-encryption-at-yahoo">26</a> &nbsp;Yahoo!: They published a blog post saying everything that touches their servers is now encrypted. "Our broader mission is to not only make Yahoo! secure, but improve the security of the overall web ecosystem."</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26863565">27</a> &nbsp;Australia: Six people have died because of shark attacks during the past three years, which has prompted the government to "order a cull of sharks". No word as to how many sharks they want to kill.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26863385">28</a> &nbsp;China: In a bid to boost the Chinese economy, the government has announced that there will be an "18% increase in the total number of railway lines being built compared to last year." Said increase in railroad infrastructure will cost $24.6 billion.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26857743">29</a> &nbsp;Europe: "Electric and hybrid cars will have to generate noise to make them safer for pedestrians, especially the visually impaired, the European Parliament says." Assuming the law gets passed, all 2019 model hybrids and electrics sold in Europe must generate noise. And all electric and hybrid cars, regardless of age, must make a noise by 2021.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26826202">30</a> &nbsp;Europe: "The biggest civil Earth-observation program ever conceived begins its roll-out on Thursday with the launch of a radar satellite from French Guiana." The Copernicus project is essentially a complex weather monitoring system consisting of six satellites. Total price: $10.3 billion.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26851906">31</a> &nbsp;Germany: Starting in 2015, Germany might have their first ever minimum wage law: 8.50 Euros ($11.70) per hour. Angela Merkel approved the proposal, but it still has to go through parliament and the upper house. A decision isn't expected until September.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26627408">32</a> &nbsp;Hong Kong: The average person in Hong Kong consumes 70 kilograms of fish every year, 10 times as much as the average American. The BBC has profiled Oceanethix, a local fish farm that's unique because they operate on the 15th floor of a tall building. They own 11 tanks and sell two tons of fish every week.</p><p><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/europe/ireland/10739277/Device-exploded-in-bombers-face-after-he-forgot-about-clocks-changing.html">33</a> &nbsp;Ireland: Some idiot forgot to push the time on his watch up an hour. He used said watch to program a bomb. Said bomb blew up in his face.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26771703">34</a> &nbsp;Israel: Researchers have discovered oxytocin, often called "the love hormone", makes people lie. The study is questionable, however, and without knowing the sample size, it's nearly impossible for me to call this conclusive.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/entertainment-arts-26848889">35</a> &nbsp;Italy: Two paintings were stolen from London in 1970 by three men who then left the art on a train. The train company sold the paintings at a lost property auction in 1975 for $32. The son of the man that bought the paintings noticed that one of them might be a Gauguin. He was right. Police recovered the paintings, which are estimated to cost $14.6 million total.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26866989">36</a> &nbsp;Russia: They're pissed that NATO is building up their military presence in Eastern Europe. Then again, who wouldn't be upset with 10 American F-15 fighter jets ready to attack?</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-26841410">37</a> &nbsp;Saudi Arabia: Archaeologists have found a 2.25 meter (7.4 foot) long elephant tusk in the middle of the desert. They say it's 325,000 years old and is proof positive that the desert was once a "lush and fertile plain". They also say the tusk would have belonged to a six ton elephant, compared to today's three ton elephants.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-26853788">38</a> &nbsp;South Africa: "South Africa's government will distribute colored and flavored condoms among students to end 'condom fatigue', the health minister has said." Normal condoms are apparently not "cool enough", so much so that condom use is dropping and the number of people contracting HIV is rising.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-africa-26859087">39</a> &nbsp;Uganda: "Private clinics in Uganda's capital, Kampala, are selling fake HIV negative certificates to help people get jobs." How much is one of these certificates? $20.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26647738">40</a> &nbsp;UK: A small trial (28 people), performed by the Oxford Health Foundation, has revealed that the "party drug" Ketamine can cure depression, even in people who have been suffering for decades.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26860982">41</a> &nbsp;USA: "An exchange student fell to his death after ingesting marijuana in Colorado - the first death linked to the drug since it was legalized in the U.S. state." Levy Thamba was 19 years old and from The Republic of Congo.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26850631">42</a> &nbsp;USA: "Fire-fighting robots designed to withstand intense heat are to be tested by the US Navy this summer." Said robots are five feet tall (1.5 meters) and were built by several universities working together.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26851336">43</a> &nbsp;USA: 110 million years ago, two dinosaurs were running in a riverbed in Texas. 70 years ago, that 45 meter riverbed was dug up, split into chunks, and photographed. This week, that research was finally fed into a computer, which then spit out a 3D map.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26855649">44</a> &nbsp;USA: The death toll from the Washington mudslide now stands at 29, with 20 people still missing.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26855657">45</a> &nbsp;USA: The U.S. Supreme Court has abolished limits on political contributions. There used to be a rule that said individuals can't donate more than $123,200. That's no longer the case. There is, however, still a limit on how much one person can donate to one particular candidate: $2,600.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26863033">46</a> &nbsp;USA: There's been another shooting at Fort Hood. Four people are confirmed dead. The gunman is one of those four people. While not as bad as the 2009 shooting that left 13 people dead, neither of these incidents should have occurred in the first place.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26841988">47</a> &nbsp;USA: Two decades ago, researchers at the University of Minnesota performed cognitive tests on 3,000 people with an average age of 25 years old. Said 3,000 people have now been retested, and it turns out those who regularly engaged in cardiovascular exercise performed "better at tests of memory and thinking skills".</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">48</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 02: 36 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 06:52:55 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/2/april-02-36-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:533bb3cee4b0c47740cdf06c</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://newsblur.com/">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: About one year ago, Google announced they were going to kill Google Reader. Now if you don't know what RSS is, then I can't adequately explain to you why that day was tragic. I immediately spent the next few weeks and months testing every RSS reader under the sun to find a suitable replacement, and I'm proud to say that I have: NewsBlur. Without NewsBlur, this website, and my enjoyment of the internet, would simply not be be possible.</p><p><a href="https://www.abiresearch.com/press/chromebook-shipments-reach-21-million-for-2013-and">02</a> &nbsp;ABI Research: These analysts say "an estimated 2.1 million Chromebooks shipped in 2013 with nearly 89% of total shipments reaching North America." Average selling price: $338. They predict 11 million Chromebooks will ship in 2019, but I wouldn't take a prediction that's five years out very seriously.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2014/04/01/amazon-will-now-allow-returns-using-lockers/">03</a> &nbsp;Amazon: You can now use their lockers (how many of them exist?) to return unwanted items.</p><p><a href="http://asia.nikkei.com/Business/Deals/Apple-looking-to-buy-Japanese-chipmaker">04</a> &nbsp;Apple: Rumor has it that "Apple is in talks with Japan's Renesas Electronics to take over a unit that designs chips for smartphone displays." Said unit costs $479 million and has 240 employees.</p><p><a href="http://adage.com/article/digital/apple-expands-iad-developers-adds-video-capabilities/292412/">05</a> &nbsp;Apple: You can now buy ads on iAd using just your Apple ID. Before you were required to be registered as an app developer.</p><p><a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/blackberry-breaks-ties-with-t-mobile-after-spat/">06</a> &nbsp;BlackBerry: T-Mobile USA will stop selling BlackBerry products effective April 25th.</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/01/bbm-stickers/">07</a> &nbsp;BlackBerry: Their chat app has been updated. It now supports stickers, sharing images with groups, and 16 megabyte file attachments. Unfortunately, only 85 million people use BBM. Anything below 100 million in the messaging space is considered niche.</p><p><a href="http://blog.flurry.com/bid/109749/Apps-Solidify-Leadership-Six-Years-into-the-Mobile-Revolution">08</a> &nbsp;Flurry Analytics: There are a ton of data points in Flurry's latest blog post, but here are the two that stand out: 86% of the time people spend on their phones is spent using apps, the rest is spent in the web browser. And the average time an American spends using a phone every day has gone up four minutes compared to last year, it's now 2 hours and 42 minutes.</p><p><a href="http://www.engadget.com/2014/04/01/google-new-android-camera-app/">09</a> &nbsp;Google: According to one of Engadget's trusted sources, Google will launch a completely overhauled camera app soon that will be able to run on any Android device (as opposed to just Nexus hardware) running 4.4 KitKat and above. Said camera app will also let developers write their own extensions, similar to how Windows Phone uses the "Lens" concept.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/04/01/android-platform-distribution-numbers-updated-kitkat-more-than-doubles-to-5-3-gingerbread-continues-its-slow-decline/">10</a> &nbsp;Google: The latest Android platform figures are out. Key highlights: 5.3% of devices that have access to the Play Store are running the latest version of Android. 17.8% are still on Android 2.3 Gingerbread, which launched in December 2010.</p><p><a href="http://www.nfcworld.com/2014/04/01/328568/intel-inside-secure-agree-us19-2m-nfc-technology-deal/">11</a> &nbsp;Intel: They just dropped $19.2 million on Inside Secure's next generation NFC modem. No word as to when NFC will actually become useful.</p><p><a href="http://www.slashgear.com/lenovo-a-series-tablet-revamp-brings-a7-30-a7-50-a8-and-a10-01323195/">12</a> &nbsp;Lenovo: They announced four new tablets, two with 7.0 inch screens, one with an 8.0 screen, and finally a 10.0 incher. They'll all hit the UK, and presumably Europe, this quarter. The key selling point of all of them is that they have front firing speakers.</p><p><a href="http://linecorp.com/en/press/2014/0402714">13</a> &nbsp;LINE: My favorite chat app now has 400 million users.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26833863">14</a> &nbsp;LinkedIn: They're trying to get a Chrome extension called "Sell Hack" off the internet. What does it do? Show you the hidden email addresses of LinkedIn users.</p><p><a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/mozilla-ceo-gay-marriage-firestorm-could-hurt-firefox-cause-q-a/">15</a> &nbsp;Mozilla: CNET sat down with Mozilla's new CEO and talked about the gay marriage issue at length. If you care about how Brendan Eich spends his money, then this is for you. Personally, I just want to see Firefox become a competitive product again, because right now it's a joke.</p><p><a href="http://www.samsungmobilepress.com/2014/04/01/Samsung-Unveils-New-Galaxy-Tab4-Series-1">16</a> &nbsp;Samsung: They announced three new tablets, each called the Galaxy Tab4. One has a 7.0 inch screen, another has an 8.0 inch screen, and the last has a 10.1 inch screen. All three have the same specs: 1.2 GHz quad core processor, 1280 x 800 pixel screen, Android 4.4 KitKat, and a 3 megapixel camera. No prices, and they launch this quarter.</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/01/spotify-poaches-googler-alexander-kubaneishvili-to-head-russia-q3-launch-planned/">17</a> &nbsp;Spotify: Alexander Kubaneishvili is leaving Google after 2.5 years with the company to help Spotify launch in Russia in H2 2014. Spotify also has plans to launch in Brazil at roughly the same time.</p><p><a href="http://www.wired.co.uk/news/archive/2014-04/02/new-spotify">18</a> &nbsp;Spotify: They redesigned all their apps. Said apps launch today.</p><p><a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/finance/newsbysector/mediatechnologyandtelecoms/telecoms/10736245/Three-rules-out-O2-UK-acquisition.html">19</a> &nbsp;UK: The CEO of Three UK told The Telegraph that he's not interested in merging or buying O2 UK. He was asked this because Three Ireland purchased O2 Ireland.</p><p><a href="http://gigaom.com/2014/04/01/opensignals-crowdsourced-testing-ranks-t-mobiles-lte-the-fastest-in-the-u-s/">20</a> &nbsp;USA: T-Mobile has the fastest 4G LTE network in the USA according to tests conducted by OpenSignal. That's the headline everyone is more or less writing. The thing is, that same research showed a T-Mobile device is connected to 4G LTE just 61.1% of the time it's on, versus 70.6% for AT&amp;T, and a massive 83.2% for Verizon.</p><p><a href="http://www.tcpalm.com/news/2014/mar/31/house-bill-could-mean-30-year-sentence-texting-whi/">21</a> &nbsp;USA: The state of Florida has proposed legislation (that will probably not pass) which will put people caught texting and driving in jail for 30 years.</p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/WhatsApp/statuses/451198381856014337">22</a> &nbsp;WhatsApp: They've announced a new daily record: "20B messages sent (inbound) and 44B messages received (outbound) by our users = 64B messages handled in just 24 hours."</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26847200">23</a> &nbsp;Australia: Philip Morris will stop making cigarettes in Australia. 180 people will become unemployed. Why? Because in 2012, the government passed plain packaging laws, which made all cigarette packs look the same, regardless of vendor.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-england-leicestershire-26835200">24</a> &nbsp;Gambia: This 90 second video features Tom Williams from the Legs for Africa project showing off his van full of 500 prosthetic legs that will be shipped from the UK to Gambia. It's not every day you see a van filled to the brim with fake legs. <a href="http://youtu.be/mKFKRuWwgjg">Magic legs</a>.</p><p><a href="http://ibnlive.in.com/news/germany-bans-managers-from-calling-or-emailing-staff-after-work-hours/461070-79.html">25</a> &nbsp;Germany: "Germany's labor ministry has banned managers from calling or emailing staff out of hours except in emergencies." Work life balance, it's not just a theory, it's the law.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26830492">26</a> &nbsp;Japan: "The first group of Fukushima evacuees have returned to their homes, three years after the disaster at the nuclear power plant." Roughly 350 people have been allowed to return; 80,000 people in total were evacuated.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26836930">27</a> &nbsp;Japan: The scientist that earlier this year said she discovered how to turn red blood cells into stem cells has been found guilty of misconduct. "The Riken Centre panel said Dr Haruko Obokata fabricated her work in an intentionally misleading fashion."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26835228">28</a> &nbsp;North Korea: Here are two photos of a North Korean drone that landed in South Korea. Said drone was used to photograph military installations and the presidential compound.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-scotland-edinburgh-east-fife-26834110">29</a> &nbsp;Scotland: Keane Wallis-Bennett, age 12, died because one of the walls in her school collapsed. Said school was built in 1959. Devon Blyth, age 13, said she complained about that wall being "wobbly" for months, but the teachers ignored her.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-26835441">30</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: There are people in the Ukraine spending their free time trying to put together the documents that the government shredded before they lost control. They have a website called "Yanukovych Leaks". So far they've found nothing.</p><p><a href="http://www.mediabistro.com/tvnewser/60-minutes-apologizes-for-audio-editing-in-tesla-report_b219821">31</a> &nbsp;USA: 60 minutes, which used to be considered the beacon of American journalism, has apologized for adding pre-recorded engine noise to Sunday's episode about Tesla and their electric cars.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26823842">32</a> &nbsp;USA: Benito Flores, age 43, remains missing a day after he was swept out to sea during an ocean baptism.</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/4/1/5570170/darpa-opens-biotech-office-to-utilize-biology-for-national-defense">33</a> &nbsp;USA: DARPA has launched a new Biological Technologies Office that will work on things such as "internet-enabled prosthetics, memory restoration, and body suits that enable soldiers to carry lots of weight." DARPA invented the internet, so there's a reason to be excited about this.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26844494">34</a> &nbsp;USA: General Motors CEO Mary Barra sat in front of a U.S. congressional committee yesterday and said sorry several thousand times. She also admitted that GM employees knew about the ignition switch defect <strong>10 years ago</strong>, but did nothing.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26830559">35</a> &nbsp;USA: The FBI is now investigating several unnamed high-speed trading firms, saying they might be acting on inside information. If you ask me, the whole practice of high-speed trading, letting computers automatically buy and sell stocks, needs to be banned.</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">36</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>April 01: 41 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 07:34:18 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/4/1/april-01-41-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:533a6c00e4b05968caf9033a</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://newsblur.com">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: About one year ago, Google announced they were going to kill Google Reader. Now if you don't know what RSS is, then I can't adequately explain to you why that day was tragic. I immediately spent the next few weeks and months testing every RSS reader under the sun to find a suitable replacement, and I'm proud to say that I have: NewsBlur. Without NewsBlur, this website, and my enjoyment of the internet, would simply not be be possible.</p><p><a href="http://www.sfgate.com/business/article/Airbnb-to-collect-hotel-taxes-for-San-Francisco-5365352.php">02</a> &nbsp;Airbnb: Starting this summer, they'll be paying San Francisco's 14% hotel tax.</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/03/31/what-to-expect-when-you-are-expecting-yet-another-apple-samsung-trial/">03</a> &nbsp;Apple and Samsung: Yes, the two are in court again. No, I'm not going to provide daily coverage of the trial. But I will say this, Re/code has published the best article I've seen about the case. Well worth a read if you want to understand what's at stake, which products are contested, and which patents are being discussed.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/01/us-apple-iphone-display-idUSBREA3008020140401?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">04</a> &nbsp;Apple: Reuters says "Apple suppliers will begin mass producing displays as early as May for the next iPhone, expected to be launched this autumn, with a 4.7-inch screen likely to be produced first while a 5.5-inch version could be delayed, supply chain sources said."</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/3/31/5566936/purported-iphone-6-pictures-said-to-come-from-foxconn">05</a> &nbsp;Apple: These are allegedly the first images of the iPhone 6. Personally, I think the photos are BS, but enough people are talking about them that I feel I should let you make up your own mind.</p><p><a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2014/04/01iPad-Air-iPad-mini-with-LTE-Performance-Available-in-China-Today.html">06</a> &nbsp;Apple: They've officially announced TD-LTE variants of the iPad Air and iPad Mini. Translation: iPads that work with Chinese 4G LTE.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-26723618">07</a> &nbsp;Canada: One year ago this month, Rehtaeh Parsons, age 17, killed herself because of online bullying. The outrage over her suicide made the Cyber Safety Act possible, which allows minors to seek police protection from bullies, bring bullies to court, and hold the parents of bullies responsible for their child's actions.</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/article_email/SB10001424052702303978304579471413209348736-lMyQjAxMTA0MDIwOTEyNDkyWj">08</a> &nbsp;Google: The WSJ says YouTube is offering big ad buyers "audience guarantees", which is a fancy way of saying YouTube will now play your company's ad until a certain number of people have watched it.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/04/01/us-hp-lawsuit-settlement-idUSBREA3008H20140401?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">09</a> &nbsp;HP: $57 million. That's how much money HP will have to hand over to settle a shareholder lawsuit over that silly time in the company's history when Apotheker said he wanted to get out of the PC business.</p><p><a href="http://www.3g.co.uk/PR/March2014/htc-one-m8-mini-confirmed.html">10</a> &nbsp;HTC: Rumor has it that HTC will launch a mini version of their flagship phone, the One M8, in May. Said phone will use the same premium materials, but it'll have a 4.5 inch screen, likely with a resolution of 720p instead of 1080p. No pics. No price.</p><p><a href="http://www.fiercewireless.com/story/huawei-ships-52m-smartphones-2013-again-misses-its-own-target/2014-03-31?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss">11</a> &nbsp;Huawei: They've announced that they shipped 52 million smartphones in 2013, short of their goal of 60 million.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/03/31/us-intel-cloudera-idUSBREA2U0ME20140331?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">12</a> &nbsp;Intel: They dropped $740 million to buy 18% of Cloudera, a "Big Data" company.</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/31/jawbone-snaps-up-playground-fm/">13</a> &nbsp;Jawbone: They bought Playground.fm. Financial figures weren't mentioned. Playground.fm makes an iOS app that mines your Facebook and Spotify data to build what they call "human-powered radio".</p><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-chops-azure-prices-to-match-amazons-latest-reductions-7000027898/">14</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: Google slashed the price of their cloud services last week. Amazon reacted less than 24 hours later. Now it's Microsoft's turn.</p><p><a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/news/misc/2014/mar14/03-31corpemail.aspx">15</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: Here is Satya Nadella's email announcing that Phil Spencer will take over XBOX and Stephen Elop will take over Microsoft Devices.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidcentral.com/motorola-updates-its-boot-animation-now-powered-android">16</a> &nbsp;Motorola: They've updated the Moto X to include the newly mandated "Powered by Android" branding on the boot screen.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26830383">17</a> &nbsp;OKCupid: The incredibly popular online dating site OKCupid is throwing up a warning message to users accessing the site via Firefox. Why? Because Mozilla's new CEO, Brian Eich, once donated money to a political campaign seeking to ban gay marriage in California.</p><p><a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/2138080/oracle-overtakes-ibm-as-secondlargest-software-vendor-gartner-says.html">18</a> &nbsp;Oracle: They're now bigger than IBM, according to the analysts at Gartner. Microsoft is King of the Hill, with $65.7 billion in software revenue in 2013. Oracle did $29.6 billion. IBM did $29.1 billion. And SAP did $18.5 billion.</p><p><a href="https://blog.getpebble.com/2014/03/31/keep-fit-and-productive-with-pebble-at-target/">19</a> &nbsp;Pebble: Target is now selling the Pebble smartwatch in their brick and mortar stores.</p><p><a href="http://www.displaymate.com/Galaxy_S5_ShootOut_1.htm">20</a> &nbsp;Samsung: According to the experts at DisplayMate, who I trust, despite the fact their website is hideous, the Samsung Galaxy S5 has "the best performing smartphone display that we have ever tested."</p><p><a href="http://corner.squareup.com/2014/03/square-market-accepts-bitcoin.html">21</a> &nbsp;Square: "Starting today, buyers can purchase goods and services on Square Market with Bitcoin." Coinbase will be their Bitcoin broker.</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/31/twitter-poaches-googler-dauman-commerce/">22</a> &nbsp;Twitter: The son of Viacom's CEO has left Google after 6.5 years with the company to become "Director of Commerce Partnerships" at Twitter.</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/31/twitter-buys-frances-mesagraph-to-ramp-up-social-tv-work-in-euroupe/">23</a> &nbsp;Twitter: They bought two companies, Mesagraph (France) and SecondSync (UK), both of which will be used to better integrate Twitter into the television watching experience. Twitter will also "expanded their partnership with Kantar" to cover "the Nordics, Russia, parts of Africa and southeast Asia".</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26818745">24</a> &nbsp;UK: Mohammed Khalid Jamil, age 34, ran a scam where he hired call center employees in India to call people using Windows machines, pose as Microsoft employees, tell them there was something wrong with their computer, and then charge them money to install free antivirus software. He now has to pay $41,000 in damages.</p><p><a href="http://gigaom.com/2014/03/31/open-up-your-routers-fcc-boosts-spectrum-available-to-wi-fi-by-15-percent/">25</a> &nbsp;USA: The FCC has agreed to open up 100 MHz of spectrum in the 5 GHz band to improve WiFi performance.</p><p><a href="http://www.phonescoop.com/articles/article.php?a=13850">26</a> &nbsp;USA: The FCC will auction off 65 MHz worth of spectrum in the AWS-3 band (1695-1710MHz, 1755-1780MHz, and 2155-2180MHz) at some point in the future to wireless operators. The exact date hasn't been decided yet.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-england-london-26821045">27</a> &nbsp;USA: This four minute video shows what happens when police officers in Rialto, California are forced to wear video cameras that record their every interaction with the public. Turns out use of force drops by 60% and complaints against officers drops by 80%.</p><p><a href="http://www.fiercewireless.com/europe/story/vodafone-brings-m-pesa-mobile-payment-service-europe/2014-03-31?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss">28</a> &nbsp;Vodafone: The wildly successful M-Pesa mobile payments service has come to Europe. Romania to be specific.</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/article_email/SB10001424052702304157204579473780432974344-lMyQjAxMTA0MDMwMTEzNDEyWj">29</a> &nbsp;Yahoo!: Rumor has it they're going to drop $300 million on News Distribution Network. According to the WSJ, NDN is "a video syndication service that supplies newspapers and other Web publishers with clips about news, sports, politics and other topics." NDN has denied that talks are taking place.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/blogs-trending-26820786">30</a> &nbsp;Brazil: 65% of 3,810 Brazilians surveyed by "a major Brazilian research institute" say a woman deserves to be attacked for wearing clothes that show off her body.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26828313">31</a> &nbsp;China: This 74 second video shows off "the world's largest aquarium", which has just opened in China's Guangdong province.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26822280">32</a> &nbsp;Germany: The Lufthansa strike, what are the numbers? Three day strike (April 02 to April 04). 3,800 flights canceled. 425,000 passengers affected.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26829120">33</a> &nbsp;Greece: Protesting in central Athens has been banned due to security reasons. EU finance ministers will be meeting in the Greek capital to sign off on yet another $11 billion loan. The country has successfully eliminated its deficit, but unemployment still stands at 27%.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26830505">34</a> &nbsp;Japan: Roughly 3,600 minke whales have been killed by the Japanese in Antarctica&nbsp;since 2005 under the guise of "scientific research". The United Nations International Court of Justice has ruled that Japan must stop conducting their "research" immediately.</p><p><a href="http://www.wired.co.uk/news/archive/2014-03/26/3d-printed-skull">35</a> &nbsp;Netherlands: An unnamed 22 year old woman had the top of her skull replaced at the University Medical Center of Utrecht. The procedure lasted 23 hours and is said to be the "first instance of a successful 3D printed cranium". Warning: The header image of this article is graphic.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26818377">36</a> &nbsp;UK: Researchers from the University College London, tracking the dietary habits of 65,226 people over seven years, have discovered that eating seven portions of fruits or vegetables a day can cut your "risk of death" by 42%. Drop the portion count to five and the cut to your risk of death falls to 36%. Note that a portion is considered 80 grams (3 ounces), so seven portions is 560 grams (1.3 pounds).</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26818747">37</a> &nbsp;UK: The UK now has their own Cyber Defense task force. The team is called CERT (Computer Emergency Response Team), they'll be based out of London, and it'll be made up of 55 people. The government says $1.4 billion has been allocated to cyber defense, but they don't say how much was actually spent on CERT.</p><p><a href="http://stream.wsj.com/story/latest-headlines/SS-2-63399/SS-2-496209/">38</a> &nbsp;USA: Another day, another recall by General Motors. This new recall, over electronic power steering issues, is for 1.5 million cars, bringing the total number of cars recalled this year to 6.3 million. The situation is so bad that GM Chief Executive Mary Barra has been summoned by the government to explain what the hell is going on.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26821080">39</a> &nbsp;USA: Scientists at Duke University have created artificial muscles that can repair themselves. "It's the first time engineered muscle has been created that contracts as strongly as native neonatal [newborn] skeletal muscle." Note that they've done work on mice. Trials on humans aren't even on a timeline yet.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-26815745">40</a> &nbsp;Venezuela: The death toll from the protests now stands at 39.</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">41</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>March 31: 45 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 09:39:27 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/3/31/march-31-45-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:533937d2e4b012d5a0b4db02</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://newsblur.com">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: About one year ago, Google announced they were going to kill Google Reader. Now if you don't know what RSS is, then I can't adequately explain to you why that day was tragic. I immediately spent the next few weeks and months testing every RSS reader under the sun to find a suitable replacement, and I'm proud to say that I have: NewsBlur. Without NewsBlur, this website, and my enjoyment of the internet, would simply not be be possible.</p><p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-03-31/alibaba-unit-to-acquire-intime-retail-shares-convertible-bond.html">02</a> &nbsp;Alibaba: China's version of Amazon just bought a 10% stake in a company that operates shopping malls for $692 million.</p><p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2014-03-26/aol-goes-after-32-billion-market-with-automated-web-ad-service.html">03</a> &nbsp;AOL: The ISP turned content company is now pivoting, again, to become an advertising company. Oddly enough, when Google, an ad company, dabbles in content, we all scream in opposition, yet no one cares when it happens the other way around.</p><p><a href="http://www.macrumors.com/2014/03/28/swiss-watchmakers-iwatch/">04</a> &nbsp;Apple: Jean-Claude Biver, President of Watches and Jewelry at LVMH (Louis Vuitton Moët Hennessy), has told the Financial Times that Apple has been trying to steal some of his employees. He "saw the emails personally".</p><p><a href="http://venturebeat.com/2014/03/27/mobile-app-monetization-freemium-is-king-but-in-app-ads-are-growing-fast/">05</a> &nbsp;Apps: App Annie and IDC have published a report on app monetization models. VentureBeat has the key highlights. Most eye opening data point: Less than 5% of developers report that more than 30% of their users have made in-app purchases, yet "freemium" games are how most companies make money.</p><p><a href="http://mobilesyrup.com/2014/03/29/blackberry-ceo-confirms-bold-9900-re-release-three-new-high-end-smartphones/">06</a> &nbsp;BlackBerry: The CEO has come up with a brilliant plan to save the company: Resume manufacturing of a three year old phone.</p><p><a href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140328PD213.html">07</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: TSMC hasn't even launched their 20 nanometer chips yet, but apparently they're gearing up to enter volume production of 16 nanometer chips in early 2015.</p><p><a href="https://readmill.com/epilogue">08</a> &nbsp;Dropbox: It's confirmed. Dropbox bought Readmill. Price unknown. Readmill will be shutting down in July. What's a cloud storage company going to do with an eBook reader app? "Our expertise in reading, collaboration, and syncing across devices" will find a new home.</p><p><a href="http://www.phonescoop.com/articles/article.php?a=13844">09</a> &nbsp;Facebook: Facebook Messenger for iOS now finally supports group chat.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/03/29/rumor-google-now-will-help-you-remember-pay-your-bills-apk-teardown/">10</a> &nbsp;Google: Android Police have found strings in the latest version of Google Now which suggest Google may soon launch a "remind me to pay my bills" feature. What's unknown is how exactly Google will mine your bills to generate said notifications.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/03/28/the-rumors-are-true-new-and-updated-android-devices-now-required-to-have-powered-by-android-bootup-logo-to-get-gms-certification/">11</a> &nbsp;Google: Handset makers that want access to the "blessed" version of Android, meaning Android with all of Google's services and access to the Play Store, will now be required to include the text "Powered by Android" on a phone's boot screen.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/03/28/google-updates-play-store-developer-program-policies-to-crack-down-on-deceptive-ads/">12</a> &nbsp;Google: They've updated the guidelines that developers must follow to get their apps into the Play Store. Quick summary: Stop being so damn sleazy.</p><p><a href="http://youtu.be/sxAVxgzX7Tc">13</a> &nbsp;HTC: The company's new flagship phone has two rear facing cameras, giving it the ability to let users refocus images after they were taken. How well does it stand up to Nokia's "ReFocus" Windows Phone app, which does the same thing, but via software? This entertaining five minute video answers that question. Spoiler: Nokia wins.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/03/28/us-media-cybercrime-idUSBREA2R0EU20140328">14</a> &nbsp;Journalism: "Twenty-one of the world's top-25 news organizations have been the target of likely state-sponsored hacking attacks, according to research by two Google security engineers."</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/03/28/us-microsoft-privacy-idUSBREA2R1XH20140328?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">15</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: After getting into hot water for reading a Hotmail user's email, Microsoft has said they will not do that again. Instead, they will consult with law enforcement officials the next time they suspect a crime has been committed.</p><p><a href="http://thenextweb.com/microsoft/2014/03/28/microsoft-pulls-fake-google-apps-windows-phone-store-doesnt-fix-larger-approval-process-problem/?utm_source=social&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=profeed&amp;utm_reader=feedly">16</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: They pulled a bunch of paid apps from the Windows Phone Store that were pretending to be official Google apps. The question here is how the hell were they approved in the first place?</p><p><a href="http://www.kantarworldpanel.com/global/News/Motorola-back-in-the-game-with-Moto-G-success">17</a> &nbsp;Motorola: According to the analysts at Kantar Worldpanel ComTech, thanks to the Moto G, Motorola's market share in the UK went from practically 0% to 6% in less than half a year.</p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/evleaksES/status/449683569514790912">18</a> &nbsp;Motorola: There will be a ruggedized version of the Moto G called the "Moto G Forte". No word on price or ship date, and this picture isn't exactly stellar, but the source (@evleaks) is solid.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2014/03/28/three-mozilla-board-members-resign-over-choice-of-new-ceo/">19</a> &nbsp;Mozilla: Half of the company's board members (three people) have resigned because the new CEO donated money to a political campaign to have gay marriage banned in California.</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702304688104579466952269048242?mg=reno64-wsj&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fonline.wsj.com%2Farticle%2FSB10001424052702304688104579466952269048242.html">20</a> &nbsp;Nokia: The government of India has ordered a "special" audit of Nokia's books, a process that the WSJ says could take six months to complete. Both Microsoft and Nokia say this audit will not affect the planned acquisition, but you never know.</p><p><a href="http://www.oculusvr.com/blog/introducing-michael-abrash-oculus-chief-scientist/">21</a> &nbsp;Oculus: Michael Abrash, Valve's Virtual Reality Expert, has left to join Oculus. Key quote from his "Hello World" blog post: "We're on the cusp of what I think is not The Next Big Platform, but rather simply The Final Platform – the platform to end all platforms – and the path here has been so improbable that I can only shake my head."</p><p><a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/business/in-new-case-supreme-court-revisits-the-question-of-software-patents/2014/03/28/a3da1c52-ad3a-11e3-9627-c65021d6d572_story.html">22</a> &nbsp;Patents: "On Monday, for the first time since 1981, the Supreme Court will hear arguments on whether software — or more precisely, computer-implemented inventions — can continue to be patented."</p><p><a href="http://blog.gsmarena.com/samsung-galaxy-s5-features-a-baby-monitor/">23</a> &nbsp;Samsung: The Galaxy S5 has a "baby crying detector". Put the phone next to your baby, and if it cries, it'll make your Galaxy Gear vibrate.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2014/03/28/judge-clears-way-for-trial-in-silicon-valley-wage-case/">24</a> &nbsp;USA: On May 27th of this year, a trial will kick off to determine whether or not America's biggest tech companies colluded to keep tech workers' wages artificially low.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/03/28/usa-spectrum-channelsharing-idUSL1N0MO1YG20140328">25</a> &nbsp;USA: Two Los Angeles television stations have successfully tested sharing one channel worth of spectrum. TV stations are currently being asked to voluntarily give up some of their spectrum, which will then be sold at auction in 2015 to wireless operators. The stations that agree to this will of course receive financial compensation.</p><p><a href="http://www.gizchina.com/2014/03/26/xiaomi-redmi-note-sells-out-in-34-minutes/">26</a> &nbsp;Xiaomi: It took them 34 minutes to sell 100,000 units of their new phablet.</p><p><a href="http://www.techinasia.com/xiaomi-sell-100-million-phones-2015-tall-task-equal-lenovo/">27</a> &nbsp;Xiaomi: The company's CEO says he wants to sell 100 million phones in 2015. Lenovo, the new owners of Motorola, have the exact same goal.</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/03/28/ready-for-marissas-closeup-yahoo-is-considering-creating-its-own-youtube-and-poaching-youtube-stars/">28</a> &nbsp;Yahoo!: Re/code is saying Yahoo! wants to launch a YouTube competitor and that the company is actively courting "YouTube stars". If everything goes to plan, we should see Yahoo!Tube "in the next few months".</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-pacific-26807485">29</a> &nbsp;Australia: In the 1890s, it was believed that spending 30 hours inside the body of dead whale would cure you of rheumatism.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26786142">30</a> &nbsp;Australia: This is a long article about the techniques scientists are using to prevent shark attacks, including designing wetsuits that make surfers look like poisonous fish. But what are your actual chances of getting killed by a shark? "Lightning strikes, bee stings, and car accidents all pose far more of a threat."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26806991">31</a> &nbsp;Canada: Facial hair transplants are now a thing. This 68 second video explains the procedure, which takes 12 hours to perform and ranges in price from $5,000 to $15,000.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/blogs-news-from-elsewhere-26784036">32</a> &nbsp;Italy: In a bid to curb excess spending, the government will be selling roughly 1,500 "non-essential cars". A list of the first 151 cars, which will go on auction on April 16th, has been published. Dozens of BMWs were on the list, as were nine Maseratis.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26815041">33</a> &nbsp;Korea: The North and the South have exchanged fire, not on land, but instead on a "disputed western sea border". No deaths have been reported, and the North is saying they gave the South warning, via fax, that they would be conducting military drills.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26790833">34</a> &nbsp;Space: After 31 months of being "asleep", the European-built Philae lander has been turned back on. Its mission is far from complete, however, with the final goal being to land on a comet in November. Note that this little guy is 655 million kilometers away from our planet.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26809066">35</a> &nbsp;Taiwan: First protestors occupied parliament. Then they occupied the government's headquarters. Now they've taken to the streets, 100,000 of them. Why? Because they want Taiwan to be far less reliant on China.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26770334">36</a> &nbsp;UK: In the 1350s, the black plague killed roughly 60% of the people living in London. Their bodies were dumped in a mass grave, but no one really knew where. Said grave has now been discovered.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26790332">37</a> &nbsp;UK: Scientists have found a genetic mutation that makes people more vulnerable to melanoma, a type of skin cancer. This will help in the early detection process, but the disease is still incredibly complex.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-26769349">38</a> &nbsp;UK: Since April 2012, the UK has issued domestic workers from foreign countries something called "tied visas". Translation: You can come to this country, but you have to work for this one family, no matter how poorly they treat you, so tough luck if they treat you like a slave. Depressing Stat: 74% of domestic workers entering the UK with this new visa have faced psychological abuse versus 28% under the old visa program.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26792004">39</a> &nbsp;USA: General Motors is adding more than 824,000 cars to their most recent recall of 1.6 million cars. They've also stopped selling the "Chevrolet Cruze".</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26807482">40</a> &nbsp;USA: Latest death toll figure from the Washington mudslide: 18. More importantly, the estimated number of people missing has fallen from 90 to 30.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26811528">41</a> &nbsp;Vatican: Two men were arrested for attempting to deposit <strong>$4.1 trillion</strong> worth of fake bonds at the Vatican Bank. No, that's not a typo.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-26793545">42</a> &nbsp;Venezuela: The death toll from the protests now stands at 37.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26724645">43</a> &nbsp;World: One million people a year die from diseases spread by mosquitoes. This BBC article details five of those diseases, and advice on how to stay safe. Spoiler: Constantly spray yourself with insecticides.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26810559">44</a> &nbsp;World: The United Nations has published a report that contains "overwhelming" evidence that climate change is in fact taking place and that there are "severe, pervasive, and irreversible impacts" we should all be worrying about. But will the UN's work push policymakers to act?</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">45</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>March 28: 41 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2014 08:01:45 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/3/28/march-28-41-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:53352c71e4b05b79d04cea2e</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.igloosoftware.com/solutions/sharepoint?ref=TabDump&amp;type=blog&amp;month=march">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: When you hear intranet, you think of clunky tools powered by SharePoint — essentially it's expensive software that doesn't work on your phone. Igloo is different, it's an intranet you'll actually like. It's built with modern, social tools to help you get work done on any device. Igloo made this special report to show you how they excel where SharePoint falls short.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/03/27/us-adidas-retail-idUSBREA2Q15P20140327?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">02</a> &nbsp;Adidas: The German clothing company is installing "Wi-Fi equipped lounges and mobile charging points" in over 30 of their stores in an attempt to get 16-to-24 year olds to hang out there more often.</p><p><a href="http://variety.com/2014/digital/news/amazon-is-plotting-free-tv-and-music-video-streaming-service-but-stocked-with-what-1201149147/">03</a> &nbsp;Amazon: The WSJ said Amazon will launch a free streaming media (video? music?) service. Amazon then issued a statement saying that's total BS.</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/03/27/amazon-launching-video-box-next-week/">04</a> &nbsp;Amazon: They're hosting a press conference on April 2nd, and everyone is expecting some sort of set-top-box. Note that Microsoft is holding a press conference the same day.</p><p><a href="http://www.google.com/hostednews/afp/article/ALeqM5hM9cqLFXTX2rv8WWnz72I-WcThPA?docId=c5c7b9dd-dc9c-4a76-bb55-5ed4a0a5f27f">05</a> &nbsp;Apple: "Russian government officials have swapped their iPads for Samsung tablets to ensure tighter security, the telecoms minister told news agencies on Wednesday."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26766045">06</a> &nbsp;Bitcoin: Several apps have snuck into Google's Play Store that on the surface appear to be some silly game, but they're actually mining Bitcoins in the background. Sadly, phones have atrocious levels of compute power, and worst of all, they run on batteries, making these apps nearly useless.</p><p><a href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140327PD209.html">07</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: "Microsoft has set an internal goal of increasing global Windows tablet shipments, including its Surface, in 2014 to 25 million units, five times the five million units shipped in 2013."</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/27/readmill-acqui-hired/">08</a> &nbsp;Dropbox: This hard drive in the sky company allegedly spent $8 million to buy a Berlin start-up that makes a pretty eBook reader app. Note how I said allegedly.</p><p><a href="http://news.xinhuanet.com/english/business/2014-03/28/c_126325526.htm">09</a> &nbsp;Europe: "European Union Trade Chief Karel De Gucht&nbsp;announced on Thursday the anti-dumping investigation against Chinese telecommunications equipment makers will not be pursued."</p><p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10101322049893211">10</a> &nbsp;Facebook: Mark Zuckerbug wants to "build drones, satellites and lasers to deliver the internet to everyone." Good luck with that.</p><p><a href="http://www.gartner.com/newsroom/id/2692318">11</a> &nbsp;Garnter: They've published some predictions about 2014 and 2015 mobile device shipments. And by mobile device, I mean four different categories: "Traditional PCs", "Tablets", "Mobile Phones", and "Other Ultramobiles (Hybrid and Clamshell)". There's little new information in here, but if you're an analyst looking to see if your models aren't crazy, enjoy.</p><p><a href="http://www.j-display.com/english/news/2014/20140327.html">12</a> &nbsp;Japan Display: They've announced that they will begin shipping 5.5 inch 2560 x 1440 pixel panels for smartphones in volume in April. That's 538 pixels per inch. And in case you're wondering, they're using low-temperature poly-silicon (LTPS) technology.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.office.com/2014/03/27/announcing-the-office-you-love-now-on-the-ipad/">13</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: Office for iPad, it's now out. You can view documents for free, but in order to create and edit documents, you need an Office 365 subscription. Office for Android phones and iPhones, it's now free too, and you <strong>do not</strong> need a subscription to view, edit, and create documents.</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/03/27/microsoft-is-selling-office-365-within-ipad-apps-and-apple-is-getting-its-30-percent-cut/">14</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: Within the new Office for iPad app, Microsoft is selling Office 365 subscriptions. That means yes, Apple is getting a 30% cut.</p><p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2014/03/mozilla-employees-to-brendan-eich-step-down/">15</a> &nbsp;Mozilla: The company's employees are asking their new CEO to step down because of his views on homosexuals. Note that Brendan Eich, Mozilla's CEO, donated money to campaigns that wanted to have gay marriage banned in the U.S. state of California.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidcentral.com/samsung-introduces-new-smart-lightbulbs-controllable-bluetooth">16</a> &nbsp;Samsung: They've unveiled some Bluetooth enabled lightbulbs. No prices or launch dates.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26762198">17</a> &nbsp;SensePost: Remember that drone I wrote about earlier this week, the one that can hack into your phone while it's flying above you? The BBC interviewed its creator, Glenn Wilkinson.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/03/27/us-softbank-son-dish-idUSBREA2Q21220140327?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">18</a> &nbsp;Sprint: "Sprint is in talks with Dish Network on a fixed wireless broadband partnership, the chairman of Sprint told Reuters on Thursday." So Sprint is going to deliver home broadband now?</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26766095">19</a> &nbsp;Switzerland: The Swiss National Competence Center of Research will be holding the first "Olympics for bionic athletes" in October 2016. Think of the sports you already know and love, but with cyborgs.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26773702">20</a> &nbsp;Turkey: Along with Twitter, they've now banned YouTube too.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/03/28/us-twitter-advertising-idUSBREA2R03J20140328?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">21</a> &nbsp;Twitter: "Twitter plans to release a mobile-advertising product in the next few weeks that will allow app-makers to encourage downloads of their software." Anything is better than the ads Twitter currently serves in their official app.</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/03/27/twitter-plays-hardball-with-facebook-over-tv-and-tv-networks-gripe/">22</a> &nbsp;Twitter: Re/code is saying that Twitter is using access to their metrics as a form of leverage against television networks. Twitter wants said TV companies to only promote Twitter, not Facebook.</p><p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/03/28/business/media/tweets-about-music-to-get-a-billboard-chart.html">23</a> &nbsp;Twitter: They're partnering with Billboard to introduce a "Billboard Twitter Real-Time Chart" that will show the music being most talked about. Said chart should launch in May.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-china-26631161">24</a> &nbsp;China: Being gay in China "was illegal until 1997 and defined as a mental disorder until 2001".</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26780542">25</a> &nbsp;North Korea: The United Nations is waving their finger at North Korea for test firing two ballistic missiles on Wednesday. No one really knows how, or if, the country will be punished.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-middle-east-26765220">26</a> &nbsp;Qatar: An American couple has been sentenced to jail for three years for allegedly starving their eight year old adopted daughter to death so they could harvest her internal organs.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26765078">27</a> &nbsp;UK: England's Chief Medical Officer, Dame Sally Davies: "I have long been concerned that being underweight is often portrayed as the ideal weight, particularly in the fashion industry, yet I am increasingly concerned that society may be normalizing being overweight." Translation: People are accepting that being fat is OK, and that's a problem.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26769388">28</a> &nbsp;UK: Researchers at the University of West England have developed a test that can detect whether or not you have bowel disease simply by the smell of your feces. In a trial involving 182 samples, their test was 76% accurate. Don't worry, humans don't do the actual smelling, it's an elaborate "gas chromatograph and a metal oxide sensor".</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26779639 http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-26779639">29</a> &nbsp;UK: The Authority for Television On Demand installed Nielsen Netview software on 45,000 computers and discovered that during the course of just one month, 23% of people had visited an adult site. Average time spent at an adult site, per month: 2.5 hours.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26766006">30</a> &nbsp;UK: Two people have been diagnosed with tuberculosis, which they contracted from their cat. This is quite rare, so there's no need to panic, but it's worth knowing that such a thing is possible.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26779765">31</a> &nbsp;USA: "The US Air Force has sacked nine mid-level nuclear commanders" over cheating on monthly proficiency tests. The case is still ongoing, and over 40+ lower ranked officers also face the boot. Let me stress this: These are the people in charge of America's nukes.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26761346">32</a> &nbsp;USA: Can the United States become one of world's largest suppliers of natural gas? This BBC article examines the issue, looking at what needs to happen first, which approvals need to be received, and how long it would realistically take for the export of gas to actually begin. Spoiler: "Between 2017 and 2019".</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26780662">33</a> &nbsp;USA: Six million people have officially signed up for "Obamacare", failing to reach the goal of seven million the White House had set for themselves.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26771260">34</a> &nbsp;USA: Six trillion. That's the number of calories the 16 biggest food companies in the United States have removed from their products during the past five years due to cries over obesity.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26780821">35</a> &nbsp;USA: Walmart is suing Visa for $5 billion for fixing the price of transaction fees.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26768445">36</a> &nbsp;World: "Scientists have created the first synthetic chromosome for yeast in a landmark for biological engineering. The new chromosome, known as SynIII, involved designing and creating 273,871 base pairs of DNA." What's the goal of all this? To get yeast to produce just about any drug you want.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26763385">37</a> &nbsp;World: "The World Health Organization has declared its South East Asia region polio-free." Translation: 80% of the world is now polio-free.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26770009">38</a> &nbsp;World: Multiple universities have poured over data from North American and European cities that have passed laws against smoking in public and have discovered a 10% reduction in premature births and a 5% decline in children being born "very small". Said data set contained over 2.5 million births.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26776416">39</a> &nbsp;World: The United Nations has officially declared Russia's annexation of Crimea illegal. Not that it matters, you think Putin cares what the United Nations thinks?</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">40</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">why not become a supporter</a>?</p><p><a href="http://tinyletter.com/tabdump">41</a> &nbsp;One more thing: Tradition dictates I remind you&nbsp;<a href="http://tinyletter.com/tabdump">Tab Dump via email</a> exists on Friday.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>March 27: 41 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 09:54:46 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/3/27/march-27-41-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:5333f569e4b084001bd94df7</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.igloosoftware.com/solutions/sharepoint?ref=TabDump&amp;type=blog&amp;month=march">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: When you hear intranet, you think of clunky tools powered by SharePoint — essentially it's expensive software that doesn't work on your phone. Igloo is different, it's an intranet you'll actually like. It's built with modern, social tools to help you get work done on any device. Igloo made this special report to show you how they excel where SharePoint falls short.</p><p><a href="http://thevoicemail.wordpress.com/2014/03/27/episode-091/">02</a> &nbsp;Podcast: James Whatley and I recorded our weekly 30 minute mobile focused podcast this morning. We talked about the new HTC One (M8), Facebook buying Oculus, Intel buying Basis, Google Glass Ray-Bans, and Microsoft's two upcoming events, one of which is scheduled to take place today.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/03/26/us-alibaba-internetfinance-idUSBREA2P0NE20140326">03</a> &nbsp;Alibaba: The world's largest e-commerce company has launched an "investment fund" where people can chip in to have a certain movie or television program made. Think Kickstarter, but purely for video.</p><p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/26/in-response-to-google-amazon-announces-massive-price-cuts-for-s3-ec2-and-rds/">04</a> &nbsp;Amazon: Yesterday, Google slashed the cost of their various cloud services. Today, Amazon is doing the same.</p><p><a href="http://9to5mac.com/2014/03/25/blackberry-sues-its-own-svp-of-software-as-he-attempts-to-leave-the-company-for-apple/">05</a> &nbsp;BlackBerry: They're suing Sebastien Marineau-Mes, former Senior Vice President of Software, for joining Apple, at least that's what the headlines say. The real story is that Sebastian's contract said he needed to give six months notice before leaving. He only gave two.</p><p><a href="http://googledevelopers.blogspot.fi/2014/03/google-io-2014.html">06</a> &nbsp;Google: Tickets for Google I/O (starts June 25th) are in such short supply that the company will randomly pick who will be allowed to buy them. Note: They're $900 a pop.</p><p><a href="http://nsn.com/news-events/press-room/press-releases/nsn-study-shows-87-jump-in-indian-mobile-data-traffic-in-2013">07</a> &nbsp;India: Mobile internet traffic in India is up 87% year over year. Traffic via 3G is up 146% year over year. Traffic over 2G (yes, 2G!) is up 59% year over year. In December 2013, a 3G user consumed 532 megabytes of data compared to 146 megabytes over 2G.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26743296">08</a> &nbsp;King: The company behind the game "Candy Crush" went public yesterday. Their stock tanked.</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/3/26/5551404/klout-which-measures-online-influence-reportedly-bought-for-200-million">09</a> &nbsp;Klout: Someone bought them for $200 million. Because ... I don't know why.</p><p><a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/news/press/2014/mar14/03-26dellpatentlicensingpr.aspx">10</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: "Microsoft and Dell have agreed to license each company's applicable intellectual property related to Android and Chrome OS devices and Xbox gaming consoles. Under the terms of the agreement, they agreed on royalties for Dell's products running the Android or Chrome platforms and on consideration to Dell for a license for Xbox gaming consoles." Wait, a Dell Xbox?</p><p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/microsoft-to-unveil-enterprise-mobility-suite-alongside-office-for-ipad-7000027717/">11</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: The company is expected to announce Office for iPad today. Mary Jo Foley says we'll also see something called "Microsoft Enterprise Mobility Suite", which is a tool businesses can use to manage iOS devices, Android devices, Windows devices, "and more".</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26762135">12</a> &nbsp;New Zealand: Kim Dotcom has launched his own political party. It's called "The Internet Party". One of their goals is to introduce "a New Zealand-sponsored digital currency that is safe, secure, and encrypted."</p><p><a href="http://www.koreaherald.com/view.php?ud=20140327000356">13</a> Samsung: South Korea's largest mobile operator, SK Telecom, has started selling the Galaxy S5 today. The rest of the world has to wait until April 11th. Samsung is obviously pissed. Note that SK Telecom, and South Korea's other mobile operators, will not be allowed to sell phones between April 5th and May 19th because they've been punished for aggressively subsidizing the devices they offer.</p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/evleaks/status/448779437220167680">14</a> &nbsp;Samsung: The company's next generation budget 7.0 inch tablet has leaked. Spoiler: It's a jumbo Galaxy S5.</p><p><a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/samsungs-gear-fit-doesnt-run-android-or-tizen/">15</a> &nbsp;Samsung: The Gear Fit, Samsung's smartwatch with a curved AMOLED screen the size of a stick of gum, doesn't run Tizen like the new Gear 2 or Gear 2 Neo. According to a Samsung SVP that spoke to CNET, it's a proprietary real time operating system specifically tuned for battery life.</p><p><a href="http://www.kantarworldpanel.com/global/News/Tablets-Value-Proposition-Still-Unclear-to-Mainstream-Consumers">16</a> &nbsp;Tablets: The analysts at Kantar have published several data points on U.S. tablet ownership. Here are the key figures: 53% of consumers interviewed in Q4 2013 said they will not buy a tablet in the next 12 months. 34% were unsure. Among those who are not planning to buy a tablet, 72% said that they are happy with their current laptop/PC, and 42% said they are just not interested.</p><p><a href="http://recode.net/2014/03/26/teens-twentysomethings-spend-more-time-watching-tv-on-other-screens/">17</a> &nbsp;Television: "A new study from Deloitte finds that teens and young twenty-somethings spend more time watching movies and television shows on their computers, smartphones, and tablets than they do on their TV screens." Sample size: 2,000 and U.S. only.</p><p><a href="http://thenextweb.com/twitter/2014/03/27/twitter-is-experimenting-with-replacing-its-sacred-retweet-button-with-a-share-button/#!BAsTV">18</a> &nbsp;Twitter: It looks like Twitter might replace the "retweet" button with a "share" button, but this isn't official yet.</p><p><a href="https://blog.twitter.com/2014/photos-just-got-more-social">19</a> &nbsp;Twitter: You can now tag people in photos (10 max) and upload four photos at a time. Best of all, photos no longer count toward your 140 character limit.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/03/27/us-yahoo-japan-softbank-idUSBREA2Q0ID20140327?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">20</a> &nbsp;Yahoo!: Yahoo! Japan wants to buy a Japanese ISP called eAccess from SoftBank for $3.2 billion. Sounds simple, right? Here's where it gets confusing: SoftBank owns 42.5% of Yahoo! Japan. So how does this work?</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-26746697">21</a> &nbsp;Art: Remember the story of that guy in Germany who hid over 1,400 works of art stolen by the Nazis in his apartment? The BBC has been given exclusive access to the vault where 238 of the paintings are being held. Note that the recovered art is so valuable that the BBC can't say where the vault is located.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26746106">22</a> &nbsp;Belgium: $13.8 million was spent and 800 extra police officers were hired, all because the President of the United States came to town.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26758933">23</a> &nbsp;China: The Chinese government has just purchased $10 billion worth of airplanes from Airbus. "The order includes 27 long-haul A330s and 43 smaller A320 planes."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26748146">24</a> &nbsp;Malaysia: "A further 122 objects potentially from the missing Malaysian plane have been identified by satellite, the country's acting transport minister has said." Some of those objects are as long as 23 meters (75 feet).</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/blogs-news-from-elsewhere-26747649">25</a> &nbsp;North Korea: If you're a man, and you're attending university, then you're required, by decree of leader Kim Jong-un, to have the same haircut he does.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26731100">26</a> &nbsp;Space: An asteroid by the name of Chariklo has officially become the smallest object in our solar system to display a ring system (like the planet Saturn). What's amazing is that the asteroid has a diameter of just 250 kilometers (155 miles).</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26743089">27</a> &nbsp;Space: The 300 kilogram European ExoMars rover will land on Mars in January 2019. Where exactly will it land? Scientists have begun the selection process, and an answer isn't expected to be announced until 2017.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26751949">28</a> &nbsp;UK: There's a bar in London that holds a different kind of singles night. Bags of t-shirts that people have worn for three days are given to potential suitors to waft. If you like someone's smell, you're matched with them.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26758788">29</a> &nbsp;Ukraine: The government has agreed to raise the price of gas by 50% in order to secure a $15 billion loan from the International Monetary Fund. The people of Ukraine are used to enjoying cheap gas thanks to government subsidies, but that's going to change come May 1st.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26755913">30</a> &nbsp;USA: Charlotte, North Carolina Mayor Patrick Cannon, age 47, accepted $48,000 worth of bribes from undercover FBI agents between February 2013 and February 2014. He just resigned.</p><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/3/26/5551120/upmc-presbyterian-hospital-will-conduct-first-human-suspended-animation-trials">31</a> &nbsp;USA: Doctors in Pittsburgh will soon be putting patients with extreme injuries in a state "suspended animation" so doctors can save them. In summary, all of a patient's blood will be pumped out and replaced with a cold saline solution that stops most cellular activity. Once the patient is done being operated on, they get their blood back. Welcome to the future.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26755905">32</a> &nbsp;USA: Katheryn Deprill, age 27, was abandoned in a Burger King fast food restaurant just hours after she was born. On March 2nd of this year, she started a Facebook campaign to try and find her mother. It worked.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26761728">33</a> &nbsp;USA: Oklahoma Judge Patricia Parrish has ruled that not disclosing the names of companies supplying chemicals used to execute prisoners is unconstitutional.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26757629">34</a> &nbsp;USA: Remember the Chicago train derailment? This 19 second video is what the security cameras saw. Spoiler: It's kind of scary.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26743090">35</a> &nbsp;USA: Scientists say the beaked whale is now the new champion of underwater diving. One of their readings showed a beaked whale going 2,992 meters deep and staying underwater for 137.5 minutes, beating the previous record of 2,388 meters and 120 minutes that was set by a southern elephant seal.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26750786">36</a> &nbsp;USA: Scientists studying the brain tissue of 22 (dead) children between the ages of 2 and 15 have come to the conclusion that autism is a disease that can be detected before a child is even born.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26761931">37</a> &nbsp;USA: The death toll from the Washington mudslide has reached 24. There are still 90 people missing.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-26761798">38</a> &nbsp;Venezuela: The death toll from the protests has hit 35.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/science-environment-26747914">39</a> &nbsp;World: "Scientists from the UK and Switzerland have used very intense X-rays to film inside an insect's body as it flies." Fun Fact: Just 3% of the mass of a fly's muscles are used to "steer".</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-26754992">40</a> &nbsp;World: Amnesty International says 778 people were executed in 2013, up 15% compared to 2012. Sad Fact: America executed more people than Somalia. And China is number one.</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">41</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item><item><title>March 26: 46 tabs</title><dc:creator>Stefan Constantinescu</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 08:27:31 +0000</pubDate><link>http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/3/26/march-26-46-tabs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">52dabddae4b01e290ccd8afc:52dac255e4b03d314575d4f6:53328f79e4b0f3136215d058</guid><description><![CDATA[<p class="text-align-center"><strong>Bits and Bytes</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.igloosoftware.com/solutions/sharepoint?ref=TabDump&amp;type=blog&amp;month=march">01</a> &nbsp;Sponsor: When you hear intranet, you think of clunky tools powered by SharePoint — essentially it's expensive software that doesn't work on your phone. Igloo is different, it's an intranet you'll actually like. It's built with modern, social tools to help you get work done on any device. Igloo made this special report to show you how they excel where SharePoint falls short.</p><p><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/mar/24/amazon-yodel-barclay-brothers-deal">02</a> &nbsp;Amazon: They've signed a deal that gives them the ability to buy a 4.2% stake in the UK's least popular delivery service, Yodel, for $14.4 million.</p><p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702303949704579461783150723874?mg=reno64-wsj&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fonline.wsj.com%2Farticle%2FSB10001424052702303949704579461783150723874.html">03</a> &nbsp;Apple: The WSJ published a piece on Greg Christie, one of the engineers responsible for the birth of the iPhone. Scott Forstall walked into Christie's office in 2004 and asked if he wanted in on project "Purple". The rest is history.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/digits/2014/03/25/british-telecom-may-be-eyeing-return-to-consumer-mobile/">04</a> &nbsp;British Telecom: They signed an agreement with EE to power a potentially new consumer facing UK MVNO. More details are expected "later in the year".</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/03/25/us-china-telecoms-spam-idUSBREA2O0WI20140325?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">05</a> &nbsp;China: Police have "detained 1,530 people in a crackdown on the use of fake telecommunication base stations to send spam text messages to mobile telephones." Over 2,600 fake base stations have been confiscated since February.</p><p><a href="http://www.nfcworld.com/2014/03/25/328422/clear-channel-take-nfc-advertising-global/">06</a> &nbsp;Clear Channel: 75,000 "out-of-home advertising sites" in 23 countries will start running either NFC, QR code, or SMS based campaigns come this June.</p><p><a href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140325PD206.html">07</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: "Apple will launch a large (around 12-inch) iPad in the second half of 2014, with Quanta Computer responsible for OEM production." This rumor refuses to die.</p><p><a href="http://www.digitimes.com/news/a20140326VL200.html">08</a> &nbsp;DigiTimes: The site's in-house analysts say 422 million smartphones will be sold in China this year, with 278 million (66%) of them being made by local smartphone makers.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26742625">09</a> &nbsp;Facebook: They bought Oculus, the company who makes that virtual reality headset that the press can't stop gushing over, for $2 billion ($400 million in cash and $1.6 billion in Facebook stock).</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/03/25/rumor-androids-l-release-to-make-corporate-adoption-push-with-partial-wipe-capability-other-security-features/">10</a> &nbsp;Google: According to The Information, the next version of Android will add a lot of business focused features in an attempt to sway the BlackBerry crowd. More importantly, Google wants to bring Samsung Knox-like features to the entire Android ecosystem.</p><p><a href="http://googlecloudplatform.blogspot.fi/2014/03/google-cloud-platform-live-blending-iaas-and-paas-moores-law-for-the-cloud.html">11</a> &nbsp;Google: In order to better compete with Amazon's cloud services, Google has reduced the prices for their "various on-demand, pay-as-you-go services by 30-85%." Storage now costs $0.026 per gigabyte, down 68%.</p><p><a href="http://gmailblog.blogspot.fi/2014/03/a-new-more-visual-way-to-view-your.html">12</a> &nbsp;Google: They're testing a way to make the newsletters that you don't want in your inbox even more annoying.</p><p><a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2014/03/25/us-hp-3dprinting-idUSBREA2O1KG20140325?feedType=RSS&amp;feedName=technologyNews">13</a> &nbsp;HP: Remember how I said HP was going to reveal their 3D printer strategy in June? Turns out Meg Whitman misspoke. She meant October.</p><p><a href="http://www.htc.com/us/smartphones/htc-one-m8/">14</a> &nbsp;HTC: They announced, and started selling, their 2014 flagship phone yesterday, the HTC One (M8). It has a 5.0 inch 1080p screen, it's 90% metal, but it has the same terrible camera as their 2013 flagship phone. Multiple sites have reviewed the device, but I recommend you read what <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/3/25/5544642/htc-one-review-m8">The Verge</a> and <a href="http://pocketnow.com/2014/03/25/htc-one-m8-review">Pocketnow</a> published and just call it a day.</p><p><a href="http://youtu.be/30aN29-r400">15</a> &nbsp;HTC: This is the 30 second ad HTC will air in an attempt to convince people to buy their new phone. Spoiler: Blah Blah Blah.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/03/25/the-htc-one-m8-google-play-edition-is-live-and-coming-soon-in-the-play-store-will-cost-699/">16</a> &nbsp;HTC: Want an HTC One (M8), but don't like HTC's Android skin? HTC will gladly sell you a Google Play Edition version of the phone for $700.</p><p><a href="http://blog.instagram.com/post/80721172292/200m">17</a> &nbsp;Instagram: They now have 200 million users who use the service at least once a month. 50 million joined in the last six months.</p><p><a href="http://newsroom.intel.com/community/intel_newsroom/blog/2014/03/25/intel-completes-acquisition-of-basis-science-inc">18</a> &nbsp;Intel: Three weeks ago, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/03/basis-goes-to-intel-for-around-100m/">rumors started circulating</a> that Intel bought Basis, the company behind "the world's most advanced health tracker and web and mobile service." That acquisition is now official. Financial details weren't mentioned.</p><p><a href="http://www.niemanlab.org/2014/03/new-technology-new-money-new-newsrooms-old-questions-the-state-of-the-news-media-in-2014/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+NiemanJournalismLab+%28Nieman+Journalism+Lab%29">19</a> &nbsp;Journalism: The Pew Research Center has published their annual "State of the News Media" report. There are more data points in here than I know what to do with. My favorite: 53% of U.S. smartphone owners have used their device to watch a "news video".</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26741017">20</a> &nbsp;King: The company behind Candy Crush will begin publicly trading on the New York Stock Exchange today.</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/blog/2014/3/25/that-special-feeling">21</a> &nbsp;LG: I've been using an LG G Flex since February 27th. I scribbled down some thoughts about it last night.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/windowsazure/archive/2014/03/25/upcoming-name-change-for-windows-azure.aspx">22</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: "Today we are announcing that Windows Azure will be renamed to Microsoft Azure, beginning April 3, 2014." Let's hope this is the beginning of the end of the marketing department's urge to stick the Windows brand on everything coming out of Redmond.</p><p><a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/microsoft_blog/archive/2014/03/25/microsoft-makes-source-code-for-ms-dos-and-word-for-windows-available-to-public.aspx">23</a> &nbsp;Microsoft: They donated the source code for MS DOS 1.1 and 2.0 and Word for Windows 1.1a to the Computer History Museum in Mountain View, California.</p><p><a href="http://notch.net/2014/03/virtual-reality-is-going-to-change-the-world/">24</a> &nbsp;Minecraft: Moments after Facebook announced the Oculus acquisition, Markus Persson, the man behind Minecraft, said he no longer wants to work with Oculus because Facebook creeps him out.</p><p><a href="http://www.wpcentral.com/nokia-will-unveil-morelumia-world-april-2nd">25</a> &nbsp;Nokia: They're going to hold an event on April 2nd where it's expected they'll announce the Lumia 930 and Lumia 630.</p><p><a href="http://www.anandtech.com/show/7899/nvidia-shield-price-cuts-and-portal">26</a> &nbsp;NVIDIA: Remember the Shield, NVIDIA's failed attempt at creating an Android powered portable gaming system? It's now $199.</p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/SonyMobileNews/status/448535248520085504">27</a> &nbsp;Sony: A lot of tech sites are reporting that Sony isn't interested in Android Wear. Sony sent out a tweet saying that's a BS rumor.</p><p><a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/03/25/spotify-launches-a-4-99-student-subscription-that-takes-50-off-the-cost-of-a-premium-account-for-a-year/">28</a> &nbsp;Spotify: They're giving U.S. college students a 50% discount on Spotify Premium for one year. That's $5 per month for all the music you can eat.</p><p><a href="http://www.gizchina.com/2014/03/25/nubia-x6-launched/">29</a> &nbsp;ZTE: They unveiled a 6.44 inch phone yesterday called the Nubia X6. It has top of the line everything, but there's no word as to whether or not it'll be sold outside of China.</p><p class="text-align-center"><strong>The Real World</strong></p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26730216">30</a> &nbsp;Australia: They stopped appointing titles of nobility (knights and dames) in 1986. That's going to change this year.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26682025">31</a> &nbsp;Canada: Doctors are telling women who just gave birth that they should lose all the weight they gained during their pregnancy within one year or face increased risks of diabetes and heart disease. If a woman doesn't lose the weight in that time, it's a "stronger predictor" she never will.</p><p><a href="http://www.cbc.ca/newsblogs/yourcommunity/2014/03/calgary-radio-station-faces-backlash-after-burning-5000.html">32</a> &nbsp;Canada: Some radio station in Canada, desperate for attention (mission accomplished!), decided to hold a vote: Should they give away $5,000 or burn it? 54% of people said burn it, so they did.</p><p><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/mar/25/danish-copenhagen-zoo-kills-four-lions-marius-giraffe?CMP=twt_gu">33</a> &nbsp;Denmark: Remember the zoo that killed that giraffe? They just killed four lions.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-26743197">34</a> &nbsp;North Korea: They test fired two medium-range (1,000 kilometers) ballistic missiles. The type of missiles in question haven't been used since 2009. Why do this? To piss off not just South Korea, but the United States as well.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-26713975">35</a> &nbsp;Russia: The takeover of Crimea has countless other countries scared. Which ones? The BBC lists 10 and their relationship with the former Soviet Union.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26738686">36</a> &nbsp;UK: 20.7% of the board room members of the UK's 100 biggest companies are women. That's up from 12.5% in 2011.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26728867">37</a> &nbsp;UK: Deaths due to liver disease have risen 40% between 2001 and 2012. Raw numbers: 7,841 to 10,948. Blame booze.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26731731">38</a> &nbsp;UK: Researchers studying more than 1,000 patients have discovered that when your doctor measures your blood pressure, it's higher than when a nurse measures your blood pressure. Why? Because most people get anxious when interacting with their doctor.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26744117">39</a> &nbsp;USA: "A BP refinery has spilled an undetermined amount of crude oil into Lake Michigan."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26733757">40</a> &nbsp;USA: 18,107. That's how many boxes of cookies Katie Francis sold in seven weeks. She now holds the record for U.S. Girl Scout cookie sales.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26743714">41</a> &nbsp;USA: The death toll from the Washington mudslide has hit 16. There are still 176 people missing.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/magazine-26669971">42</a> &nbsp;USA: This article about American unemployment and the death of the American dream is full of data points. Here's the one stands out the most, to me at least: 37.1 weeks. That's the average amount of time it takes a person to find a job today. That figure was 11.8 weeks in 1950.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-26743893">43</a> &nbsp;USA: Three secret service agents tasked with making sure the President of the United States is safe have been sent home because they were heavily intoxicated. "One was found drunk and passed out in the hallway of an Amsterdam hotel."</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-26647795">44</a> &nbsp;USA: What's going to be the hottest job in the computer industry during the next 10 years? According to the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, being an Information Security Worker, otherwise known as the person that prevents cyber attacks from taking place.</p><p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/health-26730178">45</a> &nbsp;World: Seven million. That's how many people died in 2012 because of poor air quality according to the World Health Organization. Almost 6 million of those deaths were in South East Asia.</p><p><a href="http://tabdump.com/support">46</a> &nbsp;You've reached the end! If you enjoy Tab Dump, then why not <a href="http://tabdump.com/support">become a supporter</a>?</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>